<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/">ycba.mss.0006</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Pease Family Collection of Sketchbooks and Exercise Books
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Pease Family Collection of Sketchbooks and Exercise Books</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Fiona Robinson</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Department of Rare Books and Manuscripts</addressline>
               <addressline>1080 Chapel Street</addressline>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208280 </addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8280</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">ycba.rarebooks@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts"
                       linktitle="https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts"
                       show="new">https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>August, 2010</date>
            <num>MSS.6</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency>
         <agencyname>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English.</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>under_revision</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-09-11T21:01:07+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.4.1.yale.hm.mm</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Tuesday September 11, 2018 at 21:01</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Pease family collection of sketchbooks and exercise books</unittitle>
         <unitid>MSS.6</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>3</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">3 boxes + 2 oversize</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1814">1814</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1909">1909</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_744ea33caa09096dd2a2257f1221f455">The collection comprises sketchbooks and exercise books belonging to the Pease family of Durham and Yorkshire Counties, England. The Peases were part of an important network of Quaker industrialists in the northeast of England, and established the nation's first railroad in 1825. Items in the collection date from the early nineteenth to the early twentieth century.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname identifier="dts_e166b368a18116c33ac6b581a5dc92ea4b4cdd41"
                     rules="aacr"
                     source="naf">
               <part>Pease family.</part>
            </famname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_bd5497d2f82cf8b572a37de40656713f73ea10bc" source="naf">
               <part>Gurney, Emma, ca. 1800-1860.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_2dd1ab58323fb81f646181f8ac7e4aef8624695a" source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Edward Lloyd, 1861-1934.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_a622ee9094973eb0271c2bb71be6466fc56d379a"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Elizabeth Lucy, 1833-1881.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_1e4c3ca03ba9103726c883f8d4196d53086237db"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Emma Gurney, ca. 1830-1895.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_4d947a55bc8c17ad5b9eb18c4bd468f5af2a2464"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Francis Richard, 1844-1865.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_d213cddd08a06d3ce40d872e64dac46b5cf6878a" source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Helen Blanch, 1865-1951.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_f8102aa886918327b8fddfffe0c346ad1d21a1cb" source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Henry, 1807-1881.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_8424a9faa4566cf93721d1c3d39fc6567f3623f2"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Jane Gurney, 1827-1894.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_de724f5309ea6bbd99da35c26fc167c556ae0ce1"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part>Pease, John Henry, 1836-1854.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_19d58461802a9efc97ebb0a05ec3cfa4617036ec" source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Mary Cecelia, 1892-1975.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_205b03e8c370cb2e279f6e262852aa12d5c60f3e" source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Mary W.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_55a42754c9c90b6986a1161ef639effe3b0e6e53"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Rachel, 1831-1912.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_a158dae479c7018f5a2c39ed84c6cd40481baf38" source="naf">
               <part>Pease, Sarah Charlotte, 1858-1929.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_169486825703ae18f7c164154c215c61">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <arrangement id="aspace_e2dd2d86412af7b96a2e66f69dfdf973">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection is arranged into two series: I. Sketchbooks and drawings; II. Exercise books.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2a8de2dda799fa724ba5b8890c5582be">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Acquired 2009, Paul Mellon Fund.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_2d5ad1c2095282a29dc6f0398d495682">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The collection is the physical property of the Yale Center for British Art. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the Curator of Rare Books and Manuscripts.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <bioghist id="aspace_026ed1dfafda5824e93b3a940a8c882f">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Pease family are remarkable as an example of a nineteenth century success story—success that sprung largely from their pivotal role in the development of English railroads over the course of the century. In the Victorian era, they became well established and rose to prosperity and prominence, taking part in politics and enjoying a rather lavish lifestyle. What makes the Pease family even more unique is that they were Quakers. This aspect of their identity affected their business decisions, their marriages, and their lifestyles as their fortunes rose, and the Peases' changing relationship with their faith is described in many histories and memoirs about them. The Victorian era was the peak in the Peases' fortune; the last years of the 19th century, as well as the beginning of the 20th, brought change and financial trouble.</p>
         <p>Edward Pease, born in 1767, was to become known as "the father of the English Railways" for his role in founding the Stockton and Darlington Railway in 1825. The S&amp;D Railway, used primarily for the transportation of industrial cargo between various towns along the Tees river, was the first English steam railway. Edward's diaries, published by Alfred Edward Pease in 1907, offer an extensive personal and social history of the early to mid-nineteenth century. Some of the Pease diaries and other personal writings have been published, while others remain in the family, or are kept in local record offices in Durham County. The YCBA collection of Pease family material concerns the descendants of Edward Pease, including his son, Henry Pease (1807-1881), and his granddaughters, Emma and Jane Pease (who were the daughters of Joseph Pease, the first Quaker M.P.). The collection also contains material pertaining to  the family of Edward's grandson, Sir Joseph Whitwell Pease, the first Quaker Baronet, and his great-great grandson, Christopher York Pease, who was killed in the First World War.</p>
         <p>Members of the family whose items appear in the YCBA archive:</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">"E. Gurney"= Emma Gurney (ca. 1800-1860)</emph>: Wife of Joseph Pease. Daughter of Joseph Gurney, and member of a notable Quaker family in Northeastern England. Married Joseph Pease in 1826, uniting Gurney family fortune with the Pease name, thereby bringing the Peases into prominence in the area. Mother to five sons and four daughters: Jane, Joseph Whitwell, Emma, Rachel, Elizabeth, Edward, John Henry, Arthur, Francis Richard, Gurney (father to Katherine Pease Routledge, who later voyaged to Easter Island), Alfred, and Charles Pease. Joseph and Emma lived at Southend, an estate in Darlington that, while less ostentatious than the eventual homes of their sons, was still grand. The estate included a "long carriage drive lined with thick trees" (Van Tilburg, 13). Southend was the Pease family seat during the mid-nineteenth century years of success and rising fortunes.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Emma Gurney Pease (ca. 1830-d. 1895)</emph>: Daughter of Joseph and Emma Pease (nee Gurney). Avid watercolorist and artist.  In 1851, she toured the European continent with her family, a trip that inspired many drawings and watercolors. In 1853, she traveled to Scotland . She again traveled to Europe in 1874. She never married, and lived at Southend, the Darlington home of Joseph Pease. Described by Jo Anne Van Tilburg in <title>
               <part>Among Stone Giants</part>
            </title> in later life as:</p>
         <blockquote>
            <p>Slender, with lovely skin, big eyes, and chiseled features. Bright and empathetic…she was efficient and practical with a quick, impatient manner that many people thought was pushy and sharp. Emma had no close friends but took an intellectual interest in women's issues and Quaker philanthropy, using her fortune to support schools and health and to employ her formidable administrative talents. Emma thought clearly, read widely, wrote well, and had a keen sense of humor. She kept voluminous personal journals but left strict instructions for them to be burned after her death…Emma was devout, but her faith had a strong rational component.	(Van Tilberg, 14).</p>
         </blockquote>
         <p>Emma supported her niece Katherine in her passionate desire to go to college, when Katherine faced approbation and shock from her more immediate family members. She died on 2 July 1895, and was buried with her sister Jane.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Elizabeth Lucy Pease (1833-1881)</emph>: Fourth and youngest daughter of Joseph and Emma Pease (nee Gurney). She married John Fowler (1826-1864), agricultural engineer, on 30 July 1857, in a sober and quiet Quaker ceremony, unlike the wedding of her sister Rachel in 1851. John's brother William was the second husband of Rachel Pease. After having designed and manufactured an innovative steam plough during the late 1850s and early 1860s, John Fowler founded a new steam plough manufacturing business in Leeds, "John Fowler and Co.," in 1863. William eventually loaned money to the struggling J. &amp; J.W. Pease Bank in 1897. Elizabeth enjoyed a comfortable life during the apex of the Pease family fortunes in the 19th century. John Fowler died of tetanus after a fall from his horse in 1864.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Jane Gurney Pease (1827-1894)</emph>: Daughter of Joseph and Emma Pease (nee Gurney). In 1851, she toured the European continent with her family, a trip that inspired many sketches and watercolors. Jane was considered eccentric and a spiritual visionary. According to Jo Anne Van Tilburg, family history had it that Jane had fallen in love while staying with her family at the Pease summer home, Cliffe House, in Marske-by-the-Sea. Jane's beau was supposed to become the Church of England's archdeacon of Cleveland, and her father, Joseph, refused to allow her to marry a non-Quaker (the prohibition against marrying outside of the Quaker faith would not be relaxed until the mid-nineteenth century). Jane submitted to her father's judgment and ultimately never married. Like her sister Emma, she lived at Southend, in Darlington. Described by Jo Anne Van Tilburg in later life, Jane:</p>
         <blockquote>
            <p>[preferred] seclusion and illusion. She spent her withdrawn days lying on a sofa, eating massive plates of teacakes and jam rolls and filling vast numbers of pages in her many journals with flowing script. She was preoccupied with food, filling a great emptiness inside with elaborate meals and teas prepared from heirloom Quaker recipes. Though she glided through the house with the appearance of a duchess, Jane had the heavy "Pease physique" and lethargic temperament later attributed to [her niece] Katherine. Jane had an aristocratic nose, a prominent beauty spot, a dreamy smile, and a ready laugh. She sought the companionship of young male "protégées" and charmed and flattered them shamelessly…[Jane] was a romantic who 'saw the world through a veil of poetry.' Jane had a rich repertoire of humorous and moralistic tales but also knew by heart the North Country's terrifying ghost stories…Intensely bored by the limitations of her life choices, Jane's brilliant mind turned inward. Her spiritual life grew increasingly rich and charismatic, and she blossomed from a storyteller into a remarkably gifted public speaker and Quaker visionary…As Aunt Jane grew older and her circle of visitors grew smaller, she led her life at Southend in a world of insular shadows that grew increasingly deeper and darker. She believed she could commune with the dead, especially Joseph Pease and her brothers…She saw their spirits walking on the paths and terraces of Southend, or sometimes lying snug in their graves and, she said, heard their voices. The family ghosts Jane conjured were constantly moving about, day and night, haunting Southend and deeply disturbing Emma.		(Van Tilburg, 14-15)</p>
         </blockquote>
         <p>Along with her sister Emma, Jane was a source of love, support, and stability for her nephews and nieces, among them Katherine Pease Routledge. Jane died on April 5, 1894 in Torquay. Her funeral was held in Darlington, with her coffin covered in flowers and plant sprigs from Southend. She was buried at the Quaker burial ground in Darlington.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Rachel Pease (1831-1912)</emph>: Third daughter of Joseph and Emma Pease (nee Gurney). She Married Charles Albert Leatham of Wakefield in 1851, with great festivities accompanying the event. "There was…bell-ringing,…[a] brass band…flags were flown on the stations of the Stockton and Darlington railway, and…there were salvoes of artillery. The bride was attended to the meeting house by seven bridesmaids," (Orde, 102). Leatham had established an engine works and iron foundry in Middlesbrough, along with Edgar Gilkes and Isaac Wilson, in 1843.  Charles and Rachel had five daughters:  Rachel Mary Leatham (b. 1852, m. 1874), Emma (b. 1853, m. 1875), Margaret (b. 1855, m. 1875), Elizabeth (b. 1856, m. 1880 to Leonard Pelly, d. 1930) and Jane (b. 1857, m. 1878), and apparently a son who died in infancy ("Male Leatham" in birth records from Darlington, 1858). 1851 census records show Charles and Rachel living at Southend, the estate of Rachel's father Joseph, but later records made after Charles's death show Rachel and her family, along with servants, a governess, nursemaid, and cook, living in their own household. Charles died in 1858 and Rachel later married William Fowler (1828-1905), her brother-in-law by her sister Elizabeth's marriage, in 1875. William was one of five sons of John Fowler, a dedicated member of the Religious Society of Friends. According to the <title>
               <part>DNB</part>
            </title>, he rose to prominence as a politician and financier after a period of economic lows during the 1860s. William and two of his brothers took over John Fowler's steam plough business after John's death in 1864. Rachel Pease was William's third wife. Census records show them living in London in 1901. They had no children together, although William had eight children from his first marriage to Rachel Howard.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Henry Pease (4 May 1807-1881)</emph>: Fifth son of Edward Pease and Rachel Whitwell. Henry married Anna Fell on 25 February, 1835, with whom he fathered a son, Henry Fell Pease (1838-96). Anna died in 1839. Henry then married Mary Lloyd on 19 January 1859, and had three daughters and two sons with her (including Edward Lloyd Pease). In 1845, he purchased "Pierremont" house in Darlington, a showy, Gothic mansion, which he enlarged in 1873, with vast gardens and land. Henry served as a Quaker elder for many years. He gave up Quaker dress, but used plain speech until the 1860s. He refused to allow a piano in his home until old age, and never approved of dancing. He went to Russia in January 1854 as part of a failed Peace Society effort to persuade Emperor Nicholas against entering what would become the Crimean War. He served as MP for South Darlington from 1857 to 1865. In 1867, he visited Napoleon III as part of a Peace Society mission, but the society's request to hold a peace congress during the international exhibition in Paris was denied. Henry was primarily involved in the Darlington branch of the NE Railways, working as a promoter. He opened a railway line across Stainmoor in 1861, considered "the backbone of England." Henry died 30 May 1881, during a London meeting of the Religious Society of Friends.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Edward Lloyd Pease (1861-1934)</emph>: Son of Henry Pease. He was educated at Cambridge, where he was a strong athlete (primarily in rowing). Edward traveled around the world, visiting America, Australia, and Europe, before settling down to a business career in Durham County. An avid hunter, he became director of several family business concerns in the Durham area. In 1890 he married Helen Blanche Pease, with whom he had a daughter, Mary Cecelia Pease (1892-1975).</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">John Henry Pease (1836-1854)</emph>: Son of Joseph and Emma Pease (nee Gurney). He appeared in the 1851 census, visiting Barclays' household in Essex with his family. He died at age of 18.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Mary W. Pease (d. 1892)</emph>: Married Joseph Whitwell Pease. A talented watercolorist, she made an important record of the family estate, Hutton Hall, in Guisborough, in her "Hutton Hall" album.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Sarah Charlotte Pease. (1858-1929)</emph>: Second daughter of Joseph Whitwell Pease and his wife Mary Fox. In 1897, she married Howard Hodgkin, the relative of a banking partner of the Pease family, Thomas Hodgkin.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Francis Richard Pease (1844-1865?)</emph>: Son of Joseph and Emma Pease (nee Gurney). There is a death record for a "Francis Richard Pease" in Middlesex County in 1865.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Helen Blanche Pease (1865-1951)</emph>: Daughter of Joseph Whitwell and Mary Pease (nee Fox). She was a cousin to Beatrice Pease (of the "Portsmouth affair" family scandal), who was raised by Helen's mother and father after the death of her own parents. She was cousin also to Katherine Pease Routledge, who would travel to Easter Island in the 1910s. Sister to Alfred Edward Pease. On 15 January 1890, she married her somewhat distant cousin, Edward Lloyd Pease. During her lifetime, she served as Justice of the Peace for Durham County.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Mary Cecelia Pease (1892-1975)</emph>: Daughter of Helen Blanche Pease. Married Reginald J. Mounsey (1884-) in 1921. Reginald appears to have served in WWI, as part of the Durham Light Infantry. Listed in WWI Medal Rolls Index 1914-1920.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_3303fe2afbbd038c421c55ccbe72da93">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection comprises sketchbooks, watercolors, and school exercise books. It documents the period of the Pease family's greatest fortunes in the 19th century. The collection sheds light on the changing customs of the family, as they rose to prominence in industry and politics. The exercise books record different practices and standards of education for boys and girls during this time. The drawings and sketchbooks document the Pease's financial prosperity, which allowed them to travel widely and live in grand homes in multiple locations. Items in the collection were mostly created by children and women of various generations. The material documents aspects of women's leisure life in the 19th century, especially their amateur artistic practice.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <prefercite id="aspace_285ea5b657ccfc3a895d8b37f1ca0de3">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Pease Family Collection of Sketchbooks and Exercise Books. Yale Center for British Art, Paul Mellon Fund.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <bibliography id="aspace_271e02742a42b32b09159c129807874e">
         <head>Bibilography</head>
         <p>Pease, Edward. Diaries.</p>
         <p>Pease, Sir Alfred. My Son Christopher</p>    
         <bibref>Kirby, M.W. <title>
               <part>Men of Business and Politics: The Rise and Fall of the Quaker Pease Dynasty of North-East England, 1700-1943.</part>
            </title> London: Allen &amp; Unwin, 1984.</bibref>
         <bibref>Mewburn, Francis. <title>
               <part>Larchfield Diary.</part>
            </title> London: Simpkin Marshall, 1876.</bibref>
         <bibref>Orde, Anne. <title>
               <part>Religion, Business, and Society in North-East England: the Pease Family of Darlington in the Nineteenth Century.</part>
            </title> Stamford: Shaun Tyas, 2000.</bibref>
         <bibref>Pease, Alfred Edward. <title>
               <part>My Son Christopher: Being the Story of the Childhood of Christopher York Pease.</part>
            </title> Middlesbrough: William Appleyard &amp; Sons, 1919.</bibref>
         <bibref>Pease, Edward. <title>
               <part>The diaries of Edward Pease, the father of English railways.</part>
            </title> London: Headley Brothers, 1907.</bibref>
         <bibref>Pease, Joseph Gurney. <title>
               <part>A Wealth of Happiness and Many Bitter Trials: the Journals of Alfred Edward Pease, a Restless Man</part>
            </title>. York: William Sessions, 1992.</bibref>
         <bibref>Van Tilburg, JoAnne. <title>
               <part>Among Stone Giants: the Life of Katherine Routledge and Her Remarkable Expedition to Easter Island</part>
            </title>. New York: Scribner, 2003.</bibref>
      </bibliography>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="dts_07c2c33affdeb7b936ca4972e142d5889c68ace8"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Art, Amateur -- Great Britain.</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85041030"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Education -- Great Britain</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="dts_c57fbf1502e06ba21adc4f14aa144435425cad0a"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Quakers -- Great Britain.</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85111114"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Railroads -- Great Britain</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008115264"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Great Britain -- Pictorial works</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="dts_67b2bc0ab57e3afd28d85c88e50861ce59a01280"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Marske-by-the-Sea (England) -- Pictorial works.</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008116925"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Scotland -- Pictorial works</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008117203"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="dts_72ee41f942699be2838ae078530ef2fa4b7cc316"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Yorkshire (England) -- Pictorial works.</part>
         </geogname>
         <subject identifier="dts_c5b019114e7545dbccaae6666bc1a9a68da5091d"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>School notebooks -- Specimens. </part>
         </subject>
         <genreform identifier="dts_bad237f2173f87a0dadaee79223c3fe891f15d6e"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Botanical illustrations.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_259c25a2ea8854baea6dd59969bfa6d726d997f8"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Children's art.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_4d1bd5824c71321507042678dcb2c8ef3c7cb664"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Exercise books (Penmanship)</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264330"
                    source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
            <part>Exercise books.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_a03d400ba5afa18858deb895252558ba217445d8"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Graphite drawings.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_6f044326445cf1a89ccd4ce5a8137c166922dce4"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Juvenilia.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_48695ca7a8c9b34a32d939c2204065c442378ea3"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Landscape drawings.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_9e1f7c57daeb4c7b660120b4b7fa3d96513b2c74"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Sketchbooks.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_05444e8b883efe1be85a141dbc175bbc7af1de36"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Europe.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_c8f23c75fe46b9808cbcbcf1d6e4a75e06635878"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Great Britain.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_949d50e3009a880d3bfb0f296a7a93e5c38e3765"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland.</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Watercolors.</part>
         </genreform>
         <persname identifier="dts_ad9f23ea3a0d79f72cd9685e355809bfe4805792" source="lcsh">
            <part>Gurney, Emma, ca. 1800-1860.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_406bcfc57ca9bb5ce15752ca8b4ebb48056c9df9" source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Edward Lloyd, 1861-1934.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no93015661"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>Pease, Edward, 1767-1858</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_de63c1c40458128d233d43fe9302caa918462683"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Elizabeth Lucy, 1833-1881.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_00e79dc1b094c8c979c8004ba2fd22be2e1350a8"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Emma Gurney, ca. 1830-1895.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_08523758499203174a837401c92709d7d29a635d"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Francis Richard, 1844-1865.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_aa16cdab3d743909d021b76149adc7b868819de0" source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Helen Blanch, 1865-1951.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_17ba8a6e7e3b4f4ca9f316bcd3c511e44b0e91af"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Henry, 1807-1881.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_5f97658434043bed652e5d8b84d339d410c0153a"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Jane Gurney, 1827-1894.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_03518140d3384c7096c3ec998af171e2890c87f9" source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, John Henry, 1836-1854.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_939609c0cf38d6c9e9e250124a0ed5dd70ff6f1b"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Mary Cecelia, 1892-1975.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_04992ee6535c638515c286ab2448d88c4727ba7d" source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Mary W.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_f4a4904038d9f497b9c356fe3d615ae746801016" source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Rachel, 1831-1912.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_d041553388e1b74b68c83d5d58091d53711ddcae"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Pease, Sarah Charlotte, 1858-1929.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n86138416"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>Waterhouse, Alfred, 1830-1905</part>
         </persname>
         <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85099077"
                  source="naf">
            <part>Pease family</part>
         </famname>
         <corpname identifier="dts_df377dac896ade5e673b80d6bf640ad4996a9671" source="lcsh">
            <part>Hutton Hall (Guisborough, England)</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Sketchbooks and drawings</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
            </did>
            <c id="ref127" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Emma Gurney</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref2" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Dieppe</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Gurney, Emma</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1814</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_43c6aad86960979b12206c5376c5f633">1 v. (19 drawings) ; 21 x 28 cm. Bound in quarter red roan and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_f0301deb408e9739fde2cc90246f24a6"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b70a1be4477e2fc63812df7923981305"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f0301deb408e9739fde2cc90246f24a6">1</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_f1cef204032fcd1d04f2bcfc2a549157">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Inscribed "E. Gurney" in graphite on the cover. Contains graphite sketches of scenes from a trip that Emma took with her family to Dieppe, France, in 1814. From images of the voyage across the Channel, Emma moves on to make several sketches of local scenery, residents going about their daily tasks, and regional costume. Most of the pieces are not completed, but a few are more finished than others. Some of the drawings are part of an additional smaller sketchbook, here bound in. Towards the end of the sketchbook is an apparently transcribed (rather than originally composed) verse or song, in French. While Emma's transcription has some typical learner's grammatical mistakes, the gist of the verse is clear. It seems to be a dialog between a man and a woman, torn between the potential costs and glory of the battlefield and a relationship at home. With the contemporary situation of the Napoleonic Wars, this verse must have had particular relevance and poignancy at the time of Emma's visit to France.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Dieppe (France) -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- France</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref128" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Emma Gurney Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref29" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: botanical drawings and rural scenery</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1840-1845</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_67ab4c6fc11d0a6c12710ef457ad3540">1 v. (24 leaves of drawings) ; 24 x 30 cm. Bound in half green roan and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_4ec68b1895d0a8c493c02a9b33f7e084"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_48cdf2152fcb7039cbab10532a9a0f1a"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4ec68b1895d0a8c493c02a9b33f7e084">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_b6ef551701f4282e4a63e11c11d6713a">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Inscribed, "Emma Gurney Pease--from her dear Grandmamma Gurney, 1840." Contains  graphite sketches of rural scenery and botanical studies in watercolor. The works are generally accomplished, with detailed graphite drawings and carefully painted watercolors. Emma's work seems to show a stronger aptitude in, or even preference for, graphite pieces. The scenes depicted in the sketches include images of rural cottages, architectural ruins, and studies of tree leaf patterns. Many of the images in this book are mirrored in Jane Pease's sketchbook of the same era (Box 2, Folder 9), with nearly identical pieces occurring quite often.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Botanical illustrations</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref44" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook/schoolbook: Balder Grange</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1845</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_6f9dcfe8629f5fe1a99177fd1d47e0ea">1 v. (19 p. of drawings and verse) ; 24 x 19 cm. Bound in quarter calf and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_fcc4ffc8c3e26f42c9f26abaad01f07f"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_b0b7df7bf9eef9b5abb4631e664319ed"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fcc4ffc8c3e26f42c9f26abaad01f07f">3</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_7cd6bfaae9edf80baac7a8e7e95b119f">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite sketches done mostly during family visits to Balder Grange, the home of Emma's aunt and uncle, and other local places. The sketches are labeled in what seems an adult's hand, in purple pencil. They are not fully finished, in most cases. In addition to the sketches, there are a couple of poems written in pen and black ink in a mature hand. The verse is about moral topics, but includes a rather odd poetic dialog between a sailor and a landlord, contrasting the lures of alcohol and money.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <corpname rules="aacr" source="local">
                        <part>Balder Grange (Teesdale, England)</part>
                     </corpname>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref48" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Drawings: Scotland</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1849</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_7f88ccb61f37cc15fd3e88c56dc30427">13 leaves of drawings ; 18 x 26 cm., and smaller. Unbound, in a paper wrapper.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_2ea29f3ea220deea37e0155d2ef36ce7"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f91218d50e6dd46215b1c1ecc5fde9f6"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2ea29f3ea220deea37e0155d2ef36ce7">4</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_143aedb843e759b032791e25ee6b18a7">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite and watercolor seascapes and landscapes, with scenes of Scottish towns and lakes. The sketches vary in degree of completeness. There are views of Marske-by-the-Sea, where the Joseph Pease family had a holiday residence called Cliffe House.  One sketch, labeled "Meeting House, Easington," is not signed and, based on slight differences in style and in handwriting, seems possibly to have been made by a different artist. Other locations depicted include: St. Andrew's Church in Upleatham, Stirling (?) Castle, Loch Lomond, Loch Achray &amp; Benvenue from Trossachs Inn, and Mulgrave Hermitage.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Scotland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Scotland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref32" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook (portfolio): Scotland, Switzerland, etc.
</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1849-1889</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_ad8636868c0c3778a5de9234c765eb3b">1 v. (circa 60 leaves of drawings); 19 x 27 cm. Disbound in Winsor and Newton's "New and improved solid sketch book".</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_6443cd1b98c0bab2d3628bc890a51cd2"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9758c69839937949c78d63f2429ea0a8"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6443cd1b98c0bab2d3628bc890a51cd2">5</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_2f1726b0622f7a7dad426b08a8e53a30">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Emma Gurney Pease made sketches over a number of years using this book. Because the design was such that individual pages could be removed, most of the sketches sit loose inside the covers. Most sketches are in graphite alone. Some are in graphite with the addition of sepia or indigo wash and gouache. There are a few pieces in full color watercolors. Many items appear fully finished, while some of the others have shading/coloration notes that indicate that Emma intended to come back and apply watercolor or make a more finished version. The sketches are of varying subjects, but most were done on family trips to some of the Peases' favorite destinations--the Alps and Scotland among them. There are few, if any, people in Emma's drawings here. Most items are drawn with a gaze directed outward and away from the self and family members.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Scotland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Scotland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref52" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Switzerland and Cornwall</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1851-1852</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_3ce0da5b81310fb876601359332c2a75">1 v. (circa 30 p. of drawings) ; 19 x 27 cm. Bound in dark green half roan and marbled boards, from Harrison Penney, stationer, Darlington.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_94253289241b9a38f5a29c5c1e9b15ce"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8d15f0a0dc60d0933b461fd041f36ebf"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_94253289241b9a38f5a29c5c1e9b15ce">6</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_1d7838f207fd6a1adcf7d4c006f4ebe2">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Inscribed "Emma G Pease/Southend/Darlington/1851" on flyleaf. Contains sketches, in graphite and watercolor, made during family trips to Switzerland in 1851 and to Cornwall in 1852. Most of the drawings are rough sketches, with touches of white gouache occasionally used to indicate snow on mountains or rushing water. Locations depicted include: Port Maurizio, Lake Como, Martigny, Montreux, Fribourg, Lucerne, Thun, Heidelberg Castle, M. Maggiore, Cornwall, and Colham Lawn (?).</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- England</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Cornwall (England : County) -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref35" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Scotland</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1853</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_331c146fe8e2c47d33ee5c46fd829085">1 v. (14 leaves of drawings); 12 x 27 cm. Bound in quarter green morocco and green cloth.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_260d87790b6188cc1b132c519f715cdf"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_af2fb104fb837276fb3797fd7280e3ee"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_260d87790b6188cc1b132c519f715cdf">7</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_ada2dd2351d8cd16831554f0cde3fc37">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite drawings from a family trip to Scotland in 1853. The majority of pages in the sketchbook are blank.  One sketch is labeled as having details added by "A. Lloyd," presumably a friend of Emma's. As is typical for Emma, the subject matter is that of scenes from nature or views of villages and architectural features from a distance. The sketches are mostly very complete and include a panoramic waterfront view done over two facing pages. Locations depicted include: Stirling, the Falls of Bruar, Loch Tummel, Tummel Bridge, Loch Goil (?), Fort Augustus, Iona, the Treshnish Isles (and the "Bac Mor," or "Dutchman's Cap" rock formation), Oban, Tay nuit (Muckcairn?), and Ellswater(?).</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Scotland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Scotland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref57" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Drawings: Nice, France</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1874</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_a32314d9f512b5879dfbce9f36048977">8 leaves of drawings ; most 25 x 32 cm. Unbound.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_0630a4bb83c279edea8c7746d7f4ac8f"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">Oversize 1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a14b1d60171ce122b7245736747acb8e"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0630a4bb83c279edea8c7746d7f4ac8f">1</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_9811b1fb841eac08c3eb19f4c32337ee">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains drawings in graphite and gouache, of scenes around Nice, France. The subject matter includes rural scenes and local residents, landscapes, mountain and waterfront views, and architectural features.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- France</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Nice (France) -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref129" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Francis Richard Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref38" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: scenery and domestic objects</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname relator="art" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Francis Richard</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1854-1857</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_dbfbd7d929813e7cfdf648d1a556bdd1">1 v. (ca. 30 leaves of drawings); 21 x 28 cm. Bound in blue printed boards, from an unidentified stationer/publisher.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_d44cc202aa1f4702db0f5565b631f167"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_57f12d8d916ee0498d2e90cd0c84db80"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d44cc202aa1f4702db0f5565b631f167">8</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_3aa2960dda92bf7a98c35df8e9339158">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite drawings of scenery and domestic objects. Francis Richard Pease began this sketchbook when he was roughly 10 years old. Drawings are dated from 1854 to 1857. The drawings of scenery depict houses and other buildings, including churches and ruins. Objects drawn include a press, a stool, a model tin pump, an easel, and a vase.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref130" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Helen Blanche Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref124" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Flower drawings</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Helen Blanche</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1882</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_0fca10ec79464c323e3b44aa5af6e208">1 v. (20 leaves of printed plates and 2 leaves of drawings); 25 x 19 cm. Bound in publisher's original green cloth, with title stamped in gilt.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_7e125b61115fd2aec668db1ff76c04b7"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_299c3b902828cba3f57a135b8264cfc7"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7e125b61115fd2aec668db1ff76c04b7">8a</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_d004c48d59766b9dfa7e983670dbeecf">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Consists of two graphite drawings by Helen Blanche Pease within the following published work: Hulme, F. Edward. <title>
                           <part>Flower Painting in Water Colours</part>
                        </title>. London: Cassell &amp; Co., [1881?]. The front endleaf is inscribed: Helen Blanche Pease, 1 Jany. 1882. Hulme authored several series of this title, circa 1880-1885. The present volume appears to be the first series. The title pages and other preliminaries have been neatly excised in this copy. It retains all 20 chromolithographed plates of common flowers. Helen appears to have taken minimal interest in the volume; she has copied in graphite but two specimens (the crocus and the Eschscholzia) on blank leaves facing the illustrated plates.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Botanical illustrations</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref131" level="series">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jane Gurney Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref106" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>School drawing book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Jane Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1840?</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_1b385bf82aaa911bb1ebf8fdac137be3">1 v. (22 leaves of drawings) ; 24 x 30 cm. Bound in half maroon roan and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_e56d6b8c9bb3cd6f3bbfe4b784358d58"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8cc94bd87be8f483a0cd9fa436d3ba00"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e56d6b8c9bb3cd6f3bbfe4b784358d58">9</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_f2525a60fd28ccc6251c76f6221c7cd3">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains varied drawings in graphite and watercolor. They are generally skillful drawings, with graphite landscapes and watercolor botanical studies. Most of the landscapes depict rural and/or possibly local scenery, with one of them labeled "Darlington." Many of the drawings and paintings here mirror those in her sister Emma's sketchbook of the same period (Box 1, Folder 2).</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Botanical illustrations</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref79" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketches: Yorkshire</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Jane Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1849-1850</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_028309677d147b2549a573e460718bd6">6 leaves of drawings ; 26 x 21 cm. Unbound.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_c52c374726d6bdf0f17b6f65f02a66fe"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e354a679522fd9116989bd43c3099c0a"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c52c374726d6bdf0f17b6f65f02a66fe">10</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_a3ba61a0394ed97ccb026a7afad48c87">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains six graphite sketches of scenes in North Yorkshire. The sketches are rough, and lack detail. Labeled drawings include: Skinningrove, Mulgrave Castle, Guisborough Abbey, and Easby Abbey.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Yorkshire (England) -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref60" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Switzerland and Cornwall</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Jane Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1851-1852</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_e06eb14c49bccdfbc067bf2abba0126c">1 v. (23 leaves of drawings) ; 19 x 27 cm. Bound in half dark green roan and marbled boards, from Harrison Penney, stationer, Darlington.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_3805ddebf9044efb71fab58c4fdc27e9"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_dd27a610adbc6b5d38b7416d27cf21be"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_3805ddebf9044efb71fab58c4fdc27e9">11</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_1cbbc6a2415c103ba442179a04530839">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite and watercolor drawings from a family trip to Switzerland in 1851 and a second trip to Cornwall in 1852. As is typical of Jane's work, the sketches are all landscapes of one kind or another, showing mountains, lakes, notable architectural features like Chillon Castle in Switzerland, and scenes from villages. In addition to the drawings made in Switzerland, the pieces from the trip to Cornwall consist of seascapes and landscapes. In particular, Jane includes a sketch of Cotham Lawn estate, which belonged to Margaret and Richard Fry. The Fry family was related to the Peases through marriage by this time. Other places depicted include: Lago di Como, Lago Maggiore, Montreux, Fribourg, Thun, Vevey, Heidelberg Castle, Giessbach Fall, Mainfort—Cornwall, Mount's Bay from Penzance, and Falmouth harbor.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Cornwall (England : County) -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- England</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref132" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>John Henry Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref63" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: seascapes and landscapes</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, John Henry</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1850</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_0df54d587aa6ffd2e1d629266cefa3b7">1 v. (12 leaves of drawings) ; 26 x 37 cm. Bound in green paper wrappers with gilt lettering on cover reading "Drawing Book. Geo. Rowney &amp; Co., London." </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_6f437b30b77d061e17f53cd706c6cf5d"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">Oversize 1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6fb2feca7684f4eaf358440a6b88cbf2"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_6f437b30b77d061e17f53cd706c6cf5d">2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_8db186df7dd3b40e70f8710ec01366ed">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite drawings and watercolors of waterfront views and rural architecture. The drawings vary in degree of completeness, but show a range of interest and fairly skillful handling. Two inserted drawing by Emma Gurney Pease depict Mulgrave Castle, in Yorkshire, and a scene from Marske by the Sea. Both are done in graphite and watercolor.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Marines (Visual works)</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref133" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mary Cecilia Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref66" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Portfolio of juvenile drawings and paintings</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Mary Cecelia</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1906-1909</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_f7fc611818d5153afafe02f53ba1d0ba">1 portfolio (54 leaves of drawings, various sizes) ; the volume measures 51 x 40 cm.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_8e06d7e053500aaa63d9ee3e84c4dea2"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">Oversize 1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1c2b06e8fe8d1a34b0f9cca92dbb5a0e"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8e06d7e053500aaa63d9ee3e84c4dea2">3-5</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_88db54b11ea1c772f381a2926fbe5fde">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains 54 individual pieces of artwork and a "Scholastic Drawing Book" by Mary Cecelia Pease. The drawings and paintings are in graphite and/or watercolor and represent a wide array of subject matter, from botanicals to portraits, still lifes, landscapes, and others. Many of the watercolors have tiny holes in them, suggesting they may have been pinned up somewhere (Mary's schoolroom at home perhaps?) or perhaps simply from being pinned to a drawing board/easel. The artworks are generally quite complete, with many studies included in the portfolio. On a few pieces, comments and what appear to be "scores" are given by an unidentified individual with the initials "L.W."</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Children's art</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref134" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mary W. Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref67" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Hutton Hall album</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Mary W.</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1865-1890</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_b1470281cbf0c56f882e819375f535aa">1 v. (39 leaves of drawings as part of the album, plus 22 additional items inserted) ; 33 x 43 cm.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_abc215169cd82e3030b4ce82a90a6bac"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">Oversize 2</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_8a2d17bdda6c16698f87811f81493fa7">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains drawings and watercolors by Lady Mary W. Pease, many concerning the family's Hutton Hall estate. The watercolors are done in a confident, accomplished hand. She seems to have had a particular talent for observation, composition, color, and in the handling of her paints. The works represent a close knowledge of the family home, record the style of décor that the Peases used, document family outings close by and further away (especially to Scotland), and show two other Pease properties. It includes still lifes of domestic items like cooking pots and utensils, botanical studies, and designs for wallpaper patterns. This album demonstrates Lady Mary's interest in her home and the way in which the home itself was a sort of canvas on which she expressed herself, as a prosperous Victorian wife.</p>
                     <p>Hutton Hall was designed for Joseph Whitwell Pease in 1868 by architect Alfred Waterhouse, who is perhaps best known for his work in designing the Natural History Museum in London. Waterhouse was raised in a Quaker family and received many commissions to design homes for prominent Quaker families in the North of England. Some of his very trademark elements are the terra cotta and cream colored brick construction, and the Gothic stylizing that can be seen in Hutton Hall. Hutton Hall had its own railroad station on a line that ran from Middlesborough to Guisborough, an extension of the original Stockton and Darlington Railway, established to carry more of the mineral freight from mines to ports in the area. Both of these towns were significantly developed by the Pease industrial enterprises.</p>
                     <p>It is not clear whether Lady Mary assembled this album herself or whether it was put together by another family member. Someone labeled these pieces in the twentieth century, long after her death, and it's possible that the physical album dates from the Victorian era. So, in a way, the idea of the "Hutton Hall Album" as a cohesive unit may not have been Lady Mary's exactly, although the number of paintings that are in it and their subject matter certainly shows us that the years, places, experiences depicted in the album are all sort of unified by the Hall, and by the period of time that the Peases occupied this house.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Dwellings -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </subject>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Interior decoration -- Great Britain</part>
                     </subject>
                     <corpname rules="aacr" source="naf">
                        <part>Hutton Hall (Guisborough, England)</part>
                     </corpname>
                     <persname rules="aacr" source="naf">
                        <part>Waterhouse, Alfred</part>
                     </persname>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref70" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Scotland and Wales</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Mary W.</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1870s</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_b59ff26b05ba43146b8fba160680a824">1 v. (20 leaves of drawings) ; 13 x 26 cm. Bound in contemporary dark green quarter morocco and green cloth.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_639c8bded991698ab04edbe7bb740d3e"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_770a45376984134824ef6e82da0bd763"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_639c8bded991698ab04edbe7bb740d3e">12</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_86a880d52628e72d736498fc31d13c8a">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains graphite and watercolor sketches documenting travels in Scotland, primarily. The subjects of Lady Pease's work include waterfront views, scenes of rolling hills and vegetation, studies of local residents, and architectural features. Most of the sketches are completed in watercolor. Some pieces depict scenes from Falmouth, Wales, where the Peases had a home called Kerris Vean. Labeled scenes include: Loch Bulig, Mar Lodge, Cluny Lodge Braemar, Behind Lions Face Cluny, Lemorran Creek, Penlee Point &amp; Newlyn, Hanging Stone Hulton Stream, and Ballater &amp; Crathie.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Wales -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Wales</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Scotland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Scotland</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref73" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Switzerland</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Mary W.</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1886</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_e42c78e0e59198f934651621bcce2c3f">1 v. (23 leaves of drawings) ; 11 x 18 cm. Bound in contemporary quarter dark green morocco and dark green cloth.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_19b3f06bc920fa6b78a3af42a82b77c0"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3d895fe2032599317a005a3a631c061f"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_19b3f06bc920fa6b78a3af42a82b77c0">13</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_f00031af400a1535deaaeb91d8478efc">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains watercolors made by Lady Pease during a family trip to Switzerland in 1886. The paintings are mostly very complete and depict landscapes observed throughout the voyage, from the Dover cliffs to the mountains and lakes of Switzerland. Labeled scenes include: Dover, Zurich, Silvaplana, Engadin, Poschiavo, St. Moritz, Thusis, Simplon, Chillon Castle, Lake Geneva, and Interlaken.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <geogname source="lcsh">
                        <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
                     </geogname>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref135" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sarah Charlotte Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref76" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Botanical watercolors</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Sarah Charlotte</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1880-1881</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_d2ed28b049779a72a473ff36f5a421ad">1 v. (15 leaves of drawings) ; 26 x 18 cm.  Coverless sketchbook.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_2547c23729b641b0a37b3ac144548126"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8964bae16cc35a22cced0a571b26fe3a"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2547c23729b641b0a37b3ac144548126">14</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_9c828c0323687d704429622a2e62661c">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains works signed "S.C.P.", the initials of Sarah Charlotte Pease. The botanical studies are done in watercolor throughout. Flowers depicted include roses, coneflowers, bush honeysuckle, Capsicum, lilies, poppies, and Buddleia. Several of the pieces are labeled "Ben Welldene," which was the home of the Hodgkin family, into which Sarah eventually married. Benwell Dene was designed by Alfred Waterhouse for Dr. Thomas Hodgkin, who later donated the house to the Royal Victoria School for the Blind. Other pieces were painted in Scotland, Germany, and at the Pease family home, Hutton Hall.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Botanical illustrations</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref136" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Unidentified Artist</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref82" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Sketchbook: Switzerland, Germany, Italy, and France</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857-1880</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_c0c4a2f19a54ebf8ccd600521830c114">1 v. (22 leaves of drawings) ; 19 x 27 cm. Bound in quarter dark roan and green cloth, with brass clasp.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_26dd2593222898cb70cc8c638aefa006"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_59fc7d5dfee479adc57b7bccf260dbb3"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_26dd2593222898cb70cc8c638aefa006">15</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_39fd75aacd972794ae348866ee1e098b">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains travel sketches made between 1857 and 1880, by an unidentified member of the Pease family. All of the drawings are in graphite. The style and subject matter resemble those of Jane and Emma Pease, but the skillful handling suggests that the artist was probably Lady Mary W. Pease. The sketches depict scenes from Switzerland, Germany, Italy, and France. Labeled scenes include: Hallstadt, Cadenabbia, Bouverie (Lake Geneva), Splügen, Isola Bella (Stresa), St. Moritz, La Bollène, and Lake Como.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Sketchbooks</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="gmgpc">
                        <part>Travel sketches -- Europe</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Exercise books</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
            </did>
            <c id="ref120" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edward Lloyd Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref85" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Examination books</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Edward Lloyd</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1869-1872</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_1f6ec2c948a521195c14a986ea51d093">5 v. </physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_43f261f79e42661eb99bdeea8b11425d"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_83d07300b901dc4f74aed5fababfe152"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_43f261f79e42661eb99bdeea8b11425d">16</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_49895ce21676bc63e6ecb6e0f5351aca">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains academic examination papers for Edward Lloyd Pease, the son of Henry Pease. Dating from 1869-1872, when Edward was between the ages of eight and eleven, the items evidence evaluation in composition, history, religion, and mathematics. All writing is done in pen and black ink, although an instructor (an Algernon C.P. Coote) has made comments in purple ink in the 1872 test booklet. The instructor notes particularly that Edward should not "write about things…not in the question." The examination papers indicate that they were likely administered at Pierremont, Henry Pease's estate in Darlington. An 1874 roster for Oliver's Mount School in Scarborough, which includes Edward, shows that after these examinations, he advanced to the boarding school.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Examinations</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref88" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Science exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Edward Lloyd</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1876</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_a5b1124bf9fd67b1d350071074cb1064">1 v. (60 p.) ; 23 x 19 cm. Bound in quarter green cloth and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_0ac02f36d28243bb13bcbefcccc7007f"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a5c84e4d5eccd8e647f1b182778cf813"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0ac02f36d28243bb13bcbefcccc7007f">17</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_9224e66e53eb72c648b4da3c18b92a34">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains notes on zoology, geology, arithmetic, and engineering, by Edward Lloyd Pease, who was about fifteen years old at the time of the lessons recorded in it. Some of Edward's essays include illustrations of mechanical objects. Writing is in graphite or pen and black ink. It is possible that this schoolbook was used while Edward was at Oliver's Mount School, where he is listed on an 1874 roster. However, no instructor comments appear. A rather fanciful and spirited inscription by Edward  appears on front pastedown: "Elementary Science/ comprising a treatise on Astronomy/Natural Philosophy/ Geology &amp;/ Mensuration Formulae/ An abridgment [sic] from ther [sic] larger works on these subjects, which have been carefuly [sic] consulted by Mr. Robinson, and drawn up in such a manner that it is likely to prove the greater boon to students interested in these subjects published by/ E.L. Pease. A.A.S.; B.A; A.R. A; B.C.L.B.M.: C.B.S; B.C. L; F.R.S: F.S. A: L.L. B: L.L.D. etc. etc. etc. etc./ 100,000,000,000th edition/ This work is dedicated (by the kind permission of his most gracious majesty) &amp; the most noble King of the Cannibal Islands./ Opinions of the Press:  This wonderful little work is marvelously adapted after…."</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Science -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref121" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Emma Gurney Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref14" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mathematics exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1839</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_d7d8d8bdfbf95018cd9ff15e7459c1d4">1 v. (132 p.) ; 24 x 19 cm. Bound in quarter red roan and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_edb8889982b1267bdf03143b263f771a"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_478fd0ecd7535525419bef3c104224a4"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_edb8889982b1267bdf03143b263f771a">18</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_7866da62d8c5fae87f608437008875de">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Title page is inscribed "Emma Pease, Darlington, 1839" in an elaborate calligraphic hand. Exercises are written in pen and black ink throughout. It contains dozens of mathematical exercises, primarily in practical topics, such as "Addition of Money, Weights, and Measures," "Ale or Beer Measure," "Land Measure." The practical problems may have been meant to give a child a more concrete grasp of the application of mathematics, or perhaps they were meant to prepare a young female student for future management of a household.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Mathematics -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref17" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mathematics exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1841</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_8f290652c2858ad8f3f1e43ca656218e">1 v. (128 p.) ; 24 x 19 cm. Bound in quarter roan and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_e027201051f164eaab6ff6f0b977f558"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_1b0d75c11dec9180a966851f73c84239"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e027201051f164eaab6ff6f0b977f558">19</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_d1cde18b12fc56e145d439d4350df250">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Inscribed "Emma Gurney Pease Darlington, 3rd Mo. 8th 1841." It continues the practical or topical mathematical exercises of her 1839 schoolbook. All writing is in pen and black ink. Each problem is labeled in a child's calligraphic hand, showing that Emma took pride in the appearance of her schoolbook, and that these exercises afforded her further opportunity to practice her handwriting. Exercises in this schoolbook include financial transactions and topics, such as "Stocks," "Brokerage," and "Simple Interest," perhaps reflecting the visibility and importance of the Pease family's banking business at this time.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Mathematics -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref122" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry Pease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref91" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Penmanship exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Henry</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1816</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_b3af1d6ce16f94e8ede0714d5d2a4868">1 v. (20 p.) ; 20 x 17 cm. In paper wrappers.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_fa0fd8fc10fc004f41f9211e9917d5fa"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_a59d70155525295b451982a607202ca0"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_fa0fd8fc10fc004f41f9211e9917d5fa">20</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_c19c7658285894ad0f61eb88b7119ea3">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains handwriting exercises throughout, the themes of which reflect such values as hope and the precariousness of wealth. Henry Pease created this schoolbook at the age of eight or nine. He carefully signed several pages, "Henry Pease, Darlington." All material is written in pen and black ink. It is not known what school Henry attended, and there are no instructor comments in this particular exercise book. Most likely he attended a local nonconformist school.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="rbgenr">
                        <part>Exercise books (Penmanship)</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref94" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Mathematics exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Henry</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1817</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_9b162b5652d7bb569083fac65fa7469d">1 v. (ca. 50 p. of exercises) ; 21 x 18 cm. Bound in quarter calf and marbled boards.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_285ff602923c8eb47d7b05eebbe630aa"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d2475eb11a0ea0fa225eb1748619bf64"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_285ff602923c8eb47d7b05eebbe630aa">21</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_206d447645440bd48e3ba40ea57ae8b1">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains exercises in mathematics, in pen and black ink, done when Henry Pease was nine or ten years old. Multiplication and division exercises are accompanied by prose descriptions of the various sorts of mathematical methods. There is no indication of the name of Henry's school or instructor.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Mathematics -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref97" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Penmanship exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Henry</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1821</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_be3627f49bd02f9241aa4d2a57a8813f">1 v. (16 leaves of exercises) ; 20 x 33 cm. Bound in quarter calf and marbled wrappers.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_2be704e41c997c6f48b4952d2a99bb83"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_54668de3a2f76cc746a2537860b3af69"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2be704e41c997c6f48b4952d2a99bb83">22</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_30b72ad077db3e13d260dcb5607d9dad">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains penmanship exercises, in pen and black ink, by Henry Pease. Moral values, such as the fear of wickedness, the importance of modesty, and avoidance of foul language, are promoted via the exercises. There are no instructor comments and there is no indication of the name or location of Henry's school.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="rbgenr">
                        <part>Exercise books (Penmanship)</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref100" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Composition book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Henry</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1821</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_26761c9cb5a617d3be102bed5636492c">1 v. (circa 50 p.) ; 16 x 20. In marbled paper wrappers.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_113ba60504ee3865db952d72ee51cca0"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3e9480257c02f9b2384a01acbb7d0598"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_113ba60504ee3865db952d72ee51cca0">23</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_0c1bfb0c2c2a762345596d9418c7e3e8">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>Contains compositions, in pen and black ink, by Henry Pease. Includes some instructor comments in red ink. Henry's compositions range in theme from English and world history, to ethics, to favorite hobbies and sports. Particularly notable are an essay "On the Pleasures of the Approaching Vacation," a piece debating warfare, and another about winter sports, which for Henry included snowballing, "sliding" (sledding), and skating.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Composition (Language arts) -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
               <c id="ref103" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Latin exercise book</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Henry</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1823-1825</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_25203acacda1c33c733f0216f2617aa8">1 v. (40 p.) ; 18  x 24 cm. In buff paper wrappers.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_d985a6b454e71a22df7459a004af36c5"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_8fa9a80bc2c54a197d67e82158e4c324"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d985a6b454e71a22df7459a004af36c5">24</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_1048c6b02b540337fb57486b6ae50a5d">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>The pages of this exercise book have been thriftily used during two separate years. The recto sides of the pages are dated 1823 and 1824, and the verso sides have been used (with the book flipped upside down) in 1825. The 1823/1824 portion contains Latin exercises; the 1825 portion consists of penmanship exercise. All are written in pen and black ink; some comments from an instructor or an older pupil--a John Irvine (or Irving)—appear on a few of Henry's Latin exercises.  Henry, in turn, notes where he has amended any errors. Moral values, as is typical of the Pease family schoolbooks, are promoted via the handwriting exercises throughout, with hard work and modesty being among the themes here.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Latin -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref123" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Multiple Authors</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref20" level="item">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Juvenile Compositions</unittitle>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Jane Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Rachel</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Emma Gurney</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <origination label="creator">
                        <persname source="local">
                           <part>Pease, Elizabeth Lucy</part>
                        </persname>
                     </origination>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1843-1846</unitdate>
                     <physdesc id="aspace_1e8e872643c858a2ffa59409e9085d9b">1 v. (76 p.); 20 x 24 cm.</physdesc>
                     <container id="aspace_bd45029595663376f3c5543b6902b2f4"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">3</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6200123a04a6f75e1341d82b1a2d65a9"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_bd45029595663376f3c5543b6902b2f4">25</container>
                  </did>
                  <scopecontent id="aspace_9348a1cb9c1a87f5fe6233278e7df776">
                     <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                     <p>This schoolbook is the joint project of four Pease sisters: Emma, Jane, Rachel, and Elizabeth. It contains various essays on topics such as who the best king of England was, and about the different seasons. All writing is in pen and black ink; a couple graphite sketches accompany one or two essays. Within the schoolbook, there are some creative compositions, including poems and "A Letter supposed to be written by the page of an English nobleman during the crusades to his sister at home, Ascalon (?), 1192." A very unexpected 1845 essay on Hydropathy as a treatment (something that had only just debuted in England in about 1843), is written by Elizabeth Lucy. Rachel's essay on "Winter" includes some poignant descriptions of "dirty" and "poor" children begging from door to door and avalanche victims in Switzerland. A graphite sketch of a rooster accompanies a piece on "the domestic cock" by Rachel Pease. All of the essay signatures indicate that they were written at Southend, the Darlington estate of Joseph Pease and the sisters' childhood home. The girls were most likely educated here.</p>
                  </scopecontent>
                  <controlaccess>
                     <genreform source="aat">
                        <part>Exercise books</part>
                     </genreform>
                     <subject source="lcsh">
                        <part>Composition (Language arts) -- Study and teaching</part>
                     </subject>
                  </controlaccess>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
