<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/">ycba.mss.0008</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Carr Family Collection of Travel Sketches, Scrapbooks, and Genealogical Material
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Carr Family Collection of Travel Sketches, Scrapbooks, and Genealogical Material</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Courtney Thomas; edited by Francis Lapka</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Department of Rare Books and Manuscripts</addressline>
               <addressline>1080 Chapel Street</addressline>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208280 </addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8280</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">ycba.rarebooks@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts"
                       linktitle="https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts"
                       show="new">https://britishart.yale.edu/about-us/departments/rare-books-and-manuscripts</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>June, 2011</date>
            <num>MSS.8</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency>
         <agencyname>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English.</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>under_revision</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-11-28T22:01:03+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.4.1.yale.hm.mm</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Wednesday November 28, 2018 at 22:01</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Carr family collection of travel sketches, scrapbooks, and genealogical material</unittitle>
         <unitid>MSS.8</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>10</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1699">1699</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1981">1981</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="bulk">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1811">1811</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1899">1899</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_6547b60700d70d9949d3d26a7c5cecd9">The collection comprises travel sketches, scrapbooks, and genealogical material concerning the Carr family of Northumberland, England.  </abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                     source="lcsh">
               <part>Carr family</part>
            </famname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d" source="lcsh">
               <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
               <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_8316c99780d03d29069c9b0234285ebca44f536b" source="lcsh">
               <part>Lushington, Sarah Grace, 1794-1837</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_b085375adc083bd921b28da6507ff6ea585c6ccb" source="naf">
               <part>Hogg, James, 1770-1835. ( Raid of the Kers)</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="dts_580ac16606397353f8e9d1cdfe0248c4b0a6c70d" source="naf">
               <part>Carr, Ralph Edward, 1833-1892. ( History of the family of Carr of Dunston Hill, Co. Durham)</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_c0ee484708a3d056629e18fca6f89c8c">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <arrangement id="aspace_9cf83443cd62ad830fa1e6ec1bcc2f62">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Arranged in four series: I. Sketchbooks, 1811-1863; II. Scrapbooks, 1699-1981; III. Family history and genealogy, 1823-1912; IV. Photographs, etc.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_720c12a5b66fb263a229366d7a277d06">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection comprises travel sketches, scrapbooks, and genealogical material concerning the Carr family of Northumberland, England. The Reverend Thomas William Carr (1830-1912) appears to have played a key role in compiling the material, especially genealogical items.</p>
         <p>The collection documents the burgeoning of interest in local and family history in the nineteenth century, as reflected by the thorough efforts of the Rev. Thomas William Carr to collect information and physical items relating to the history of the Carr family; the travels and artistic works of two Victorian women, Anna Margaret Carr (who traveled to Europe and India) and her sister Sarah Grace Carr (who focused on local English themes), whose numerous landscape sketches can be used to reconstruct their travel itineraries and provide insights to their interests as both travelers and artists; the often overlooked but pivotal role of Geneva and other Calvinist areas as stops on the Grand Tour (especially for English travelers); Victorian decorative arts, as seen in the greeting and note cards from the period preserved in the collection; and the religious attitudes, daily social life, and business interests of a nineteenth century Anglican clergyman, as reflected in the journals and correspondence of the Rev. Thomas William Carr.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_3aa9a48f44694b6727974e0ad9288018">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Carr family was originally based in Northumberland and became particularly prominent in Newcastle.  It included several prominent branches.  The Carr family of Woodhall and Hexam can be traced to John Carr, a yeoman who lived c. 1450-1515.  From here the family spread to Kibblesworth and Newcastle and then to Dunston Hill in Durham.  The notable businessman Ralph Carr, who made a fortune in the eighteenth century in the Newcastle area through merchant and trading activities, was a member of this branch of the family and acquired a sizeable fortune which he partially used to build an estate at Hedgeley in Northumberland for the family.</p>
         <p>Another branch of the family settled in Hetton and traces their roots to William Carr who, in 1412, was a notable landowner in Northumberland.  This branch of the family eventually acquired Castle Ford and lived there for several generations.</p>
         <p>The final major branch of the family settled at Eshott Heugh and Frognal. It is this branch of the Carr family that concerns most of the material in the present collection.</p>
         <p>The Carr family history is richly treated in: <title>
               <part>The History of the Family of Carr of Dunston Hill, County Durham, and the Collateral Lines in England by Colonel Ralph Edward Carr and Cuthbert Ellison Carr</part>
            </title> (London: Mitchell and Hughes, 1893-99)--an annotated copy of which is available in the present collection.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Thomas Carr (1733-1793)</emph>
The patriarch of the line of Carrs based at Eshott Heugh lived from 1733-1793.  He traveled to Georgia as a child and was a Sub-Officer of the Marines.  In this capacity he participated in the siege of Havana.  With four different wives, Carr produced four sons (Mark William Carr, a soldier, Thomas William, a lawyer, William Ogle, a sailor, and John Thomas, a merchant) and two daughters (Ann and Rebecca).  Thomas Carr was very reckless with the family finances and nearly obliterated their wealth and landholdings.  His son, Thomas William, however, managed to retain Eshott Heugh.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Thomas William Carr (1770-1829)</emph>
Carr records that he was born on 19 March 1770 in Savannah, Georgia and that he and his family returned to England in 1772.  He trained as a lawyer and married Frances Morton in 1794.  He appears to have been very industrious and worked to rebuild the family fortune.  He was called to the Bar in 1801 and made Solicitor of Excise in 1805.  Carr was described as "thoroughly a family man," who took great joy in spending time with his wife and children.  He had eight children: Sarah Grace (1794-1837), Frances Rebecca (called Fanny) (1796-1880), Anna Margaret (1797-1872), Thomas William (1801-1840), Andrew Morton (1799-1852), William Ogle (1802-1856), Isabella (1804-1860) and Laura Carr (1807-1868). He died suddenly from a "rupture of the septum of the heart" at Frognal on 27 April 1829.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Sarah Grace Lushington (Carr) (1794-1837)</emph>
Sarah was born in London on 6 December 1794.  The family history records that in 1810 she was travelling in Italy and Switzerland and so it appears she also, like her sister Anna Margaret, took a Grand Tour of sorts. A letter from her father survives asking her to translate a Latin poem for him, and she appears to have been reasonably well-educated. On 8 August 1821 she married Dr. Stephen Lushington, the son of the Director of the East India Company.  She became a close friend of Lady Byron (whom Stephen Lushington represented in her separation from Lord Byron).  Sarah and Stephen had five sons and five daughters and she died on 20 September 1837.  According to the DNB, her last illness was harrowing and it deeply moved her husband.  After her death, her sister Frances kept house for her husband until her own death.  Aunt Fanny Carr was regarded as somewhat severe and harsh but she displayed a great love for all her nieces and nephews and lived until 1880. 
Sarah's husband Stephen had an important legal career as a judge, a Member of Parliament, and an anti-slavery activist.  He also represented Queen Caroline in her trial by Parliament to have her crown and status as the wife of George IV stripped from her on grounds of her adultery.  His defense of her was successful and she remained in contact with him until her death, naming him as the executor of her will.  Of the couple's children, Edward Harbord Lushington (1822–1904), became a senior Indian civil servant; Vernon Lushington (1832–1912), a county court judge; and Godfrey Lushington (1832–1907), Vernon's twin, permanent under-secretary in the Home Office.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Anna Margaret Carr (1797-1872)</emph>
Anna was born in London on 13 December 1797.  Notes in the family's Bible record that she was inoculated for smallpox in 1798.  In 1833 her brother William was appointed to a diplomatic position in Ceylon and she travelled there with him.  She returned to London when her brother married in 1836 and spent the rest of her life living with various family members until her death on 9 March 1872.  According to biographical notes on her, "she was devoted to natural history, and was especially proficient in botany.  Her quick and gifted pencil has left her relations quite a gallery of interesting sketches … her chief sketches were bits of scenery in places where she stayed, and with a few but very telling touches the effect produced was singularly graceful."</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Rev. Thomas William Carr (1801-1840)</emph>
Son of Thomas William Carr. He passed his divinity school requirements in the 1820s and was licensed to serve as a cleric in the county of Rutland in 1825, thereafter becoming Curate of St. Michael's in Bristol, and of Teddington. In 1829 he married Susan Hamilton (née Woodward) (d. 1834), to whom was born their children Thomas William Carr (later of Barming) (b. 1830), Lucy Emily (1832-1888), and Francis Culling Carr (b. 1834). After Susan's death, Rev. Thomas William Carr married Joanna Maria Childers in 1837.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Laura Carr (1807-1868)</emph>
Daughter of Thomas William Carr (b. 1770). In 1850 she married Sir Robert Monsey Rolfe (1790-1868), who was raised to the peerage as Baron Cranworth the same year, and served as Lord Chancellor from 1852-1858 and 1865-1866. The couple had no children. In the Rev. T.W. Carr Scrapbook (Oversize 7), there is a letter from Arthur Bigge in 1895 referring to correspondence between Her Majesty and the family of Lord and Lady Cranworth. Bigge writes that "The Queen was very fond of Lady Cranworth."</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Rev. Thomas William Carr (1830-1912)</emph>
Thomas William Carr was the son of the Rev. Thomas William Carr (the brother of Sarah Grace and Anna Margaret Carr) and his wife Susan.  He was the grandson of Thomas William Carr of Eshott Heugh, the family patriarch and son of Thomas Carr.  He was born on 14 July 1830 and earned his BA from Wadham College, Oxford in 1853.  He followed this with an MA in 1854 and was ordained a deacon in 1856 and a priest in 1857.  In 1865 he became the rector of Barming in Kent and was also recognized as an English Chaplain of Bordighera, Italy.  Carr and his wife Harriet had seven children: Mary Joanna Sophia (1859); Thomas William (1861); Robert Lancelot (1863); Alured John Deacon (1866); Laura (1868); Frank Collett (1870); Margaret Lucy (1871).  Upon the death of his wife, he was remarried (in 1891) to Emily Maria Charlotte, herself a widow.</p>
         <p>
            <emph render="boldsmcaps">Harriet Carr (Deacon) (1829-1889)</emph>
Harriet Carr was the wife of the editor, Rev. Thomas William Carr, and predeceased him on 21 February 1889.  In her obituary, reprinted in the Carr family history, she is described as living "a life of usefulness" and as "loving and loved by all her husband's relations, and winning golden opinions in the parish."  She is also described as loving plain needlework and working industriously within the parish (undertaking such activities as teaching Sunday school each week).  Prior to her death she had suffered six years of illness, mostly associated with her lungs and, despite her trips to Nice and Bordighera to recover her strength, she became increasingly sick.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_210c3e17352fa66efbd16e52ce3685e7">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Carr Family Collection of Travel Sketches, Scrapbooks, and Genealogical Material. Yale Center for British Art, Paul Mellon Fund.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1462f07b617c7e8286d19bc9ffeedb1a">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The collection is the physical property of the Yale Center for British Art. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the Curator of Rare Books and Manuscripts.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_890c4255d56dab1335e3c2babf2aaad4">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Acquired 2009, Paul Mellon Fund.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh00002558"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Grand tours (Education)</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="dts_0c1b4468fe558c4af13b53c0974e3ca300bf2585"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Women artists -- Great Britain</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="dts_00e52606761df720d1daade2b535fb6593b506e6"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Women travelers -- Great Britain</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname identifier="dts_9146c478c8641c8ff5272553015e95fb92b83b13"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Northumberland (England) -- History</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="dts_823bf7826bee65ee3014b89bbf0d5e8fa8babe31"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Northumberland (England) -- Social life and customs</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="dts_07e6d53cc13842cfe2a9e7c7e0b5ed6c7df6dabc"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Pisa (Italy) -- Pictorial works</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112"
                    source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
            <part>Diaries</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_028173a231a37bf55d5aa5e1aec9654c07f948c0"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Genealogies</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_512e289b774a13eb6ed28d521d0f8814a6c991ff"
                    source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
            <part>Scrapbooks</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027354"
                    source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
            <part>Sketchbooks</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_48695ca7a8c9b34a32d939c2204065c442378ea3"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Landscape drawings</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_e5888f519bfeed01d831946e72b43b2e3f1ae886"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Views</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_05444e8b883efe1be85a141dbc175bbc7af1de36"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Europe</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_14b935da23a28b6bf2b3b87b12c7a7919203c6f2"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- France</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_c8f23c75fe46b9808cbcbcf1d6e4a75e06635878"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Great Britain</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_cf4d5a8a1acbc983e19193e9fa1665880d153b51"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Italy</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_949d50e3009a880d3bfb0f296a7a93e5c38e3765"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300390908"
                    source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
            <part>Charcoal drawings</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_aabc7ec7f748be9e97a3e84d979e14014b180853"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Engravings</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                    source="gmgpc">
            <part>Graphite drawings</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300"
                    source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
            <part>Photographs</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_fce1a7170be2040b43c0409cec0f1be7c558e241"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Wash drawings</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                    source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Watercolors</part>
         </genreform>
         <subject identifier="dts_1068c7543c8e938a3cc3e8cb80523623ec272baa"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Chron -- 1824-1899</part>
         </subject>
         <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part>Carr family</part>
         </famname>
         <famname identifier="dts_f1f26bc03d125161b792bc1fbde70109a57df619" source="lcsh">
            <part>Carr family ( Heraldry)</part>
         </famname>
         <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d" source="lcsh">
            <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_75914fe890029b8c0c5b038617b57b9663969e36" source="lcsh">
            <part>Carr, Harriet, 1829-1889</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
            <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84123147" source="naf">
            <part>Cranworth, Robert Monsey Rolfe, Baron, 1790-1868</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_2f0f3392e9be43e36f8128834fe60f871c4ca9f2"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Cranworth, Laura Rolfe, Lady, 1807-1868</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_8316c99780d03d29069c9b0234285ebca44f536b" source="lcsh">
            <part>Lushington, Sarah Grace, 1794-1837</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname identifier="dts_81d70d7580125aed5497700bd92cfa6a02354889" source="lcsh">
            <part>Eshott House (Alnwick, England)</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref1" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Travel sketches</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
            </did>
            <c id="ref5" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Album of drawings of Great Britain and the Continent</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_8316c99780d03d29069c9b0234285ebca44f536b"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Lushington, Sarah Grace, 1794-1837</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1811-1859</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_f94dd043cfb461b8206490e0e5852073"> 1 volume (81 drawings) 
:  graphite, some with watercolor 
;  32 x 47 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_32909aaae0c390744b31f13da3711323"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4918a4a36ecce19650c0801bae68f8db">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album of drawings by Anna Margaret Carr and Sarah Grace Carr . Only three drawings appear to be signed: "Hougoumont, Sept. 21, 1816" (no. 2) and "Salden House, January 26, 1832" (no. 19) are initialed by Anna Margaret, while "Hampstead Heath, Jun. 9, 1815" (no. 57) is initialed "SGC". From this evidence it is difficult to determine which drawings were executed by which sister, especially since the 1816 drawing initialed "AMC" has a very similar style to those that appear to be by SGC. The differences in style among the drawings seem to be attributable more to the age and maturity of the artist than to individual aesthetics, since the earlier drawings are generally more exact, detailed, and stiff; the later drawings are vaguer and done with a blunter pencil.</p>
                  <p>Places identified in the drawings include St. Mary's Scilly, Hougoumont, Dover harbor, Delft, Pisa, Nuremberg, Bex, Baveno, Tourtemagne, Edgeworth, Holdenby House, Lowestoft, Tynemouth, Windsor Forest, Hampstead Heath, West End, Hormead Bury, and Tunbridge Wells.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008115264"
                            source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Great Britain -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Europe</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Watercolors</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Great Britain</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Europe -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref8" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Drawings of Great Britain and Atlantic Isles</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_8316c99780d03d29069c9b0234285ebca44f536b"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Lushington, Sarah Grace, 1794-1837</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1812-1863</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_cddbfadbe0b742865b11b270e0b17688"> 38 drawings 
:  graphite, some with watercolor 
;  27 x 39 cm, and smaller </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_03f4e232c8c83afadeee7fdd89e353e8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67eea6e8953fde76349955c05413f7d2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>An unbound set of drawings, most of which are mounted on heavier paper stock. A small label on the original paper covers reads "My mother's and aunt Anna's drawings." Only two of the sketches are signed: Easby Abbey is signed "SGL" (Sarah Grace Lushington); "Westhumble" is labeled "Aunt Anna". Presumably, the drawings include a mix of work by Anna Margaret Carr and Sarah Grace Carr Lushington.</p>
                  <p>Included are sketches of Mount Batten, Dorking, Tunbridge Wells, Hampstead Heath, Kirkby, Fountains Abbey, Easby Abbey, and Duddingston Loch. There also a few drawings of locations outside the British Isles, including Berne, Bodenbach, Madeira, Mauritius, and St. Helena.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Great Britain</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Watercolors</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008115264"
                            source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Great Britain -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref12" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Album of drawings of France and Switzerland</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1824</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ea3d10d0869be89c76d4173f7a314b08"> 1 volume (69 drawings)  :
 graphite, some with watercolor  ;
 38 x 54 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_56d8ddeb92f934d88db4dc524c28b2fe"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3712b78302ff981130d1cd67ff6f6cb2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Labeled on the spine "Vol. 1 1824". Comprises sketches from Anna Margaret Carr's Grand Tour, in France and Switzerland. The sketches begin on 22 August 1824 near Montreuil. Carr traveled for five weeks from Paris to Florence (first going north-east through Reims via Soissons, then south through Geneva via Dijon and Poligny, and finally along the northern shore of Lake Geneva through Lausanne). The first volume ends on 8 September 1824 at Saint Maurice.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh00002558"
                           source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Grand tours (Education)</part>
                  </subject>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Watercolors</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008117203"
                            source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>France -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- France</part>
                  </genreform>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Album of drawings of Switzerland and Italy</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1824</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_44d2109f4f1cef9540f77d70b4c5687e"> 1 volume (67 drawings)  :
 graphite, some with watercolor  ;
 38 x 54 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_5f3662d42074904617c456c5979c4b15"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f9919ea10724206d654a8759ae337319">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>A continuation of the previous sketchbook, labeled on the spine "II Vol 1824". Carr's Grand Tour continues on 9 Sept 1824 at Tourtemagne (Turtmann, Switzerland). She crosses through Simplon Pass in early September and moves southeast towards Como, south to Genoa, and spends the last week of September traveling east along the Mediterranean, with sketches concentrated in La Spezia, Livorno, Pisa, and Florence.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008117203"
                            source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Switzerland -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Switzerland</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Italy -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Italy</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh00002558"
                           source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Grand tours (Education)</part>
                  </subject>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Watercolors</part>
                  </genreform>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Album of drawings of France and Italy</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1827</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_1e53703a176e3a8a1b16e4523c00d49f"> 1 volume (63 drawings)  :
 graphite, some with watercolor  ;
 32 x 47 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_d960d5d7c4190723e34f1c5e0fdef5e1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2e0f2cc5306d49d4d5a77f58af46ea1c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Labeled "Foreign Sketches 1827" on the spine. This album seems to record the start of Anna Margaret Carr's 1827-8 voyage to the Continent, beginning near Paris (the first labeled sketch is in Montreuil, France, on 7 September 1827) and tracing her voyage southeast into Italy and eventually to Pisa, where the sketchbook ends in November 1827 (though she remained there through early 1828).</p>
                  <p>The drawings are pasted into the album in rough chronological order. In her first week near Paris, Anna Margaret visited Abbeville and St. Germain. She spent two weeks traveling southeast toward the Italian border, visiting Auxerre, Autun, Chalon-sur-Saône, Lyons, Les Echelles, Aiguebelle, Montmeillant, and various places in Savoy (including Saint-Michel-de-Maurienne, "Lans le Bourg", and Modane) before crossing into Italy.</p>
                  <p>In Italy, she traveled southeast along the Mediterranean coast to Sarzana, Spezzia and the "Mountains of Carara" (Carrara, the source of Michelangelo's marble) in early October, finally arriving in Pisa, where the album ends. She seems to have arrived in Pisa at some point in mid-October 1827, but some Pisa sketches are dated November as well (the next volume reveals that she stayed in Pisa through the spring).</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Watercolors</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Italy -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Italy</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh00002558"
                           source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Grand tours (Education)</part>
                  </subject>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>France -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- France</part>
                  </genreform>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Album of drawings of Pisa and vicinity</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d"
                               relator="art"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1827-1828</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_56357493c4551de0e29f9086a24120b0"> 1 volume (59 drawings)  :
 graphite, some with watercolor  ;
 32 x 47 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e6c03d7706ab8b2a03b4d05e4f0f0ce4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_57b41785d1bff8b4ae6ce29e59a9826d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Labeled "Foreign Sketches 1828." The album is mostly comprised of drawings from Anna Margaret's travels in and around Pisa from January through April of 1828, but also includes a few from late 1827. The album ends with two drawings from Martigny, Switzerland in May 1828. Aside from these final two, the drawings are pasted into the album in no discernible order.</p>
                  <p>Aside from Pisa, places identified in the drawings include Florence (drawn from afar), San Domino, Serchio, Lucca, and La Verucca (in the Valle dei Calci).</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_9850c848ac3aab4fd2a0779bb14954fa1b8be9f3"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Watercolors</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Italy -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <genreform source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Travel sketches -- Italy</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Pisa (Italy) -- Pictorial works</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh00002558"
                           source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Grand tours (Education)</part>
                  </subject>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Scrapbooks, notebooks, and genealogical material</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
            </did>
            <c id="ref22" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Carr Family scrapbooks</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                        <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1699-1890</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_e2517a614ef1ef7f5737fb05ba6edfdf"> 2 volumes (volume 1 circa 225 pages, volume 2 blank)  ;
 53 x 37 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_ae551c908d40a55a12017004e9f36efa"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 7-8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b6cfb7214ff013a87d9f084e4162b987">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Large bound book labeled "Scrap Book, Vol. I" on the spine. Pages are heavy paper, colored (or discolored?) pinkish, some yellowish. Documents have been pasted, stapled or laid in. First half largely contains legal documents, ordination certificates, passports, etc. from the lives of Thomas William Carr  (1770-1829) made Solicitor of Excise in 1805, his son the Reverend Thomas William Carr (1801-1840), Rector of Teddington?, and his son Reverend Thomas William Carr (b. 1830), Rector of Barming. It seems likely the scrapbook was assembled by Rev Thomas William Carr of Barming, and that he collected manuscripts from friends, family, etc. One newspaper clipping, for instance, is reported as having been found in an old cabinet in the Eshott Heugh estate.</p>
                  <p>Some of the documents (such as a 1699 lease from the Palatinate of Durham regarding some Carr family properties) have paper or wax seals affixed to them. Others (such as the Confirmation of Arms and Grant of Crest to Gayus Dyxon in 1565) are colored, photolithographed copies of much older documents (photoengraving techniques, pioneered in the 1850s, had developed greatly by 1880).</p>
                  <p>The documents don't seem to follow any particular order, although they are grouped more or less by document type and time period. In a very, very rough scheme, the groupings move through:</p>
                  <p>(1) Sale of Eshott Heugh estate
(2) Documents from lives of Rev Thomas William Carr (of Teddington) and Rev Thomas William Carr (of Barming), including when they were ordained curates, rectors, etc., certificates of examinations passed, declarations of subscribing to the 39 Articles and the Liturgy of the Church of England. Many of these have the Episcopal Seals of various bishops attached (particularly the Bishop of Peterborough and Archbishop of Canterbury).
(3) Travel passports allowing travel on the Continent; some sheets seem to have been issued by French government and stamped/signed by notaries or officials of different countries visited.
(4) One large, elaborate declaration on vellum headed "George the Third by the Grace of God," apparently appointing Thomas William Carr a Solicitor of the Excise in 1805.
(5) Painted images and photolithographed copies of coats of arms and Carr family genealogies
(6) "Fac-similes" of historical documents and newspaper articles from historic events
(7) Documents surrounding the death of Major Mark William Carr when the steamer General Outram was lost off "Rutnagherry" in India. A Carr Compassion Fund was established in 1871 (?) in Major Carr's honor, to aid police officers' widows.
(8) Turn-of-the-century greeting cards, Christmas cards, Valentines, many with colored images and personal messages.
(9) Sketches and photos of memorials and sarcophagi of Carr family tombs. Include photos of tombs of William Ogle Carr (Rev TW Carr of Barming's uncle) and Rev Thomas William Carr (of Teddington, labeled "my father's grave," presumably by TW Carr of Barming). Also letters, death notices, etc. regarding Carr family burials.
(10) Notecards and engravings of various churches associated with Carr family.
(11) Copy of Carr family pedigree.</p>
                  <p>Large albums with spine title: "Scrap Book, Vol. I[-II]." Volume II is entirely blank. Some of the documents are affixed to sheets of the album; many others are laid in (on stubs). The first half of the album comprises legal documents, ordination certificates, passports, etc. from the lives of Thomas William Carr (1770-1829) made Solicitor of Excise in 1805, his son the Reverend Thomas William Carr (1801-1840), Rector of Teddington, and his son Reverend Thomas William Carr (b. 1830), Rector of Barming. It seems likely the scrapbook was assembled by Thomas William Carr of Barming, and that he collected the scrapbooks material from from friends and family. One newspaper clipping, for instance, is reported as having been found in an old cabinet in the Eshott Heugh estate.</p>
                  <p>Some of the original documents, such as a 1699 lease from the Palatinate of Durham regarding Carr family properties, have paper or wax seals affixed to them. Others, are facsimiles (many photolithographed) of  much older documents.</p>
                  <p>There is no apparent ordering scheme, although they are grouped very roughly by document type and time period. These groupings include the following:</p>
                  <list listtype="ordered" numeration="decimal">
                     <item>Sale of the Eshott Heugh estate.</item>
                     <item>Documents from lives of Thomas William Carr (of Teddington) and Thomas William Carr (of Barming), including items concerning their ordinations as curates, rectors, etc., certificates of examinations passed, and declarations subscribing to the 39 Articles and the Liturgy of the Church of England. Many of these have the Episcopal seals of various bishops (particularly the Bishop of Peterborough and Archbishop of Canterbury).</item>
                     <item>Passports allowing travel on the Continent. Some sheets seem to have been issued by the French government.</item>
                     <item>One large, elaborate declaration on vellum headed "George the Third by the Grace of God," apparently appointing Thomas William Carr a Solicitor of the Excise in 1805.</item>
                     <item>Carr family coats of arms (originals and copies), and Carr family genealogies.</item>
                     <item>Facsimiles of historical documents and newspaper articles from historic events.</item>
                     <item>Documents concerning the death of Major Mark William Carr when the steamer General Outram was lost off "Rutnagherry" in India. A Carr Compassion Fund was established in 1871 (?) in Major Carr's honor, to aid police officers' widows.</item>
                     <item>Turn-of-the-century greeting cards, Christmas cards, and Valentines, many with colored images and personal messages.</item>
                     <item>Sketches and photos of memorials and sarcophagi of Carr family tombs. Include photos of tombs of William Ogle Carr (the uncle of  T.W. Carr of Barming) and Thomas William Carr (of Teddington). Also present are letters, death notices, etc., regarding Carr family burials.</item>
                     <item>Notecards and engravings of various churches associated with the Carr family.</item>
                     <item>Copy of the Carr family pedigree.</item>
                  </list>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_512e289b774a13eb6ed28d521d0f8814a6c991ff"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Scrapbooks</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027392"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Passports</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026778"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Greeting cards</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <subject source="lcsh">
                     <part>Sarcophagi</part>
                  </subject>
                  <subject source="lcsh">
                     <part>Clergy -- Great Britain</part>
                  </subject>
                  <corpname identifier="dts_81d70d7580125aed5497700bd92cfa6a02354889" source="lcsh">
                     <part>Eshott House (Alnwick, England)</part>
                  </corpname>
                  <persname source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Thomas William Carr scrapbook</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                        <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1819-1899</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4e9ae7e2f6fd434c8d5d4854feb8e113"> 1 volume (468 pages)  ;
 36 x 25 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_d2e3c730a6fc99b79d13fd8351a44b13"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 9</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_91be245b023c9e6cbb45c63fa4dbf2c8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album is titled in gilt on the spine: "Carr M.S.S. Scraps."</p>
                  <p>Notes at the front, signed "T.W.C.", remark that the album was "rebound &amp; enlarged in 1889," and "the first vol. begun perhaps 10 years before and also the folio volume." The notes suggests that the current scrapbook was compiled later than the others, although presumably all three were put together by Reverend Thomas William Carr of Barming.  His obituary, from December 1912, is included in the scrapbook's final pages. It is clear that leaves 229-234 were added later, since they are of different paper from the rest of the album.</p>
                  <p>In general (though there are many exceptions), the material in this scrapbook seems to date from the lifetime of Thomas William Carr of Barming, coming from his immediate ancestors or relatives, and descendents. Occasionally, later descendents have added material from the mid or late 20th century. The volume also seems focused on personal documents (rather than the legal documents collected in volume 1 of the earlier folio scrapbook). It especially includes family and portrait photographs, photos and engravings of houses and churches associated with the family, personal letters, the family coat of arms, genealogies, and death notices, memorial inscriptions, and photos of tombs. There are also letters from those with whom T.W. Carr of Barming corresponded in his attempts to gather information and documents for his family history. In many places, T.W. Carr of Barming has helpfully penned in notes explaining the provenance of a document or its relation to the Carr family. However, the album itself is not clearly organized and follows no narrative structure. It has a loose chronological arc, but there are also 16th century documents on the purchase of Eshott Heugh estate in the final pages of the book.</p>
                  <p>Affixed to the inside of the back cover is a collection of wax seals. Most appear to date to the 1800s, with a handful perhaps from the 1600s.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300028877"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Seals (artifacts)</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Photographs</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Correspondence </part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Laura Carr (Lady Cranworth) scrapbook</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_2f0f3392e9be43e36f8128834fe60f871c4ca9f2"
                               rules="aacr"
                               source="lcsh">
                        <part>Cranworth, Laura Rolfe, Lady, 1807-1868</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1839-1870</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_4bb0f87b2897e118c06010cd92d21591"> 1 volume (96 pages)  ;
 30 x 24 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_176acb2370739d2ef2210ee0335e7f7b"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 10</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_abaef15b954f317f845a09b061fedcc2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The scrapbook has a leather label on front cover reading "L.C. Scraps" and a calling card on the back cover reading "Lansdowne Place: Miss Carr."  The scrapbook is structured tête-bêche, so that it begins from both front and back covers, with blank pages in the middle. This suggests that at least two people contributed material to the book. Given the "L.C." in the title and the material's content, one probable compiler of the book was Laura Carr (1807-1868), who was the daughter of Thomas William Carr (1770-1829) and married Robert Monsey Rolfe (1790-1868) (created Baron Cranworth in 1850).  A number of elaborate Valentines addressed to "Laura" are included, plus various newspaper articles about Lord Cranworth (who twice served as Lord Chancellor). Most of the material specifically related to Laura occurs in the first half of the scrapbook, which is considerably more personal, and includes Valentines, love poems, riddles, letters, and sketches. The second half consists largely of newspaper clippings and printed engravings (most from after Laura's death).</p>
                  <p>Dates of the material suggest that the scrapbook was begun from the front cover (probably by Laura), and that someone began adding material from the back after Laura Carr's death in 1868. Laura could not have contributed all of the front material, however, since the notices on Charles Dickens' death post-date her, while one final item, an etching, is labeled "given to me by Margaret Wilson in London in 1871." It may be that the second compiler initially began adding material to the front, and then decided to flip the scrapbook around. This person may also have pasted the upside-down bookplate to the back cover reading "Miss Carr Lansdowne Place." It is possible the unidentified contributor is Laura's older sister Fanny Carr, who lived until 1880 and by 1872 was the only surviving sibling.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_512e289b774a13eb6ed28d521d0f8814a6c991ff"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Scrapbooks</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Frances Rebecca</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84123147" source="naf">
                     <part>Cranworth, Robert Monsey Rolfe, Baron, 1790-1868</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_2f0f3392e9be43e36f8128834fe60f871c4ca9f2"
                            rules="aacr"
                            source="lcsh">
                     <part>Cranworth, Laura Rolfe, Lady, 1807-1868</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">The history of the family of Carr of Dunston Hill, Co. Durham</emph> : and the collateral lines in England / by Colonel Ralph Edward Carr ... and by Cuthbert Ellison Carr (C.E.). London : Mitchell and Hughes, 1893-1899.</unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                        <part>Carr, Ralph Edward</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1893-1899</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c364311daccd18f99bafe674ce77c8ea"> 3 volumes 
:  illustrations 
;  38 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6ba7b2682d28a3c9f4caee59260fd686"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 11-13</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c7f2b8826a96914c08544632f58b973a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The copy was owned by Thomas William Carr (of Barming), and includes his significant annotations and corrections, along with inserted correspondence, photographs, and sketches (by Anna Margaret Carr).</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_028173a231a37bf55d5aa5e1aec9654c07f948c0"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Genealogies</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname identifier="dts_743330b1cbbc2abb676811fb87592f57026ca97d" source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr, Anna Margaret, 1797-1872</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Eshott Heugh notebook</emph> : volume 1</unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                        <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1881-1899</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_cf15d555a9c0f5be74465559d0186fc2"> 1 volume (138 pages) 
;  23 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_28c1f0bb441d295cc605ffa06d9f7941"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2d732edd49b320750d4a125eda6fdccd"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_28c1f0bb441d295cc605ffa06d9f7941">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bf4636165023f1da8e38d761e7c378d1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Thomas William Carr kept two notebooks, both stamped Eshott Heugh in gilt on the cover, which served in part as personal journals, as well as records of the Carr family and the Eshott estate.</p>
                  <p>The first notebook includes material from 1881 to about 1899, and includes: notes on the Eshott Heugh estate, including comments relating to its magnetic and astronomical position made by the royal astronomer; a history of the estate and its owners; notes on visitors to the estate; sketches of memebers of the Carr family; and the history of various pieces of furniture at the estate.</p>
                  <p>While most of the notebook appears to be the work of Thomas William Carr, shorter sections were also written by Robert Lancelot Carr (b. 1863) and Frank Carr.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Diaries</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
                  <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Robert Lancelot</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912 -- Diaries</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Frank</part>
                  </persname>
                  <corpname identifier="dts_81d70d7580125aed5497700bd92cfa6a02354889" source="lcsh">
                     <part>Eshott House (Alnwick, England)</part>
                  </corpname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref45" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Eshott Heugh notebook</emph> : volume 2</unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                        <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1899-1912</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_58fa1bf8fa6cd9ed72b5e9d51f2cb52c"> 1 volume (circa 200 pages, with blanks) 
;  23 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_061599ee03f985d7ca63d531cb60dfe2"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8e8fbd6d6c82e5c86abc187a12ea7740"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_061599ee03f985d7ca63d531cb60dfe2">2</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_51946aae63f318db9da41e25a958a45f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The second of the two Eshott Heugh notebooks resumes in 1899. Like the first, it serves as a journal for Thomas William Carr, and also includes: more family history; Carr family coats of arms; notes on maintenance of the estate; notes on social visits and the weather; verse; and letters written to Carr. The end of the volume includes an index (to both notebooks).</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Diaries</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
                  <corpname identifier="dts_81d70d7580125aed5497700bd92cfa6a02354889" source="lcsh">
                     <part>Eshott House (Alnwick, England)</part>
                  </corpname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912 -- Diaries</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Diary of Harriet Carr (Deacon)</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_75914fe890029b8c0c5b038617b57b9663969e36" source="lcsh">
                        <part>Carr, Harriet, 1829-1889</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1869</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_979b483fcd48755db9d375f0996f6e14"> 1 volume (42 pages, with blanks) 
;  13 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f70254657ed98d92dba3933be33d67ef"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_56b7703ab159f4a738ec3bc9a759fda4"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f70254657ed98d92dba3933be33d67ef">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1065934ae35d6000f37b7269e23bea4f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The first part of the diary describes a family holiday to Bath and Lynmouth in August and September 1869. Harriet describes her family's enjoyment of the beach and natural scenery of the area. The family took several day trips to nearby locations, where Harriet purchased some souvenirs, including photographs.</p>
                  <p>The second part describes the family's journey to France and Italy from 24 November to 10 December, 1869. Harriet provides sketches of Roman history when recording her observations of sites such as a Coliseum. She also describes in detail the architectural qualities of various churches that they visited in France and Italy.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027112"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Diaries</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname identifier="dts_75914fe890029b8c0c5b038617b57b9663969e36" source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr, Harriet, 1829-1889 -- Diaries</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref51" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Armorial notebook</emph> : with Carr genealogy</unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                        <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1878-1902?</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_e52f12e3bc8bae68650c6ff3429fa670"> 1 volume (46 pages, with numerous items tipped in or laid in) 
;  28 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_e24aaa20f3889c7ca2c231905b1d20bc"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3bc2009bc16991af53ad70f48fcacfff"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e24aaa20f3889c7ca2c231905b1d20bc">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d92accfe27317deed95b9db3c5baf580">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The compiler of the notebook is unrecorded, but it is probably Thomas William Carr (of Barming). Most of the contents concern the coats of arms of the Carr family, and those of related families. The volume includes manuscript notes, assorted printed material (tipped in), engravings of coats of arms, drawings of arms (many colored), and letters to Thomas William Carr.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <subject source="lcsh">
                     <part>Devices (Heraldry)</part>
                  </subject>
                  <genreform source="aat">
                     <part>Coats of arms</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform source="rbgenr">
                     <part>Armorials</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref54" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Chart shewing the descendants of Thomas William Carr of Eshott Heugh.</emph> London : Mitchell and Hughes, 1887.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_ffa47fc27eceb0b5200e98c544fa6ed5"> 1 volume (1 sheet) 
;  55 x 77 cm, folded to 30 x 20 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6243da6f4968a3b31144287079279456"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ff3a27da9cb3e5aa8a3bacb62ef2817f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6243da6f4968a3b31144287079279456">5-7</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_80054a639e1551e63f5e7a460418a55b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Three copies of a genealogical chart, privately printed in December, 1887. The chart documents the Carr family of Eshott Heugh beginning with the marriage of Thomas William Carr to Frances Morgan (a match which resulted in eight children, many of whom feature prominently in the present collection).</p>
                  <p>All three copies are annotated (to varying degrees) by Thomas William Carr (of Barming). The first copy includes minimal additional information concerning T.W. Carr's own entry, that of his wife Harriet, and that of his sister Lucy Emily.</p>
                  <p>The second copy has 10 additional pages bound in (preceding the chart) in which  Carr has written out a series of genealogical tables showing the descent of the Ellison and Woodward branches of the Carr family.  Interspersed are biographical notes on members of the family.  Also laid in to this section is a photographic reproduction of a portrait miniature of Matthew Carr Hexham.</p>
                  <p>The third and final copy contains the most prolific additions. These include: several printed pedigrees of the Carr family, from unidentified sources; manuscript notes on Carr arms, mottos, and genealogical matters; a heavily annotated version of the title genealogical chart; several pages of notes, much later, recording "Egerton-Warburton Cousins"; and a printed chart showing the "Pedigree of Bonner of Newcastle-on-Tyne."</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_028173a231a37bf55d5aa5e1aec9654c07f948c0"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Genealogies</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref57" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Probate of the last will and testament and four codicils of Margaret Lewen Morton, spinster deceased</emph> : dated at Durham the 20th day of August 1823.</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1823 August 20</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_da73fe0767d310d7595891cb41623bc0"> 1 sheet (on vellum) 
;  58 x 64 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_fc5fa5097b4e8bc60d9be2a35d1e10ba"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ae1585628b465ad2228589fdd6b44284"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_fc5fa5097b4e8bc60d9be2a35d1e10ba">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b76bc635d08674a71f4475495ce70fcf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Margaret was the sister of Frances Morton, and the great-aunt of the Rev. Thomas William Carr of Barming.</p>
                  <p>The will has a seal affixed to it, presumably that of the Bishop of Durham. In the will, Margaret makes an array of small bequests of money and personal items to her female family members and close female friends.  A note affixed to the will by a clerk records that she named her brother-in-law, Thomas William Carr, as her executor.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform source="aat">
                     <part>Wills</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname source="local">
                     <part>Morton, Margaret Lewin</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref77" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Carr family documents and letters</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1788-1894</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c7ca1b0932647c2ba4187b3772566302"> 22 items 
;  25 x 20 cm, and smaller </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_c6e419abce0477fc4bad45bcb68a040c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d5daf802e714d266c43a923de32ef6f3"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c6e419abce0477fc4bad45bcb68a040c">9</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0b4e643832684d55413fa79381458891">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes correspondence and printed documents or forms. The items were collected in a contemporary file labeled "Documents &amp; old letters relating to the Carrs: photographs and paintings." They are now removed to a new folder; the original is retained.</p>
                  <p>The authors of the correspondence are varied and largely unidentified. Recipients include the Lord Bishop of Cloyne, Miss Edgeworth; Harriet Carr (nee Deacon); Mrs. H. L. Carr; and Mr. Thomas Woodward.</p>
                  <p>Documents include: a newspaper clipping narrating the naval feats of Sir C. Ogle of Kirkley, a member of the Ogle branch of the Carr family; the certificate of baptism of Thomas William Carr, 1801; the marriage certificate of Thomas William Carr and Harriet Deacon; death certificate of Susan Carr, 1834; the marriage certificate of Mark William Carr and Elizabeth Collinson, 1 December 1788; and the will of Frances Carr's father, 1798.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Correspondence </part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">The raid of the Kers, by the Ettrick Shepherd</emph>. [London] : Thomas Kell, 1876.</unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80062998" source="naf">
                        <part>Hogg, James, 1770-1835</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1876</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_79b78c747c5e24c09dbda5b72e0a1165"> 1 volume ([6], 27, [3], v, [1] p., [8] leaves of plates) 
;  26 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_37a536100d7f7380d62690e2ce08e5b6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5aa3c6b8c5ae96182e03905ed087f868"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_37a536100d7f7380d62690e2ce08e5b6">10</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_839578ad21a998d7472fa5ce44704d4e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>A ballad, by James Hogg, originally published in Blackwood's Magazine, December, 1830. Lithographically reproduced. The final 8 pages contain "Notes with armorial bearings of the ancient family of Ker."</p>
                  <p>The present copy was owned by Thomas William Carr of Barming. It includes, tipped in at end, two letters from R. Thompson (?) concerning the book.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <persname identifier="dts_b7c27df164820b85a10517f6fd8a218f02952c88" source="naf">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas William, 1830-1912</part>
                  </persname>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref80" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="bold">
                        <part>Christ the believer's life</part>
                     </title> : a sermon preached in the church of Teddington, Middlesex, on Sunday, July 13, 1834, on occasion of the lamented death of Susan, the beloved wife of the Rev. T.W. Carr ... By the Rev. James Hough, A.M. ... </unittitle>
                  <origination label="creator">
                     <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                        <part>Hough, James</part>
                     </persname>
                  </origination>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1834?</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_d7cfc6d5b9689be93d45d11c135b091b"> 1 volume ([4] p., p. 251-278) 
;  19 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_6700370ba88b2851e69b476cc1a1bc92"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_62e32ad370131c8056cb3b843fa15ab8"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6700370ba88b2851e69b476cc1a1bc92">11</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4d5b58cb694092c0bc13402c353c5398">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Printed sermon on the occasion of the death of Susan Carr. Given the page numbering in the present volume, it appears that the sermon was once part of a larger collection. The binding of the present copy is gilt-stamped. T.W.C.</p>
                  <p>The copy appears to have belonged to multiple members of the Carr family, including Thomas William Carr, Harriet Carr, and Elizabeth Carr. Affixed to the rear pastedown is a lithographed portrait of an unidentified woman, almost certainly Susan Carr. Opposite the portrait is noted, "The etching [sic] and sermon were done at her mother's expense. Letter of T.W.C."</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026669"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Sermons</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Susan Hamilton</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref3" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Photographs, etc.</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
            </did>
            <c id="ref63" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Album of Carr family portrait photographs</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1865-1899</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a9afcc1630c8ab9b2f3f61c2954c8e25"> 1 volume (46 photographs) 
;  16 x 13 cm </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_7235c035c0710f12ba2b12c3500a809c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 14</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_214277c332a700144467933587e3f512">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Comprises portrait photographs of individual members of the Carr family. The inside front cover of the album is inscribed: "The Children of T.W. Carr, Rector of Barming." Mounts of the photographs have been labeled in a single (much later?) hand. The majority of photographs appear to be albumen prints.</p>
                  <p>The album includes portraits of T.W. Carr, Harriet Carr, Mary Carr, Thomas Carr, Robert Carr, Al (Alured) Carr, Laura Carr, Frank Carr, and Margaret Carr. The first photograph depicts Barming Rectory (with Carr family members in the foreground).</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300127121"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Albumen prints</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Photographs</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300015637"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Portraits</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref86" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Framed images</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">19th century</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_0922d54d889a9d2716ada35160b9d3da"> 3 items 
</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9ce2b21e6dd7bff0527f326c0fa55921"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">Oversize 15</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cc71d14de79e5636a6341fc6111abff7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes a framed tintype photograph of a young girl in a dress carrying a basket of flowers.  The image depicts Mary Joanna Sophia Carr, the eldest child of the Rev. Thomas William Carr (of Barming).</p>
                  <p>The second image is a silhouette portrait, perhaps lithographed, of a middle-aged man. The subject is probably the family patriarch, the eldest Thomas William Carr.</p>
                  <p>The third and final framed image is a small portrait, drawn in graphite, of Margaret Lewen Morton. A note on the reverse reads: "Copied by Miss Ethel Baruster (?) from one belonging to Mr Russell of Hatchford. A fair copy, but the lower part of the nose is larger than the original."</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/graphicMaterials/tgm004700"
                             source="gmgpc">
                     <part>Graphite drawings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300015423"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Silhouettes</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300134759"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Tintypes (prints)</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300015637"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Portraits</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <persname source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Thomas</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname rules="aacr" source="local">
                     <part>Carr, Mary Joanna Sophia</part>
                  </persname>
                  <persname source="local">
                     <part>Morton, Margaret Lewin</part>
                  </persname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref66" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Photographs of the Carr family at Barming and Linnington</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1876-1931?</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_56feb2804f031077acf7b2d35ec6a095"> 20 photographs 
:  albumen and b&amp;w 
;  20 x 15 cm, and smaller </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_053d1dd29f0997a5f4e598aaa2be5210"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d16baeead2c9db7c68b9c34d6344398e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_053d1dd29f0997a5f4e598aaa2be5210">12</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d4ca6fb4d777a52b8b53e6fd47995171">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Loose photographs, collected in a contemporary file labeled "Old family photographs, and Carrs at Barming &amp; Linnington." The photographs have been removed to a new folder; the original is retained.</p>
                  <p>Many of the photo subjects or sitters are unidentified. There are several photographs of painted portraits of Carr ancestors. Identifiable subjects include: Marjorie Fitzherbert (1907 and 1910/1911); William Carr (from a painting, 1709); Frank Collett Carr(?); Harriet Carr (?); and the Eshott Heugh property.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300015637"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Portraits</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300127121"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Albumen prints</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Photographs</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300054230"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Travel photography</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref69" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Photographs of the Carr family</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">Late 19th century?</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_728868ff95f543d9747acf52ce3ab26e"> circa 50 photographs 
:  albumen and b&amp;w prints 
;  19 x 12 cm, and smaller </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_f3989fdeff6d5feefa845f72c7d1a278"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_652128d477bf2ffef68e205d5e95b0f9"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f3989fdeff6d5feefa845f72c7d1a278">13</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_612e1e8897b0a55b2f0c29d8e6b3399e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Loose photographs, collected in a contemporary file labeled "Documents &amp; old letters relating to the Carrs: photographs and paintings." The photographs have been removed to two new folders; the original file is retained.</p>
                  <p>Many of the photo subjects or sitters are unidentified. There are numerous photographs of painted portraits of Carr ancestors. Identifiable people include: Thomas Carr, d. 1793 (painting); Thomas Woodward, Sheriff of Bristol, 1636 (painting); Frances Carr, née Morton; Arthur Saplé Webb; T.W. Carr in 1838; a sketch by Andrew Morton of T.W.C. circa 1825; Francis Woodward MD at Bath; Rebecca Carr (painting); Sarah Morton (painting); Sir William Ogle (painting); and Margaret and Lucy Carr at St. John's College, 1890.</p>
                  <p>Identifiable places (in the second folder) include: the Pont Marengo in the French town of Carcassonne; San Sebastian, Interior de la Iglesia Santa Maria; Bayonne, la Théatre; Cairo (?); Haddon Hall; several beach scenes, including Biarritz; the Crescent, Buxton; and Ludchurch.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300015637"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Portraits</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300127121"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Albumen prints</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Photographs</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300054230"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Travel photography</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <famname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85020455"
                           source="lcsh">
                     <part>Carr family</part>
                  </famname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref73" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Engravings of prominent homes in Northamptonshire and Northumberland</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">mid-19th century</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_a86cec68398a96b12fc791d5c753ed88"> 11 engravings 
;  20 x 13 cm, and smaller </physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_57bbd680a4e33447c9c24af6b96fb8d5"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bc5f44075f83850ba848438f1880f447"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_57bbd680a4e33447c9c24af6b96fb8d5">14</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e59f47972bfb1af06f05230cc89e96aa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Engravings collected in a contemporary file labeled "Documents &amp; old letters relating to the Carrs: photographs and paintings." The engravings are now removed to a new folder; the original is retained.</p>
                  <p>Subjects depicted include: Chipchase Castle, Northumberland, seat of John Reed; Wollaton, Northamptonshire in 1667; Rushton Hall, Northamptonshire, seat of the Hon. Mr. C. Medlycott; Kirby Hall, Northamptonshire; Bamborough Castle, Northumberland; Heaton Hall, seat of Sir Matthew White Ridley; Tynemouth Priory; Faxton Chapel, Northampton; and Battle Stone, or Percy Cross, Northumberland.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="dts_aabc7ec7f748be9e97a3e84d979e14014b180853"
                             source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Engravings</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2009122135"
                           source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
                     <part>Country homes -- Great Britain</part>
                  </subject>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Northumberland (England)</part>
                  </geogname>
                  <geogname source="lcsh">
                     <part>Northamptonshire (England)</part>
                  </geogname>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
            <c id="ref83" level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <emph render="bold">Webb family photographs</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">circa 1930-1980</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_c79a49bc54a0c1ecbe2d2c0d66178c0d"> 26 photographs 
</physdesc>
                  <container id="aspace_9aa4e8bad4aaed1751df9e68bce0c4e2"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c683521ff447cd1d78acfe6b794bfaf8"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9aa4e8bad4aaed1751df9e68bce0c4e2">15</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_57fa6ab2eaf7d3915351b6c10f833129">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>The items were housed in a file labeled "Webb Family Snaps and L.J.W. at Various Stages of her Career. Australian Family and Friends." They are now removed to a new folder; the original is retained.</p>
                  <p>The photos depict members the Webb family of Australia, an offshoot of the Carr family. Some of the family members pictured here may be related to those named in genealogical tables drawn in the 1960s or 1970s labeled as "Egerton-Warburton Cousins" which feature in Item 7. Also included are a few newspaper and magazine clippings that feature members of the Webb family and a program for a funeral service and an informational pamphlet about St. David's, Wales.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <controlaccess>
                  <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300"
                             source="Art and Architecture Thesaurus">
                     <part>Photographs</part>
                  </genreform>
                  <subject source="local">
                     <part>Webb family</part>
                  </subject>
               </controlaccess>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
