<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/divinity.265">divinity.265</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Morse Family Papers: William Reginald and Anne Crosse Kinney Morse
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Morse Family Papers: William Reginald and Anne Crosse Kinney Morse</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by Morgan Gagne and Martha Lund Smalley</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Yale University Divinity School Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>409 Prospect Street</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06511</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">divinity.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://web.library.yale.edu/divinity/special-collections"
                       linktitle="http://web.library.yale.edu/divinity/special-collections"
                       show="new">http://web.library.yale.edu/divinity/special-collections</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2015</date>
            <num>RG 265</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencyname>Yale University Divinity School Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>finding aid prepared according to local divinity library descriptive practices.</abbr>
         <citation/>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-11-05T23:02:21+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.4.1.yale.hm.mm</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Monday November  5, 2018 at 23:02</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Morse Family Papers: William Reginald and Anne Crosse Morse</unittitle>
         <unitid>RG 265</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Yale University Divinity School Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>2</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(5 boxes)</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1909">1909</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1940">1940</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_7694ddb153528ca43ed32fda933903c4">Medical missionary William Reginald Morse and his wife Anne (Anna) Crosse Kinney Morse served under the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society in China from 1909 to 1937. Substantive correspondence describes the daily life and work of the Morses, their travels, medical practice and education in China, and the turbulent political and social situation in China during this era. The Morses were based primarily Chengdu, Sichuan Province and at the West China Union University.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84805612" source="naf">
               <part>Morse, William R. (William Reginald), 1874-1939</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2ab1214878d3492100c055daf07c5814">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased in cooperation with the Harvey Cushing/John Hay Medical Library of Yale University in 2014.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_3a604a5870e17dd9c4b0fad4ede4d355">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Morse Family Papers: William Reginald and Anna Crosse Kinney Morse (RG 265), Special Collections, Yale Divinity Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b81948d45fd00123daeaa1dbae6ac73c">
         <head>Associated Materials</head>
         <p>The Morse Family Papers acquired by Yale in 2014 have been divided into two sections. The Morse Family Papers: William Reginald Morse and Anna Crosse Kinney Morse are held by the Yale Divinity Library while the Morse Family Papers: Marjorie Morse and Photographs are held by the Medical Historical Library.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <bioghist id="aspace_2bee8cf6aaf36ecab432f9137f52b92f">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Dr. William Reginald Morse (1874-1939) was born August 30, 1874 in Lawrencetown, Nova Scotia, Canada, the son of Ellen Marry Fitch and Leander Rupert Morse. He received his medical degree from McGill University in 1902 and later did postgraduate work at Harvard University, Johns Hopkins University, and the University College of London, receiving a B.A., M.D., C.M, F.A.C.S., L.L.D, and F.R.G.S.</p>
         <p>Dr. Morse practiced medicine in Rhode Island and Nova Scotia before being appointed in 1909 as medical missionary to China serving under the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society with his wife, Anna Crosse Kinney Morse (1875-1951), whom he had married in 1903. The Morses had one daughter, Marjorie, born in 1913.</p>
         <p>Upon arrival in China the Morses traveled to Sichuan Province, West China, where Dr. Morse worked at a small missionary hospital for a few years. In 1914 Morse was sent to the provincial capital, Chengdu, where he helped found a medical school at West China Union University, an institution supported by various Protestant mission agencies. He was elected as Dean of the WCUU Medical School in 1919, Director of the College of Medicine and Dentistry in 1935, and was Professor of Anatomy and Surgery at West China Union University until his retirement in 1937. Dr. Morse also held positions at the Baptist College, and the Methodist Hospital in Chengdu. He served at the Hankow International Hospital during the revolution of 1911-1912 and at Lingnan University in Canton from 1927 to 1928.</p>
         <p>In addition to his medical practice, Morse published five works relating to the history and practice of medicine in China and Tibet, including "The Practices and Principles of Chinese Medicine" and "A Memorandum on the Chinese Procedure of Acupuncture" in 1926. His major work was "The Three Crosses In The Purple Mists;: An Adventure In Medical Education Under The Eaves Of The Roof Of The World", published in 1928. Morse also did research and writing in the field of anthropology, publishing, for example an article titled "Schedule of Physical Anthropological Measurements and Observations on Ten Ethnic Groups of Szechwan Province, West China" in the Journal of the West China Border Research Society in 1937. Morse was the first president of the West China Border Research Society, and did much to maintain interest in its growth and development. He served as a research associate at the Peabody Museum at Harvard University in 1930-1931.</p>
         <p>Dr. Morse passed away in the United States in November 1939.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4a3a662bd73286a9dfaf22e5d0dd9f5a">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection provides valuable documentation of the life and work of medical missionary William Reginald Morse and his wife Anne (Anna) Crosse Kinney Morse, who served under the American Baptist Foreign Mission Society in China from 1909 to 1937. Very detailed and substantive correspondence describes the daily life and work of the Morses, their travels, and the turbulent political and social situation in China during this era. Based primarily Chengdu, Sichuan Province and at the West China Union University, the Morses also spent time in Shanghai and other areas.</p>
         <p>The Morse Family Papers acquired by Yale in 2014 have been divided into two sections. This collection at the Yale Divinity LIbrary includes papers of William Reginald Morse and Anna Crosse Kinney Morse while the Morse Family Papers: Marjorie Morse and Photographs are held by the Medical Historical Library.</p>
         <p>The first series, Family Correspondence, includes many multi-paged letters from Dr. and Mrs. Morse to relatives in Nova Scotia and, after 1927, to their daughter Marjorie (born in 1913 in China) while she was attending an American high school, Wellesley College, and Yale Nursing School. These letters describe events such as the Morse family's 1909 initial long trip, traveling 1,800 miles inland from Shanghai, perilous travels by boat and by train, assistance to rural Chinese and military casualties caused by the fighting between Chinese warlords, the growth of Communism, and the Morses' religious, professional, and social interactions with the overall missionary and Chinese Christian community.</p>
         <p>The second series, General Correspondence, includes primarily letters of condolence written to Anna Morse following the death of Dr. Morse in November 1939.</p>
         <p>The third series, Writings and Notes, includes papers written by Dr. Morse including a medical report, two articles, and an essay regarding Chinese medicine and his medical work. This series also includes a book review of Morse's work "The Three Crosses in the Purple Mist" and several handwritten notes.</p>
         <p>The fourth series, Personal Items and Memorabilia, includes biographical documentation regarding Dr. Morse, a friendship calendar with notes and photographs from supporters, and other memorabilia.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_71d6596caef41323b20fd64d68e3e8ff">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <list listtype="unordered">
            <item>I. Family Correspondence</item>
            <item>II. General Correspondence</item>
            <item>III. Writings and Notes</item>
            <item>IV. Personal Items and Memorabilia</item>
         </list>
      </arrangement>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_43a29b7d15f588d78a2573e9d315f2a3">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008107861"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Missions -- China</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85086083"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Missions, Medical</part>
         </subject>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n84805612" source="naf">
            <part>Morse, William R. (William Reginald), 1874-1939</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="dts_4911f18b44ba0b1508487188112749a090bcf8b8" source="lcsh">
            <part>Morse, Anne Crosse Kinney</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n78043381"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>American Baptist Foreign Mission Society</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Family Correspondence</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1909-1937</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>W. R. Morse (WRM) and Anne Crosse Kinney Morse (ACM) to Mother and Rose en route to China</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1909 September-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_9f625aa18a34d4f6a4f93238f6cf791c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_79331f8c5ba9ad1dc69d290665181676"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9f625aa18a34d4f6a4f93238f6cf791c">1</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bdb430e7e95a5dd6a025a2d34289b604">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>William Reginald Morse was known as "Reg" and Anne Crosse Kinney Morse was known as "Anna". Letters describe travel to China and exploration of new scenes and cities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Shanghai, boat on Yangtze River, Ichang</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1909 November</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_0e685602d1d1e970ca569ad5bcec35a0"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_47b1ac59adfabcf578c9abdd6e39eb54"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_0e685602d1d1e970ca569ad5bcec35a0">2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from boat on Yangtze River, Chungking (Chongqing)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1909 December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_817445d47ec71aa2c033d9e5d6085a97"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_761fee9d3ffdc4700e0c6560005f8df1"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_817445d47ec71aa2c033d9e5d6085a97">3</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_13a6e68979d22fcaa31f5d4400adc690">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of operation of houseboat WRM is traveling on, landslides in the Yangtze River, Chinese language study, and WRM's medical work on passengers and workers aboard</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother and Rose from boat on Yangtze River, Suifu (Yibin)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 January</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_70a4484f8c3f299de728ef102077ce81"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e536c8ea54ef8333909747e0bd37589d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_70a4484f8c3f299de728ef102077ce81">4</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7bd0cfad5c561ac1cef320ebba4a40fe">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of treatment of patients along the way to Suifu, arrival in Suifu, and the beginning of WRM's Chinese language study.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to Mother and Rose from Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 January-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_ac4104a3ce0146eae094b0044f11e866"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_66577e48e5cfbcabbb279bcb757123cd"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ac4104a3ce0146eae094b0044f11e866">5</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_136de64dda6907535e8307005a87bd26">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Arrival in China, plans for house.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 February</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_0f31ba705bb19baef96459238834c8ef"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0574d508417ba0c2f3512ffc269ab605"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_0f31ba705bb19baef96459238834c8ef">6</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0f9bab2b790974c274db1e95da294e90">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Descriptions of Chinese people, homes, customs, and WRM's anxiety to learn the Chinese language and begin hospital work.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 March-April</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_9a9250fb34dadd0d75873bedc667c6e1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_602fc380fb4c30a2ce6d0e6e54eef83c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9a9250fb34dadd0d75873bedc667c6e1">7</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7d9f4440769fa13e0c2992886f442faf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of WRM and ACM's move into new house, Chinese customs (such as clothing, women's bound feet, and ancestral worship), and WRM's visit to his teacher's home.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu, Chungking summer bungalow</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 May</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_c826868fbb037c38383d66ab5cf9e897"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9aef7d640fb718579062e96a70975043"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c826868fbb037c38383d66ab5cf9e897">8</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_81b7fae9648ed4acc5cadc37e96cb7ba">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM's visits to patients, learning of Chinese medical remedies, and move to summer bungalow.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Chungking summer bungalow</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_30cb888fbbbff1a52a740c32f888c0cf"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1e24ad8c476b451a96af0e77598186b1"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_30cb888fbbbff1a52a740c32f888c0cf">9</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c5bc23394bdafb02d7f535f91dfe9725">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Severe storm damage to bungalows, Chinese wedding and feasts, and continuation of language study.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother and Walter from Chungking, Ichang</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 July</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_1b5bea73ceccb02d4e2f5ea446134b91"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0c8f54004fb6f56bbdc7e33fbd568fda"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1b5bea73ceccb02d4e2f5ea446134b91">10</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3cdb57de36cf2e63f838ff33284ee107">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Weather in China (overwhelming heat and insects), WRM's attendance at a childbirth, WRM and ACM's 26-day travel from Chungking to Ichang.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother and Lew from Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_4061cac6be845c0abe025d81834b10a0"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_be8efdfdcfe1f8f3d2beeeb9a6574b3a"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4061cac6be845c0abe025d81834b10a0">11</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3c4fcfb12f5ff2d39ecacd0bf80cd2ee">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Death and funeral of a Chinese Christian evangelist: the transportation of his body to his home, Chinese ancestor worship in graveyard, and Chinese feast.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Chungking, Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 September</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_74b51123a68f7ca76f39278d2664ed2e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a21a6d19b10e46cc5cbcb846e851e7f3"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_74b51123a68f7ca76f39278d2664ed2e">12</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2a1334ae2091c527d4bb5fe611adfeda">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM and ACM move back to Suifu from summer bungalow in Chungking, visit a wildlife park and salt mine.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu, boat on Yangtze River, Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_85752515083ffb8e1cf1d85627e1f8be"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a9a40572aff62f4a908434e4ceae3373"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_85752515083ffb8e1cf1d85627e1f8be">13</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9dca54fd99e469400372319b58a9bf52">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes description of the failing health of fellow missionary Dr. Lewis, WRM's escort of Lewis' family to Chungking, and WRM's visits to Chinese hospitals and British gunboat.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from boat on Yangtze River, Ichang, Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910 November-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_08c0e6ddbc55891d860932680a2e3543"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8d7c435a90078d701ac8ca3ff7e9b0d3"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_08c0e6ddbc55891d860932680a2e3543">14</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0ec163fefc9063b7fa8b222eafd0a962">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Two-week return trip by houseboat to Suifu, the one-year anniversary of WRM's "active service" in China, river trip with a missionary and native evangelist, and return to Suifu.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu, Yachow</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 January</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_8353c1bf93bebe4e8505f6aaaf74f0be"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_100dfded248fadebd60c843763b44b32"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_8353c1bf93bebe4e8505f6aaaf74f0be">15</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0525848be0a39c77dedcd81280b06166">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM and ACM on 10-day trip to Yachow for a conference; description of Chinese hotels and travel on river, and Chinese New Year customs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref42" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Yachow, Chengtu (Chengdu), boat on Chengtu River</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 February</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_81cf37c5ceb2c3d63f2e6cd6ee86092e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fdc4b19a9dc0548a7490da3d83e29708"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_81cf37c5ceb2c3d63f2e6cd6ee86092e">16</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6ecf1254f58d496577b7bc631d2d3418">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM meeting with other missionaries, talk of some missions combining hospital work and religious work, and hospitality in Chengtu (Chengdu)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref44" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 March-April</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_5a850f8d3436ab33fb966712e878d33d"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_27988508d70e914de738e2d0e714f441"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_5a850f8d3436ab33fb966712e878d33d">17</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_99e553a686c7f5cab5de4d0d8bb72715">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM's return to Suifu, Chinese-language study and medical work, the death of the missionary Salquist from typhoid fever, and a shortage of workers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to Mother and Rose from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 April 2</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_26fc2eab1c4df578e73196b25315c4ae"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0480a832df33583136c78e38cd8d8041"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_26fc2eab1c4df578e73196b25315c4ae">18</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0acf4c0643dece571ee773dfc768b602">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Description of gifts that were sent to WRM and ACM from ACM's family, book recommendations for ACM's family, and life in the countryside of China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref48" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_bb79db1da9a5cacd50798289941b13d4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d4a8565bb136be0568661b961c82b25e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_bb79db1da9a5cacd50798289941b13d4">19</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_83ff8da4f4c2a4f909b2d897125b9b11">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding weather in China and problems with getting supplies.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref50" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Chungking summer bungalow, Kiating</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 July-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_aab08a981f265c4ec8e103294cf3c2b6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3ad22c6c30e9e3968c77b1deb603cd29"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_aab08a981f265c4ec8e103294cf3c2b6">20</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3e22aa0c6af26c378ef635432808ae84">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Daily life at summer bungalow in Chungking, trip to Kiating (Leshan), and the treatment of patients in Kiating.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref52" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu, Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 September-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_5b9e677103f09a3915017cee82785a0e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7d64d9de7958132fd3630d31a409c515"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_5b9e677103f09a3915017cee82785a0e">21</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_abd7e64a5394948f37a3c14fa8e7d38f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding government unrest and missionaries' removal to Chungking and Shanghai. WRM granted permission to stay in Chungking to work in hospitals, anxious to get back to Chengtu.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref54" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother and Walter from Chungking, Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 November</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_9badba510aaab9559ad2595f528a58d6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_38fb12a6fe998222b173aaf573de88fd"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9badba510aaab9559ad2595f528a58d6">22</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8715787a34b6cfb809e9d3551db450f7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Rebellion brings death to many Chinese, many missionaries forced to move but WRM able to stay in Chungking.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref56" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Ichang, Hankow (Wuhan)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911 December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_dac1622e6d7c4659c857508f630e05af"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0aeddaa813245a055948caafcd003b84"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_dac1622e6d7c4659c857508f630e05af">23</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b0f235da28efdc731beedf6372e68fad">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's removal from Chungking station by British Consul, arrival in Hankow, and destruction of the city. WRM working with the Red Cross at Hankow International Hospital.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref58" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Hankow, Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 January-February</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_c2ea9a0f84d8b4700eb837c1db40e7e3"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a5070a6714faaf7aa926f8d80859d570"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c2ea9a0f84d8b4700eb837c1db40e7e3">24</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_897fce1afafcc72095d0a93f9a0feeab">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding the ending of WRM's work at Hankow International Hospital, temporary travel to Shanghai, and WRM turning down an offer to care for the wounded and famished at a hospital along the line of TienTsui Pakow Railway.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref60" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 March-April</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_222a4ec47cc0675c86d5aedb03d3b972"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7b96372954e9a972d69b6a41357c79f8"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_222a4ec47cc0675c86d5aedb03d3b972">25</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2659ebd94230100d94f046ba898f76a5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM attending a language school in Shanghai. Missionaries receive appeal to volunteer for distribution food for famine relief; WRM joins this effort</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref62" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Shanghai, Kuling</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 May-July</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_466001adc302bb6660bcb7dec8840217"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2922f29ca8c84460612199c153a2f164"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_466001adc302bb6660bcb7dec8840217">26</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_956160c891afdde593b45bf4075ae7e6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM leaving Shanghai, river trip to Kuling (Lushan District), and resort in Kuling.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref64" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Rose, Lew, and Mother from Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 June-November</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_35c929b67b34c9d723b1445450e0b988"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c6168779d363e9c286a22e62602f32c6"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_35c929b67b34c9d723b1445450e0b988">27</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9ee002b18b40f7078e22a5982cdd4ab2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding WRM and ACM's celebration of ninth anniversary of marriage and ACM's medical emergency and eventual recovery from kidney problem.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref66" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Kuling, boat on the Yangtze River, Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 August-September</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_81bc9c4de293d16d13632950433d5b3a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1fa225f4129b39575f7c601cf9b81ab5"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_81bc9c4de293d16d13632950433d5b3a">28</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3d1abcaa2c08a1318939b9bf1d584e54">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of Anna's pregnancy and improvement of pregnancy complications, arrival in Chungking to help Dr. McCartney, and WRM's medical courses.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref68" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Ichang, boat on Yangtze River, Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_322441d3a0b624f3f4760150fe8908df"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_90594ada330a3bcfde8bb79a1e0d6d66"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_322441d3a0b624f3f4760150fe8908df">29</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6236b33f3eeb81dcad6e899dfec61a89">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM's travels from Ichang to Chungking (on the way to Suifu) and unsatisfactory conditions on boat.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref70" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from boat on Yangtze River, Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912 November-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178657"
                             id="aspace_356a7cb704dd0c76148c5788de65cc6b"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bd047844e64f3381cf52d2f8769bd11b"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_356a7cb704dd0c76148c5788de65cc6b">30</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4393b638594c4f993cced09ee7fadac8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM arrives in Suifu, reassembles servants, does necessary repairs on house and hospital, prepares to open a dispensary</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref72" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1913 January-February</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_d1c869401a3da0cbcfcc4bd770d7c3f6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5c42f1fc9be1c5f96e42e3ea107fc216"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_d1c869401a3da0cbcfcc4bd770d7c3f6">31</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_22b82b35b093837fe20bcc5e5a3e176d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the continuation of hospital repairs, WRM's busy dispensary and interactions with dispensary patients, and the birth of daughter, Marjorie Morse, on February 24, 1913.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref74" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1913 March-April</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_d5221d9b8a96a6753a474f7aa4d4829b"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_fb9df6f881f692d3b5de7e5158944023"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_d5221d9b8a96a6753a474f7aa4d4829b">32</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a42206a295413f67e1ecd075f8feeed9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding WRM's work with patients in hospital and dispensary and an unusual request from the Cabinet of the New China Republic for prayers that virtuous men be elected and that government be established on a firm foundation.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref76" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1913 May-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_9bc75c83bbf5e53907060f1812fc28de"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_022b3deced2eda4ecf964627032f4cf1"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9bc75c83bbf5e53907060f1812fc28de">33</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_76c545514493bc188da87db3f1d78755">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Continued work at hospital and dispensary; WRM pleased by visit from the officers of a British gunboat in port.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref78" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1913 July-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_1b73b0efb1ec12e789078185272cec17"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2739ce1e342928b700deff9f1d1dd94d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1b73b0efb1ec12e789078185272cec17">34</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_41cabfa96f01110996b421aeef091ebf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Amidst political unrest and tension in China, ACM and Marjorie visit the "hills", WRM continues his hospital work.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref80" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1913 September-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_96ff948ea67607409eb9e423d357e4c8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_36501cb00e29e09c3d4ba85693a0a02a"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_96ff948ea67607409eb9e423d357e4c8">35</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5eccc97de2a30126930b56def6c90a47">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Rebellion in area crushed for a time; hospital full.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref82" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu, Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1913 November-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_2d631de9a8104d0c53b8d46eb4f55bfc"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a591872b530028f21ec877fd0380a56e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_2d631de9a8104d0c53b8d46eb4f55bfc">36</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_41176632212386dba7ad7a636d48a20c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's happiness with his profession, growing fondness towards Marjorie, preparations for conference and thoughts about medical school</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref84" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1914 January-March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_a016fab1f7a4a7d862ee4d84816572aa"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_161364c07d74425c52fecdaba8afaaf4"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a016fab1f7a4a7d862ee4d84816572aa">37</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_78a597a957b1fb0fbb66defdda5863ef">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM turns 40 years old, satisfied with large amounts of work (over 300 operations). He expresses sadness and excitement towards leaving the hospital and going to medical school for new opportunities.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref86" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Chungking, Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1914 April-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_b3fb0e0856283c054ae0bcefb25fd513"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d3f6c727421d7f7b35139a516daef9aa"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b3fb0e0856283c054ae0bcefb25fd513">38</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fe3a8ecd8d240ce8f0a17727ed72333b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Political unrest in China, WRM's treatment of patients who were victims of violence, ACM's illness and recovery, and the celebration of WRM and ACM's eleventh wedding anniversary.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref88" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1914 July-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_90c668fba83e2bb8236eddfceb0ee41f"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_45aac11487222b73101b502e1892cab3"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_90c668fba83e2bb8236eddfceb0ee41f">39</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9c4be849adf55050a4097d4a19640531">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM's continues his hospital work. Description of summer weather and a growing foreign population in China, and WRM's urge to volunteer as a doctor in the European war.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref90" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Suifu, Kiating, boat on the Fu River, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1914 September-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_1e11c7fd29d65d5dc7b61b63e8bcf80d"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_402ae58ef8b4dc19a52c77659588375f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1e11c7fd29d65d5dc7b61b63e8bcf80d">40</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_40c3955ae4a7dd12c34f376e69f67525">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of life in Suifu and the positive experiences of ACM and WRM, WRM waiting to hear back from the medical school, French and German soldiers going off to battle, and the Morse family settling in Chengtu.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref92" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu, Kiating</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1914 November-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_c33ccbaf6bf27a89fbf44e8c9fb15a7f"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c8bf518b6ee5ef5b1b5a651c54c94d9c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c33ccbaf6bf27a89fbf44e8c9fb15a7f">41</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_65172321a9f2d2ef5c9dead6b0b9ec2e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM recommended by the hospital Reference Committee for a teaching position at the West China Union University's Medical Department, the meeting of WRM and ACM's mothers in Brooklyn, and ACM starting to teach English to Chinese students.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref94" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to Mother from Suifu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1915 January-May</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_88c2fa1a0fbaad36ae14c46332c2e82c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a49c804a433249c0ef1d96fcbdf410d0"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_88c2fa1a0fbaad36ae14c46332c2e82c">42</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_823c6780264004007f7f97e170441c13">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding the start of WRM's work conference, Chinese tensions with Japan and the United States growing larger, and WRM's thoughts towards enlisting in the war in Europe.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref96" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to Mother from Chengtu, Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1915 July-November</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_6ed79d975fd40c71ef9de56a5f110828"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_79aab1302f8ced99b217cbf2c154513b"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6ed79d975fd40c71ef9de56a5f110828">43</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4b1e467501e5ef48b2c2aee89ce402e2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes description of WRM's travels in China, the physical changes of WRM and ACM since their arrival in China. WRM now the only foreign teacher in the West China Union University anatomy department.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref98" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to Mother from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1920 August 25</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_676281d550652be432d7162200a0b197"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_21da5171d4037666648635e86180b189"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_676281d550652be432d7162200a0b197">44</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c3f378c80b428e48ad488e7330721a5d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>ACM makes suggestions to mother about how to make life easier and describes Chinese nature, Chinese life, and her meeting at the Natural History Club.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref100" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to Mother from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1921 June-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_00ff74b23148799626a54962f3e0f1ea"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4c1c4073fea9f13bbdd5ea47e3bb8a8d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_00ff74b23148799626a54962f3e0f1ea">45</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_547e505029f7358f3fdf6581c7b468cb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>ACM's life at home and with friends while WRM is away on a trip, encloses letter written by a Mrs. Humphrey about WRM and his life in China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref102" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM, WRM, and Marjorie Morse (MM) to Mother from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1922 January-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_46252ba2a218c3b1992d9fc2b5213da7"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4d5e43d33d2dd4edcfd9ab454a5f1ae7"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_46252ba2a218c3b1992d9fc2b5213da7">46</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d697ea0a424f871432a225e849b2dbaa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes events in the lives of ACM and MM and WRM's travel to Peking.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref104" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM and WRM to Mother and Elsie from Chengtu, Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1923 January-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178665"
                             id="aspace_6996cbb71f8e8b5580d948da30656630"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_786b49d0aacf81ea9c423b7d0b174d7b"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6996cbb71f8e8b5580d948da30656630">47</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67e47ff852fb0e52fc4740db3895fffa">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>ACM worried about the amount of work that WRM is taking on, WRM's thoughts about leaving China for England, life with MM and work at the medical school; ACM teaching English and Drawing classes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref106" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Shanghai, Canton, Hong Kong</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1927 May-November</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_e404874bf46e3f8f2c05fba1c3d0a9e2"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bf2123e0207932bca3604da284fd4aff"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e404874bf46e3f8f2c05fba1c3d0a9e2">48</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cd1342b7cf310c5b5dc421b2e09006a1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the Morse family's move from Shanghai to Canton, daily hospital work and domestic life, MM beginning high school, WRM and ACM living in separate places, growing tensions between Chinese and foreign missionaries.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref108" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to MM from Canton, Hong Kong, Shanghai, Seoul, Onseiri</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1928 January-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_472cc5eb928a1cdaa5535e96019c715a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7854a38b2cc193d3294cf61b9b10636e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_472cc5eb928a1cdaa5535e96019c715a">49</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_df05e7280a08f3abcd43517c07d3c04a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the daily life events of WRM and ACM, WRM and ACM's travels and life events to and in Shanghai, Hong Kong, Seoul, and Onseiri.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref110" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Canton, Shanghai, Seoul, Onseiri</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1928 January-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_87a3e19a30519fecf7636aa1fd6b787c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a91130bbc768c05c9f4a7eb6bbfa2609"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_87a3e19a30519fecf7636aa1fd6b787c">50</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8c5928b243886c7660bb0a6d969e46d2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM writing a book about the history of the Chengdu Medical School, WRM and ACM's celebration of their twenty-fifth anniversary of marriage, continued medical work, and travels to Shanghai, Hong Kong, Seoul, and Onseiri.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref112" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Onseiri, Shanghai, Peking, Chungking, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1928 July-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_455ca4fd8aa8230b0d9623a055ab35d8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6e9ceaf28b75201f5e33fdf2fd7ebe19"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_455ca4fd8aa8230b0d9623a055ab35d8">51</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dfac86be04e4a896a10ca67dfa833a29">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Regarding WRM's book, political tensions and unrest in China, ACM's art exhibition opening, and the Morse family's travels and cultural experiences in Shanghai, Hong Kong, Peking, Seoul, and Onseiri.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref114" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Onseiri, train to Mukden, Shanghai, boat on the Yangtze River, Chungking</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1928 July-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_80b07d4586bd75a1166d7d9b6a617259"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a1955736bcf38cf8f6a02b4e07471103"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_80b07d4586bd75a1166d7d9b6a617259">52</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_84e3655fcc7b36cd39b471e1a596b213">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM and ACM's journey across China, Manchuria, and Korea, political tensions between the Chinese and the Japanese, and summer weather and daily events.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref116" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1929 January-March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_c938b1edc79cde3f602db3ffb837e883"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5cc95b2c56865d94dabf01710dc24e0a"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c938b1edc79cde3f602db3ffb837e883">53</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_24bd02a602f6c2e62f0be1b654fe8fc3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the passing of MM's Aunt Rose, severe fighting and assaults on steamers in China, MM's sixteenth birthday, WRM's work as a teacher in anatomy department, and his writing of a research paper about Chinese medicine.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref118" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1929 April-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_68b8df23a5c4198800ba5d62bafba5c6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b5b890d2001d3cae50f442fcc3121f56"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_68b8df23a5c4198800ba5d62bafba5c6">54</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_20a7960486b13127f4da105e0c71d316">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding publication and reviews for WRM's book "The Three Crosses in the Purple Mists", MM's college entrance examinations and induction into the National Honor Society, and WRM and ACM's recovery from bad health.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref120" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Beh Liu Din, Lifan, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1929 April-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_b7f0c44e411c878a7d3685301addaade"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ecf6455a86a50aadf3de9680b6ea094d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b7f0c44e411c878a7d3685301addaade">55</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1f48869ee2c593afb96bb73e1d7101f8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding college recommendations for MM, WRM's travel to Lifan and life in Lifan, ACM teaching classes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref122" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, boat on the Min River, boat on the Yangtze River, Shanghai, Madras</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1929 October-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_b965e682d3027d085be6f0f00c8ad020"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_452180fe80a5fe5b192ce0c83e3add5b"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b965e682d3027d085be6f0f00c8ad020">56</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_62452f792484de5c15bb482d566d3cff">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM reducing his time at hospitals and only taking on special medical cases, making preparations for travel back to America.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref124" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Madras, train to Benares, Bombay, boat on the Red Sea</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1930 January</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_1e5ca9ae8aa34d51e83a0c2931f9d806"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_28ea564b245838e8bcb4a8ab0e6c1b1f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1e5ca9ae8aa34d51e83a0c2931f9d806">57</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d5e8f1dd0842b68296dab76544e86c3d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of the people and customs of Madras and Bombay, dates and deadlines for arriving in Bombay and Egypt's Port Said, and WRM and ACM's excitement of getting home to MM.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref126" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from boat to Cairo, Cairo, the steamer S.S. Laurentic, Paris, London</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1930 February</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_ab35070ef7439c00bceb44358e0e69e4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2cc01d85d8785aae8643c07c44263084"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ab35070ef7439c00bceb44358e0e69e4">58</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_25eb151c1e3dbeea7a95c6dc7081231d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes a smallpox outbreak on WRM and ACM's ferry, sightseeing in Cairo, Egyptian people and customs, WRM getting asked to make a class speech at a college commencement</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref128" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from London</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1930 March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_e54064176e2a3dfa715decdae07cfe31"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_017e4f44f6038c7b3726cddb822da433"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e54064176e2a3dfa715decdae07cfe31">59</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_222ac2e4a0b647846f6331162bfff5d9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM visits London hospitals and the Medical Museum of the Royal College of Surgeons, travel in United Kingdom</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref130" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, in U.S on train en route to Detroit, Chicago, Evanston, the Rockies, Ontario, S.S. Empress of Russia boat en route to Yokohama, Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1931 June-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_21c0d2ce83348ff50cda831f361ad883"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b699c2a5446577acc606519b21d87658"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_21c0d2ce83348ff50cda831f361ad883">60</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1d466366be928b32913f22f998669dae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM and ACM's happiness towards MM's success at school, MM starting at Wellesley College, WRM and ACM's railway travels to Detroit, Chicago, Vancouver, and Ontario to visit family and see scenery, MM starting college, and WRM and ACM's experiences in Japan.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref132" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Shanghai, boat on the Yangtze River, Chungking, boat on the Min River, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1931 October-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_dbb03ae5a3aae8b030f6b020c03f9771"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_908827f26cf962e448b614743ac10672"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_dbb03ae5a3aae8b030f6b020c03f9771">61</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9d410f98911a3b2130aef2aef864a0b0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of WRM's excitement to help people in medical need, meetings of the National Christian Council, effects of the flood of the Yangtze on Chinese homes and people, legal trouble with Chinese travel customs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref134" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1932 January-March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_343cb012a5d07654b3a409ce77361254"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7cc7f0f64c1e8bf56f640e5dbfca75b9"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_343cb012a5d07654b3a409ce77361254">62</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e5f8373b62701b5f1e1f588e2fc3ab15">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's home and work experiences in Chengtu and at the West China Union University; WRM acting as the president of the West China Border Research Society and giving a lecture on acupuncture; special operations conducted at the hospital, and the tensions of the Sino-Japanese situation in Shanghai.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref136" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1932 April-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_5cce2de595d7dc6c6207d64b24259a54"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_20a6a128468dd0316b41baddb609474e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_5cce2de595d7dc6c6207d64b24259a54">63</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6fc169ca1f3433f7bc4f764af6aba2f2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding tensions between Chinese and Japanese; ACM teaching painting classes and WRM teaching at the university, meetings with foreign missionaries, and MM's college life and curriculum.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref138" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Beh Liu Tin, Chengtu, Canton</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1932 August-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_712e68f357d60814fe9e6780d1ad8dcf"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_422fc24fa107542b187419c320785841"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_712e68f357d60814fe9e6780d1ad8dcf">64</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4d00d370712510dd5b06efa782e1c75c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's writing on anatomy and anthropological measurements, the outbreak of cholera in China, WRM and ACM's registration with the Chinese government, and WRM publishing work for the Peabody Museum at Harvard University.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref140" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1932 November-1933 January</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178673"
                             id="aspace_a2b5c6c78228decf5057a5833c78db58"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c41ebe39c848e363da22d6489c1d157a"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a2b5c6c78228decf5057a5833c78db58">65</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e04f0579a99264edce8e4f441de4b193">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM has large amount of hospital work, including treatment of wounded soldiers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref142" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 January-March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_b47617e6229b8179dc159ecee9fc9e92"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_22e60f75183f78a23b77001c4269ed46"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b47617e6229b8179dc159ecee9fc9e92">66</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_04f497e745389183542020a746e1f518">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes troubles arising in the United States, China, Europe, and Russia, WRM working on different reports and lectures, the illness and health improvement of WRM's colleague Dr. Lenox, and Chinese spring weather and seasonal customs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref144" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 April-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_733b1a45dbb73fc60e1752a9c3ff1024"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8bcd441497757920c22490aa4a800164"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_733b1a45dbb73fc60e1752a9c3ff1024">67</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c2f1e88dececd36afe275b1c136f0eb5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding uprisings of Communism in the north-east and the eastern sections of the Szechuan province, MM's college examinations, China's election of a new president (Chang), the defeat in power of the warlord Liu Wen Hwei at Chengtu, and the temporary end of the Chinese Civil War.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref146" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Chengtu, Seung Pan, Beh Lin Tin</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 July-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_e1bb16dd957502a18944a0fb20e44989"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d63845f883ea8e4f6ef9b282438b35c3"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_e1bb16dd957502a18944a0fb20e44989">68</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_334464e1e84ab698b09e3a1ec2899a74">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the departure of the warlord Liu Wen Hwei from the city of Chengtu, the effects of the war-like conditions on normal citizens</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref148" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Beh Liu Tin, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 September-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_7428cfaf3cca5938f0d58ed0c06372a2"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e48d5d81b0db59ea8a271dbad0e48a9c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7428cfaf3cca5938f0d58ed0c06372a2">69</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7cbaaa23538a9e5b58bbd4a8adf5d450">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding the beginning of MM's final undergraduate year at Wellesley College and her worries about her future, WRM's large classes in Anatomy and Surgery at the university, and the growth of Communism in China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref150" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 November-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_c7879f08e7445e6582fa83a428d69f9d"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_713b6c2fa79b54de099759c743ffa755"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c7879f08e7445e6582fa83a428d69f9d">70</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_94fea29dd65082faba1f60514a2738cb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes a German Government official visit to China, the rise of the Communist party and WRM's fears regarding Communist success in Chinese government, financial and legal issues in the Chinese government, and WRM and ACM's holiday celebrations and plans.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref152" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to MM from Chengtu, Peu Hsien</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 January-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_c5f4ecc8c49ea1d3a0753478d4c6d86a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1b944392bb046a2e8f97ee99c405a0f7"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c5f4ecc8c49ea1d3a0753478d4c6d86a">71</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7b12ce4c04fe2afe104f07513dd8a786">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes ACM's travel to and time in Peu Hsien, her support of MM's college work and future experiences, ACM's sketch and artwork processes, and daily life in Chengtu.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref154" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to MM from Chengtu, Bei Liu Tin (Bei Lu Din)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933 July-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_4f91d4c4d1a33f914d9e0d99f2e68f86"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2d241bd58fc9b23d34982b86ecaccc99"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4f91d4c4d1a33f914d9e0d99f2e68f86">72</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e03e85952b10b0d015b9f652df1fbe31">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of nature and scenery that ACM comes across during the summer season, her meetings with the Fine Arts Committee, military affairs, art exhibition openings, the devastation of an earthquake, and life events in Bei Lu Din and Chengtu.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref156" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1934 January-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_24b339ffe44b356bbcbd258c53e66238"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_304cb71ba7cea719fbe799726b3c6d5e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_24b339ffe44b356bbcbd258c53e66238">73</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_71f8fde9444262d2c3acb1c50b6695e4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's advice to MM for her future profession, WRM resigning from the Deanship of medicine in order to have more freedom, MM filing legal papers for American citizenship, and WRM's report writing for the College of Medicine and Dentistry.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref158" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Shih Men Kan, Beh Liu Tin, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1934 July-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_37d38e1730803f60bfc7c6973be5a212"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c0e83160a760a3a3671d056b283bf211"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_37d38e1730803f60bfc7c6973be5a212">74</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_60997e0f049da32dbeca24a87f040ec8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding WRM's travels across the Szechuan province, characteristics and customs of the Miao people of China, WRM's thoughts on turning 60 years old, pressures at work, the growing reality of the Communist troubles in China, and MM's new experiences with working.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref160" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1934 January-June</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_cb2caf6850874903e19f165db60b6d17"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c4cac73461fe1e6c39a77b93e0f6acb7"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_cb2caf6850874903e19f165db60b6d17">75</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_eb205a16f4773be4309ae31a928e96ff">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes political tensions in China, WRM's success with his lecture presentations, MM's commencement from Wellesley College, and the daily life events of ACM and MM.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref162" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to MM from Beh Liu Tin, Chengtu, Hong Kong</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1934 July-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_62ced82ebddf2fa6fcfcc26a67c8c523"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_83c229fc359d657948cd80544916502e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_62ced82ebddf2fa6fcfcc26a67c8c523">76</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9cc9e168962b2f1a40cabd7210ba7fb1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding WRM's trip across Szechuan province, rainstorms in Chengtu, warm weather, and events that ACM attends.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref164" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1935 January-March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_6ec93c3eccf5240bb640fa8222943743"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_79c882d8b7b017d5a415e1910d8fdd33"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6ec93c3eccf5240bb640fa8222943743">77</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a33acd768057551774b0eb12a1beedd0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including description of unrest in China and resistance towards the Communist party, mail deliveries from foreign countries being held up and eventually coming through to China, WRM's optimism towards new medical students joining his classes in the face of Chinese Communism, and WRM's views on missionary work.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref166" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1935 June-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_eced4cf9779f896d549195577bcb3f2f"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f617c720899f7fbeff4fba68832cda6d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_eced4cf9779f896d549195577bcb3f2f">78</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a7e81de045c7ae57b3ddb08e7cdbdea5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM and ACM's work with students and art exhibitions, visits with guests, housework developments and changes, worries and conflicts arise with the "Reds", WRM dropping out of office during the university's elections</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref168" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Yachow, Shin Kai Si</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1935 June-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_50fbc0ef9f19f309752ab6e4371f510b"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_559c3a7138409e49f3ee072e25320653"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_50fbc0ef9f19f309752ab6e4371f510b">79</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_73eef93839ea9f36c6ffff80dd18605a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding MM's wedding engagement, WRM and ACM celebrating their 32nd wedding anniversary, the Nanking government requesting information from WRM and ACM, a lecture by Professor Weigle of the Yale Divinity School in Yachow, and WRM working on a paper called "The Ancient Aboriginal Tribes of Szechuan."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref170" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from boat on the Min River, Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1935 September-October</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_7390f89415ecef5ed077d0416fee8b06"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d47c51746850d85b04ffc3af709732c2"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7390f89415ecef5ed077d0416fee8b06">80</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8760a49d992e9b261c42c8fae96d86ae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's happiness at MM's engagement and enthusiasm for work, the initiation of new members into the Christian Church Council, WRM's teaching processes of Anatomy and Surgery, and the death of the Morse family's friend Mrs. Williams.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref172" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1935 November-December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_d2d6e2ad3699a2b4c51d01e4c18e6c19"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ebffd98b75f5cb7d273dbb8ecebba6b1"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_d2d6e2ad3699a2b4c51d01e4c18e6c19">81</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bad529b6ce07ed39e5e6f1e2f0016ce1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the meetings of the United Church of Canada, the spread of communism to the living areas of Chinese tribes, Chinese students against Japan, earthquakes that have occurred in Szechuan province, and a sketch of where communism has spread in the Szechuan province.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref174" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_08aa573c8093a513c039e415172ee1c9"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a972f73c5fd27167fe1decaad8eb1dbc"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_08aa573c8093a513c039e415172ee1c9">82</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_33b1f57f77e279eece6980217f6ed39e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Including regarding ACM's city visits and visits with friends, painting, WRM and ACM giving students examinations, typhoon damages to Chinese houses.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref176" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1936 January-March</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_8086b2e4c324dc3063fe5c3c4ef0ea0c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bd986252b83ab77bcfb73bc5a32dc6cc"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_8086b2e4c324dc3063fe5c3c4ef0ea0c">83</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_20d84cfbf2ec76a0aa22cf0f1599eeae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes MM's attendance at the Yale-Harvard football game, the annual West China Border Research Society conference at Chengtu, changes in Chinese culture and marriage customs, and WRM and ACM's visits with colleagues and friends.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref178" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1936 March-July</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_788b2eb9750276623eb426bcdae6f570"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b26a7d78a258ee06a8363782d299d086"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_788b2eb9750276623eb426bcdae6f570">84</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_46dde475c2e355050cd52262d8c2d485">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Incluidng regarding the deaths of two friends of the Morse family, WRM's invitation to a conference for all of the Deans and Principals of the Medical College in China, MM receiving a letter from the president of the "Yale-in-China" Medical School (Edward H. Hume), Communists who are continually active, and political unrest in China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref180" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Kiating, Nanking, Chengtu, Beh Liu Tin, Miao country</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1936 April-July</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178681"
                             id="aspace_80310c75c2c7d9080dfdd6499ba3f4d5"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9742f53d938de20656dc7b55f9551fdf"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_80310c75c2c7d9080dfdd6499ba3f4d5">85</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f351cbd1c304a146cce065f20af43e0a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes WRM's time in Nanking as part of a trip conducted by the West China Union University and its medical college, MM contracting scarlet fever, WRM elected as director of the medical college of the West China Union University, and summer weather in Chengtu, Miao country, and Beh Liu Tin.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref182" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1936 December</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_15963d6999478541051478891aece3f1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_988d418b0739a37f479205a9d53a14bb"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_15963d6999478541051478891aece3f1">86</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9dc3814213785c65e71d84e2290d2a4e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>WRM giving up hospital work and his position as director of the medical college in order to focus on anatomy and anthropology, Chinese feasts and customs for the start of the spring season, and a recipe for a Chinese meal.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref184" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Peu Hsien</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1936 August-November</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_5fcc579b286d4e366d2aaf1318ea3bea"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_01348907d9fc9e2d1a699b909b28e76d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_5fcc579b286d4e366d2aaf1318ea3bea">87</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_15c9f2d5a5b5bc8d6f04bcecbfe89e73">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes government requirements for colleges and college classes, the customs and events of the Chinese Republic anniversary holiday "Double Truth Day", the Chinese goverment's set of counter-demands to Japan, and autumn weather in China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref186" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from boat en route to Singapore, Colombo, London</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1937 April-August</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_3732cd4cfcbc987178f0505bb09e949f"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6f52bfc79899c80c8d98b957d7521d9e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_3732cd4cfcbc987178f0505bb09e949f">88</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_34a659356b3f795291745bc9b885b7b4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Incluidng description of the physical conditions of WRM and ACM, monotonous travel to Singapore by steamer boat, WRM trying to rewrite a paper on the blood groups of the Chinese Miao tribe, MM's wedding plans, participation in activities on a steamer boat to London, and WRM and ACM's positive experiences in London.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref188" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>WRM and ACM to MM from Chengtu, Chungking, Ichang, boat on the Yangtze River, Shanghai</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1937 January-April</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_90582d8ce2294eb4581e5a73698bede8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_aae9083e833494d642d834f40bd60f9c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_90582d8ce2294eb4581e5a73698bede8">89</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7359985e73803fbb24f8b5f62bb4dd42">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Describes the health recovery of WRM, WRM and ACM giving away many of their household items, WRM staying at home in order to rest and regain his health, MM's wedding date is planned and set, and travels to Chungking, Ichang, and Shanghai.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref190" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Fragments</unittitle>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_916aae01bfa4337c98528aee4dc9c4f3"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3888e86f166402dcb96b29a53e6cdb7c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_916aae01bfa4337c98528aee4dc9c4f3">90</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref191" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912-1940</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="ref192" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence to/from W.R. Morse (WRM)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref193" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>W.R. Morse (WRM) to the First National Bank of Boston; WRM to Mr. Morrison; Stephen Yang to WRM; R. Gates to WRM from The University of London King's College</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1933-1939</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_0095216080a1ff3780475768e277c192"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2d491262c390c5d6463f09940428096f"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_0095216080a1ff3780475768e277c192">91</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref194" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence to WRM and Anne Crosse Morse (ACM)</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref195" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Irene Chambers to WRM and ACM from Boston; May to WRM and ACM from Suifu</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1931-1939</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_e429b2aa0e41061571f828ce31c4b682"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c2660f83e67fab8e35b131d92c13ae1f"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e429b2aa0e41061571f828ce31c4b682">92</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref196" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence to ACM</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref197" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>From James M. Andrews , Ernest A. Hoolan, Board of Governors of the West China Union University, J.W. Decker</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_c41fb31bd75a8c048f01eead46064993"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_080e5df859cd6860db93537cc97330d9"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c41fb31bd75a8c048f01eead46064993">93</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref198" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>From Anne M. Salquist, A.B. Cunden, Ernest Hubbard, Ed Cunningham , Y.T. Beh</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_2ae45059b655e9c62ba81e386dc420bc"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4c636ab79160653a812b4507cf228075"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2ae45059b655e9c62ba81e386dc420bc">94</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref199" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>From S.H. Fong, Mrs. Cunningham, Anne M. Salquist, Leslie G. Kilborn, Joseph Chandler Robbins</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_57c2d02044c4a88e0001e9fdec5ebc27"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_6ae0cb0f2aa47cf091e1d63b4289f870"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_57c2d02044c4a88e0001e9fdec5ebc27">95</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref200" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>From E.C. Wilford, West China Union University, May to ACM from Suifu., R. Eates from the University of London King's College, Anna M. Salquist</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_8976640096a1ce795a9c28cf77093281"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_495fc9705d1db06acddb9ce4ff8185a9"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_8976640096a1ce795a9c28cf77093281">96</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref201" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>From T. Torrance, Fred Abrey, Tsu Ku Sze, Cheng Liang</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1940</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_bb6871ee819da4f41838ea96764c4dcd"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d2b839dc941e6c5bce5ebfd2459ea41a"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_bb6871ee819da4f41838ea96764c4dcd">97</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref202" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence of others</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1921-1939</unitdate>
               </did>
               <c id="ref203" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Harold to Elsie; Randolph S. Howard to relatives of the Morse family; Fred Haggard to mother of WRM</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1912, 1921, 1931</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002084178699"
                                id="aspace_db1ab6e39924ddda325a0fda1114eddf"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">5</container>
                     <container id="aspace_7461d955f425fd3b1faf3d19c2c3b442"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_db1ab6e39924ddda325a0fda1114eddf">98</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref204" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Writings and Notes</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1915-1936</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="ref205" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical report by W.R. Morse (WRM) from Suifu and Chengtu</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1915 January 1</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_713872680dfb0f2b7dcd923a9c244041"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_43054c55549492127e56924b1e9de0b1"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_713872680dfb0f2b7dcd923a9c244041">99</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref206" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pages 2-7 of handwritten essay by W.R. Morse regarding Chinese medicine and his medical work</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_3c8e4190adff98dddb2ab157f40a342e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_944578fa2e5a200570a895783deb1309"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_3c8e4190adff98dddb2ab157f40a342e">100</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref207" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Articles by WRM</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1932-1936</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_7894bcc54e805f07e75920b41f73f470"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4ac824d8f2371c1b88215b752e372581"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7894bcc54e805f07e75920b41f73f470">101</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9d21b1f75da14ca96f85b7fa720e34d7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Articles Included: "Opportunities for Graduate Work in West China" (Published in the Chinese Recorder," October, 1932); "An Expedition into the Chwan Miao Country: A Vacation with a Purpose" (Published in the W.C.U. Newsletter, October, 1936)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref209" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Book review of "The Three Crosses in the Purple Mist" by WRM</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_0a01a2bf07eeb835a9d276a884ad3c54"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_05067897deeb14466fd38a31685ca7b7"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_0a01a2bf07eeb835a9d276a884ad3c54">102</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aef5ca51387dd1b554e9375efe7628eb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Published in the West China Missionary News, written by "J.T."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="ref211" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_4da5bb2aa944e10d19e73caca917ebb4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_82eaa2d715cd2b84d85c346cfba70a1e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4da5bb2aa944e10d19e73caca917ebb4">103</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref212" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Personal Items and Memorabilia</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series IV</unitid>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1929-1941</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="ref213" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Biographical documentation regarding W.R. Morse (WRM)</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1928-1939</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_342029183a93a518b6a7e562896f2707"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2a677b2c15b2300e576d20ac5bbeec0d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_342029183a93a518b6a7e562896f2707">104</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref214" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Farewell Speech to Dr. and Mrs. Morse from Anatomy Class</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1929 November 29</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_ce192d7b7dfbb62a6f3569126a4fa74d"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_75b28de6e7619c218c8bbe727bcce9ec"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ce192d7b7dfbb62a6f3569126a4fa74d">105</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref215" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notice in minutes of West China Union University College of Medicine and Dentistry regarding William Reginald and Anne Crosse Morse Memorial Fund</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1941 September 18</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_13164049c45ea86950a1801f0eb24e76"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_8820210dbb084cc239ac6f56dd701b54"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_13164049c45ea86950a1801f0eb24e76">106</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref216" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notice regarding publications of Royal Anthropological Institute</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1939</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_9d2154793de584d2ac1ec02eedea3c26"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4cdb0e04717efe26d9a5515b4957d937"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9d2154793de584d2ac1ec02eedea3c26">107</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref217" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Friendship calendar with notes and photographs from supporters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1910</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_cae8eedf70be569f779a741e5e77a238"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f0b4a5e3176e546ee1713eb14d1118fa"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_cae8eedf70be569f779a741e5e77a238">108</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref218" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Photograph, cards, wedding invitation, Chinese language material</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1911, undated</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002084178699"
                             id="aspace_dd5719fda81f775b191bc1f575d36b3e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_82d3cc9f1ec33eb036462d578a05b420"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_dd5719fda81f775b191bc1f575d36b3e">109</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
