<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/med.ms.0076">med.ms.0076</recordid>
      <otherrecordid localtype="BIB">15593135</otherrecordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Stanley B. Burns, M.D., Historic Medical Photography Collection </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Burns, Stanley B., M.D., historic medical photography collection</titleproper>
            <author>Katherine Isham</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University</addressline>
               <addressline>333 Cedar St.</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8014</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">historical.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://historical.medicine.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://historical.medicine.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://historical.medicine.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2020</date>
            <num>Ms Coll 76</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-M</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>English</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>Finding aid description and metadata in Archives at Yale are licensed under a CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication. This means that anyone may copy, modify, and distribute this descriptive metadata without restriction or permission. The CC0 license is explained in full on the Creative Commons website: <ref href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication</ref>. More information is available on our <ref href="https://archives.yale.edu/help">Help page</ref>.</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>in_progress</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2021-02-05T03:00:09+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.7.1.yale.20200820</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Friday February  5, 2021 at 03:00</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc altrender="/repositories/10/resources/11880" level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Stanley B. Burns, M.D., historic medical photography collection</unittitle>
         <unitid>Ms Coll 76</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>10,000</quantity>
            <unittype>Items</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <unitdatestructured altrender="Circa 1840-1979"
                             certainty="inferred"
                             label="creation"
                             unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1840">1840</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1979">1979</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_a1410a8204c31202f53cd53806d71fa9">The collection includes photographs collected by Stanley B. Burns, M.D., that document medical practice and medical practitioners circa 1840 through the 1970s. The collection includes items created using multiple photographic techniques and supports including daguerreotypes, ambrotypes, tintypes, lantern slides, photographic negatives, cartes de visite, cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), stereoscopic photographs, panoramic photographs, picture postcards, gelatin silver prints, albumen prints, and photolithographs. Most of the collection is organized by topic and/or format,  with the exception of a group of framed photographs (the Archive Wall) formerly displayed at the Burns Archive. Approximately half of the photographic prints in the collections are contained in photograph albums. Materials include extensive holdings documenting physicians and medical scientists at work, operative scenes, hospital wards, laboratories, nurses and nursing, notable physicians, surgical specialties, war medicine, patients, and disease states. Published works in the collection have been individually cataloged.</abstract>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88044204"
                      relator="col"
                      source="naf">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Burns, Stanley B.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8241a567b63627c51e894ac183d9e082"
                      localtype="InProcessSpecColl">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The collection is unprocessed. Contact the Medical Historical Library at historical.library@yale.edu to request access.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_904d7f9603bd793213ee1e1d6e585f2d">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased from Stanley B. Burns, M.D., 2020.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_c08a64b4246a327799895c76cd832be3">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection is arranged in 8 series: Series I. Archive wall. Series II. Hard images. Series III. Lantern slides. Series IV. Panoramic photographs. Series V. Assembled collections. Series VI. Special collections. Series VII. Medical photograph albums. Series VIII. Albums des Internat.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_a79619c9f46da0d1eb6ad5e9a91c66da">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Stanley B. Burns, M.D., is an ophthalmologist and Research Professor of Medicine and Psychiatry, Professor of Medical Humanities, and Adjunct Professor of Obstetrics and Gynecology at New York University Langone Medical Center and Medical School. He is also an author, curator, historian, collector, archivist, and television and film consultant.</p>
         <p>In 1975 Dr. Burns began collecting unique historic photography documenting multiple subjects including medicine, war, death, crime, racism, Judaica, and African American history. In 1977, Dr. Burns founded the Burns Archive in his home located in the  Brooklyn borough of New York City, to provide access to his collection of historic photography. The Burns Archive holdings currently contain over one million photographs.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_5f7bade1c6c5574fba3d8b33f33134aa">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Stanley B. Burns, M.D. Historic Medical Photography Collection. Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_a1efff1892130ddbe06257f592668a51">
         <head>Content Description</head>
         <p>The collection includes photographs collected by Stanley B. Burns, M.D., that document the history of medical science and medical practice circa 1840 through the 1970s. Items in the collection were created using multiple photographic techniques and supports including daguerreotypes, ambrotypes, tintypes, lantern slides, photographic negatives, cartes de visite, cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), stereoscopic photographs, panoramic photographs, picture postcards, gelatin silver prints, albumen prints, and photolithographs.</p>
         <p>Materials in the collection are grouped in series and subseries by topic and/or format according to the order in which they were received from Dr. Burns. Description of materials in the collection, including subject terms and item numbers, is based on description provided by Dr. Burns when the collection was acquired.</p>
         <p>Series I. Archive Wall includes 81 framed photographs which were formerly displayed at the Burns Archive. Photographic prints in the series cover a range of subjects and photographic techniques.</p>
         <p>Series II. Hard images includes daguerreotypes, ambrotypes, and tintypes. Most items in this series are encased in original hinged frames. The series is further divides into two subseries: Physicians (78 items) and Patients (151 items). The Physicians subseries documents physicians, medical practitioners, and medical students, often posed with skulls, medical equipment, or other accoutrements of their profession. The Patients subseries documents patients suffering from a variety of ailments, some depict treatments.</p>
         <p>Series III. Lantern slides includes 264 glass plate slides.</p>
         <p>Series IV. Panoramic photographs includes two large photographic prints.</p>
         <p>Series V. Assembled collections includes photographic prints created using a variety of photographic techniques grouped into 33 subseries. Items in subseries were not acquired as established collections, but were grouped by Dr. Burns according to topic and/or format.</p>
         <p>Series VI. Special collections incudes photographic prints created using a variety of photographic techniques grouped into 58 subseries. Items in subseries were acquired by Dr. Burns as established collections; many were created by a single medical practitioner or to document a project or event.</p>
         <p>Series VII. Photograph albums includes 49 albums containing prints created using a variety of photographic techniques. Albums in the series were created by medical practitioners, organizations, or institutions. Albums document the personal lives of medical practitioners, medical institutions, medical colleges,</p>
         <p>Series VIII. Albums des Internat includes 13 annual volumes documenting interns at all of Paris' hospitals.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_0d94a6546b0b9a51279d12ec54f48893">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright status for collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_abcfa9112be4db5844296e45114918eb">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Published works from the Stanley B. Burns, M.D., Historic Medical Photography Collection have been individually cataloged and can be discovered by searching Orbis.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="sh2008121880" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Hospitals</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85082871"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medical care</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85082916"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medical education</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85082949"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medical instruments and apparatus</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="sh85101290" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medical photography</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85083080"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medicine</part>
            <part localtype="topical">History</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85083153"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medicine, Military</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008107280"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medicine</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Practice</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85083097"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medicine</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Research</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85083104"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medicine</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Study and teaching</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2010106017"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Pharmacy</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Practice</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2010106302"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Physicians</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85101628"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Physicians</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85130770"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Surgery</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Practice</part>
         </subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243962"
            id="aspace_bd789c4fb1d558fef42b7c64aad71465"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Archive wall</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <unitdatestructured altrender="1863-circa 1960"
                                   label="creation"
                                   unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <daterange>
                     <fromdate standarddate="1863">1863</fromdate>
                     <todate standarddate="1960">1960</todate>
                  </daterange>
               </unitdatestructured>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_645c19213f4eed6e457a71ae0f14bcd4">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Item numbers used by Dr. Burns have been retained in this series.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243963"
               id="aspace_2653e0ae124ead4eed8d340e780bffd1"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>1. Tent dressing station</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1944" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1944">1944</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f52f70b82cd649b28b7d5f7490718483">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 15.5 x 12.5 inches, frame 18.75 x 22.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: New Georgia Island. Description: caption reads "In the dimness beneath a tent dressing station on New Georgia Island, an army medical oﬃcer cleans the bomb fragment wounds in a soldier's knee. Col. George A. Enion, a surgeon, watches intently." Subject: general surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243964"
               id="aspace_d1120c6ca8cc5448cf5a1aabbe9a377d"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>2. New York Homeopathic Medical College and Hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1908" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1908">1908</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9ed452cfa88d9f4a830f9ef69fc091b6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7 x 5 inches, frame 18.5 x 14 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: New York. Description: osteology display advertising institution. Subject: .</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243965"
               id="aspace_09b8e214bc6b547ddc8664a24b0df545"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>3. Lord Joseph Lister</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1890" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_442814917a204d1a4e17a228be583991">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 13.75 x 16.5 inches. Photographer: Mr. R. A. Bickersteth FRCS. Description: discoverer of anti-septic principles. Subject: general surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243966"
               id="aspace_9f960a8a7c253b93dcee61f90a48934a"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>4. Mechanical phoropter</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1895" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1895">1895</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d61039f139e88cfd3989146f190625a0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7 x 8 inches, frame 12 x 15 inches. Photographer: unknown. Subject: ophthalmology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243967"
               id="aspace_ac33e1c0be0b2741d45add4242161c0e"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>5. Dental/maxillo-facial surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bb6ed7ea8d13f572ea654d34c39da566">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 9.5 x7.5 inches, frame 14 x 12 inches. Photographer: unknown. Subject: dental surgery, maxillo-facial surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243968"
               id="aspace_62227618893ede449faeaf1919d0f411"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>6. Children's ward, Connecticut hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1912" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1912">1912</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_03bbedd440704aeb55a7842bf79128f0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7.5 x 9.5 inches, frame 16.5 x 13. 25 inches. Photographer: Ford; stamped Beggs Art. Location: Torington, Connecticut. Description: six nurses and one doctor in attendance. Subject: pediatrics.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243969"
               id="aspace_8359066b60365a5d5eb35d9672324eaa"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>7. Hospital ward</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7b74d274c983e803c8be3f94f4743715">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 9.5 x 7.5 inches, frame 17.75 x 14.75 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243970"
               id="aspace_2137bc61bbf4c46eb4657cc10db09509"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>8. Chevalier Jackson's bronchoscopy clinic</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1939 January" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1939">1939</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4b1cb6680d4471bb9c9d207140d74a15">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 9.5 x 7.5 inches, frame 13.25 x 12.25 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Subject: ear, nose, and throat; pulmonology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243971"
               id="aspace_206e63753555b1ad2bdcaaa0ae77c692"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>9. Brigadier General Justus Morris Brown, Surgeon General United States Army (1840-1912)</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1901" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_99b3e4f259e31cb55ce3da0b92560b4b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 5 x 7 inches, frame 11 x 13 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243972"
               id="aspace_87dd79845dec76b4c5aeaee459bec063"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>10. John J. Nagle, Civil War surgeon carte de visite and diploma, New York State Volunteers</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1863" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1863">1863</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b242752342cab0b3041e23ce89d84e88">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Carte de visite with document, 15.5 x 12 inches, frame 19.75 x 16 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: New York.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243973"
               id="aspace_d46a1412bb4e3d0bad2fb04082860bd2"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>11. Two female syphiloderma patients, Plate XXVII, George Henry Fox, M.D.</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1880" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9d4b86d2ba6f464fe726201128d0b4a3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Artotype, 2 photographs, 3.5 x 5 inches, frame 15 x 12 inches. Photographer: O. G. Mason. Location: New York City. Subject: dermatology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243974"
               id="aspace_7705fe8a4b3fd583de08991d42b47600"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>12. Physician in laboratory</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1910" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1910">1910</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_85c99cd5a625d02560e579a286262a47">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 5 x 7 inches, frame 10 x 7.5 inches. Photographer: Theo Duenaul.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243975"
               id="aspace_e181dd165979232b9846f7a48efc489c"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>13. Oﬃcials and staﬀ of State Custodial School, Medical Lake</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1930 October 5"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_45c28d5adf19f647123a87d498b32783">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Panoramic circuit photograph, 30.5 x 7.75 inches, frame 30 x 7.5 inches. Photographer: P. Libby. Location: Washington.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243976"
               id="aspace_a87d75cff4590f2a6c9f74bc5982e9c9"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>14. Surgical scene, Bellevue Hospital amphitheater</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1885" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1885">1885</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2c69aadb76613025f123bc49395b435f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 16.5 x 14.5 inches. Photographer: O. G. Mason; stamped Bellevue Hospital Photography Department. Location: New York. Subject: general surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243977"
               id="aspace_637fde79845bd4d73761e03981ba29aa"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>15. Grand Rounds, Bellevue Hospital amphitheater</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1885" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1885">1885</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_213f6a12f2e1f4e685e076e251639a7d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 11 inches, frame 16.5 x 14.6 inches. Photographer: O. G. Mason; stamped Bellevue Hospital Photography Department. Location: New York. Subject: general surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243978"
               id="aspace_2f63f6d8a44d6b7f47d9b5859c118e2d"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>16. Anatomy class, Philadelphia Medical College amphitheater</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1888" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1888">1888</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_31cdc9350728de5213f7d7f05e6a6fdf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 25 x 10.5 inches, frame 31.5 x 15.5 inches. Photographer: possibly Gilbert. Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243979"
               id="aspace_32c75fdd00e4ec62ea179fb42c862a94"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>17. Professor M. H. Cryer's Clinic, demonstration of electric dental drill, Philadelphia Hospital amphitheater, University of Pennsylvania</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1902 April 5" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1902">1902</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_269ccd70216d2336b4c13d9282efb206">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 13 x 9 inches, frame 18.75 x 13.75 inches. Photographer: G. E. Waterman. Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Subject: dentistry.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243980"
               id="aspace_d8b855b9722949168b127a57864af650"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>18. Surgeon William L. Rodman's clinic, Medico Chirurgical Hospital, Philadelphia</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1903 March 26" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1903">1903</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_981c7be38741a05e43a4271146c9642e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 13.5 x 10 inches, frame 18 x 15 inches. Photographer: G. E. Waterman. Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Description: 200 people watch the surgery. Subject: general surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243981"
               id="aspace_ba88f5603e288ae721b62b05fdc34767"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>19. Panoramic view of Boston City Hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1905" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1905">1905</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9b172be8b783345c6b262f0b319a33c6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Panoramic photographic print, 44 x 9.5 inches, frame 48 x 13.5 inches. Frame by Sprague Hathaway Boston. Photographer: unknown. Location: Boston, Massachusetts.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243982"
               id="aspace_07e1b84a61c926c3291ab7594b01b6f6"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>20. Surgical scene, Connecticut hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1912" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1912">1912</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e4a07be1b8a485192aa32c87375d66f6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 9.5 x 7.75 inches, frame 17.75 x 14.75 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Connecticut. Subject: general surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243983"
               id="aspace_9aa10900bbc2f3a4b8c1990194752984"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>21. Discoverer of the X-Ray, Wilhelm Roentgen, posing with his device</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1906" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1906">1906</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_83c19f2dd05ab3cdd7dcf8b9e16e2b9d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>7.5 x 9.5 inches, frame 11.5 x 15.75 inches. Photographer: Nicola Perscheid. Location: Berlin.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243984"
               id="aspace_fd0cc7026dfd283427ad2411121e2990"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>22. Dissected head of Italian criminal</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1906" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1906">1906</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f20e416ca1e03ecf13618e3991cb3353">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8.5 x 10.5 inches, frame 20 x 21.5 inches. Photographer: Omg. Coni Feres. Location: Buenos Aires, Argentina. Description: from a series.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243985"
               id="aspace_6962f3cc3c350cff533d5467ce6e2819"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>23. A Student's Dream</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1906" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1906">1906</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a38344ff0f9f7de190e6370e9a849a70">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 8 inches, frame 12.5 x 16 inches. Photographer: A. A. Robinson. Description: part of a series depicting students on dissecting tables surrounded by cadavers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243986"
               id="aspace_aaf4114fceed64635d5401cd5758e90f"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>24. Nurses graduating class</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4fa136bf736b140db8f710f3d4cd0cbd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 8 inches, frame 10.75 x 8.75 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243987"
               id="aspace_de491c3cf4beb6b97dc83ac659e6634e"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>25. "Dressed in White Suits" Graduate School of Banking, Rutgers University, class of 1940</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1940 June 17" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5ca35b3050c4cd3411e49d148709a7ff">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Panoramic photographic print, 39 x 9.5 inches, frame 36 x 6.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: New Jersey. Description: graduates identified on reverse.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243988"
               id="aspace_33961f608370a4f5a232873e8f51c998"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>26. Surgical scene</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1939" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1939">1939</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_df8b3028e218d32ccf452162e6aeefa7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10.2 x 12.7 inches, frame 17 x 19.5 inches. Photographer: E. R. Deats. Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243989"
               id="aspace_4c5afdb5476f48ad313bdd94aaae67bd"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>27. Pediatric crib ward with doctors and nurses, Connecticut hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1912" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1912">1912</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5cca253f5f61903be35e2213a43ae5b3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7.5 x 9.5 inches, frame 16.5 x 13. 25 inches. Photographer: Ford; stamped Beggs Art Store. Location: Torington, Connecticut. Subject: pediatrics.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243990"
               id="aspace_f4a71dba7612e44c5c9287f6df6503c6"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>28. Tent surgery, Philippine Insurrection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1901" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1901">1901</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_df716f612b2c48ff19a410e4aa955719">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7 x 5 inches, frame 8.75 x 6.75 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Philippines. Description: modern copy print.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243991"
               id="aspace_d6d41df1c152499eb2c742ae2f17be40"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>29. Pediatrician at the bedside</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f5267997cdfa2bfd8e28783f0bff8341">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 12 inches, frame 15.75 x 13.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Description: classic scene. Subject: pediatrician.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243992"
               id="aspace_f830aaeca80d212e461819a6eb5d47f3"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>30. Federal personnel look at Red Cross flag Used by Clara Barton in the flood of 1889</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1936 April 4" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1936">1936</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_72140f1a96359dea64be8c44d48e84c8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7.5 x 9.5 inches, frame 8 x 10 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243993"
               id="aspace_7227ebed9d28907a17940fdfa76786dc"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>31. Amphitheater operative scene</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1906" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1906">1906</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_107fffbb739c230e5c90297879fc5d4e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 6.5 x 4.5 inches, frame 9 x 11 inches. Photographer: unknown. Description: personnel not wearing masks.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243994"
               id="aspace_e3219c99b733fef71d8ad992def8c38b"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>32. Pharmacy with two pharmacists</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1915" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_beb4f16b3d9335090a9f0781f1bfd16c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 6.5 x 4.75 inches, frame 10 x 7.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: France.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243995"
               id="aspace_a6f6b46ee3fe38516467686fd36d4638"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>33. Dissection scene, Pittsburg School of Dentistry</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1923" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1923">1923</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0ff2919b180ebe3e4848fb0e673e42fe">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 8.5 x 10.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Subject: dentistry.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243996"
               id="aspace_0189755b94f8430376c407b6de0f9453"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>34. Dissection scene, examining the body</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3ee94114de38925c7249f9f11334495e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 20 x 16 inches, frame 21 x 17 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243997"
               id="aspace_c29b2c130f079e8ed123ba7dca1ab1ea"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>35. Close-up of organ during surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1915" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dccceec7dcb1a567b064490790c9bdcf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 10 x 12 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243998"
               id="aspace_8b73b099a9c6d91c629ad5643807d438"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>36. Children being nursed with goat's milk</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f71e13bca6747d3fcba4e62879398733">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 6 x 4 inches, frame 9 x 6.75 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243999"
               id="aspace_e62f515594491c3d10dc6cc90f9a2109"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>37. Dr. Daniel L. Borden performing surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1925" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1925">1925</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_60c93441ba95c381c7ff9d03783f627b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 13.5 x 11 inches, frame 11.75 x 14 inches. Photographer: unknown. Description: Dr. Borden was a promoter of motion pictures.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244000"
               id="aspace_41e03580f1d59486f3c78b8d674af6d9"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>38. Rehabilitation clinic</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1925" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1925">1925</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c9e9723114cb567bf5f131597e09984d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 8 inches, frame 15.5 x 13.5 inches; frame label from Marino Gallery Olin's Art Shop, Ellicott City, Maryland. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244001"
               id="aspace_26d8e0ba920003a4cd5878fda0af2328"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>39. Physician performing procedure in medical oﬃce</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1895" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1895">1895</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d53ac6f335f7317a43d66553c94fe8f7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 9.5 x 7.5 inches, frame 16.5 x 13 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Illinois. Description: Illinois State Board of Health Certificate on wall.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244002"
               id="aspace_3c261aeb1a2cbf8dc05c58847074d3bb"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>40. Anesthesiologist teaching</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1925" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1925">1925</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7a3acfd02d09f876c2a6084911dd6497">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 12 x 14 inches. Photographer: unknown. Subject: anesthesiology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244003"
               id="aspace_f1d323b408f942128eb757ed1b36d32c"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>41. Healing ceremony with medicine man and dancers, Panama</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0abc80194f01ddc669fc978ddbf8a676">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 13.3 x 10.5 inches, frame 15.5 x 18 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Darien, Panama. Description: curandero del Darien.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244004"
               id="aspace_bdf178bc6eb5cc54d083fd89b4946f23"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>42. Amphitheater surgical scene with large audience</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1905" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1905">1905</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_195af5b37e80e6f4c33759e642e2becf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 9.5 x 7.5 inches, frame 14.3 x 11.75 inches. Photographer: unknown. Description: no masks are worn.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244005"
               id="aspace_4811628b204cc879c0774069cf8c2243"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>43. Dissection of or experiment on a cat, physiology laboratory</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4252f698dc7ab778ee3021b8900f4b00">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7 x 5 inches, frame 9.75 x 7.25 inches. Photographer: unknown. Subject: veterinary.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244006"
               id="aspace_892ef037815cdfb90811e52a59344281"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>44. Man with tumor of the head and jaw</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1890" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1890">1890</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9cfa288eff0c8abdd9bdea3706bed59f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 12 x 15 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: France.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244007"
               id="aspace_f914120d1d59b13f557f9d9db5979479"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>45. French surgeon Jules Émile Pean (1830-1898) posing by operating table</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1890" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1890">1890</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_724798ed577a08e98936281ec621c751">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 6 inches, frame 11.75 x 9.75 inches. Photographer: Pierre Peterie. Location: Paris, France.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244008"
               id="aspace_46844ad33b333f864c1404ae02298e14"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>46. Orthopedist manipulating foot deformity in amphitheater</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_64f6be617a89901c0b0bdf9d8ceeb719">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 8 inches, frame 10.5 x 8.5 inches. ; Duncan, Vail Co. Photographer: unknown. Location: California. Subject: orthopedics.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244009"
               id="aspace_f5bd5789565d67ffee54858533ae33cf"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>47. Weighing infant, newborn ward</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1935" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1935">1935</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bce1c7919632f30bd0dcd288953c4b5f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 6 inches, frame 8.75 x 6.75 inches. Photographer: unknown. Subject: pediatrics.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244010"
               id="aspace_e9ad9aaa40539a8952f3ad64b46e2d66"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>48. Dentist at work</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1950" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1950">1950</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_068c548c34739f7e594904fd107a3f0b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 3.5 x 4.5 inches, frame 5.5 x 6.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Subject: dentistry.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244011"
               id="aspace_347e56b6a3020209d6013727ebf29160"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>49. Willowbrook Hospital ward</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1972" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1972">1972</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9bfdc7bc71a170182101ecf50e97a93c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 7 inches, frame 15 x 12 inches. Photographer: unknown. Description: Geraldo Rivera's expose at Willowbrook Hospital. Subject: psychiatry.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244012"
               id="aspace_adcac3d6fdc48ba2ca922da172a4822d"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>50. Two patients with skin disease, plate III, George Henry Fox, M.D.</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1880" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3c918b447c40edf8ed517ed70ec3372e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Artotype (photolithograph), 3.5 x 5 inches, 2 prints, frame 12 x 15 inches. Photographer: O. G. Mason. Location: New York City. Subject: dermatology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244013"
               id="aspace_cbcc8b868a70f14e671531e1b9f28787"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>51. Demonstrating facial wound from Mauser bullet, Mexican Revolution</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1916" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1916">1916</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7fb4db39392c56c93b7abb706b296872">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 14 inches, frame 16 x 20 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Mexico.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244014"
               id="aspace_c84f796ae037c473fdb2d8c9e8f941e2"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>52. Physiology laboratory experiment, Mount Sinai Hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1915" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3ea1ee152d3a548cb82c2f7defdd1677">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 13 x 15.5 inches. Photographer: Beals, New York. Location: New York.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244015"
               id="aspace_ea9f476f21b9dacd6442fa37c76ffd62"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>53. Medical building, McGill University</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1910" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1910">1910</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_67025f7f0e729bdc2bb5431c2573c22d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 6.5 x 9.5 inches, frame 11 x 15 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Montreal, Canada.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244016"
               id="aspace_899a49e72c183e29d68086e0f9135b8c"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>54. Blind massage therapist/physician at work, Japan</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1880" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_39449734af7f0a80ea78441f680f00c4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 10 x 8 inches, frame 20.5 x 16.5 inches; hand painted. Photographer: Losey. Location: Japan.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244017"
               id="aspace_1b6d551956d7f82271d196496e494088"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>55. 7th Company Medical Oﬃcers training camp, Fort Benjamin Harrison</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1917 August" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1917">1917</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d5311f520e97f74c0b0be23674052872">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 19.5 x 12.5 inches, frame 21 x 13.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Indianapolis, Indiana.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244018"
               id="aspace_3daa940adc8c69b862aafce4aa0524d4"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>56. Physician operating heart-lung machine</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1970" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1970">1970</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_32e0c3677feeeafff066262157da2f68">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 7 x 9 inches, frame 9 x 11 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244019"
               id="aspace_1c76ea153d32baa892ea442e194a5ce5"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>57. Extreme close-up of surgeon operating</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1960" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1960">1960</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_15a1179cf2f609d0bbc3f64567d2bdb9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 16 x 20 inches, frame 16 x 20 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244020"
               id="aspace_20843fcbb6669c6e5cfde2ab4623f695"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>58. Female physician taking pulse</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1898" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1898">1898</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_367852ac76b7bfd81088093f7ac14a7a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Photographic postcard, 3.5 x 5.5 inches, frame 6 x 8 inches. Photographer: A. Bergeret. Location: France. Subject: veterinary.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244021"
               id="aspace_4cf9c55e2cd2d003e6e1f461b4a6d1bf"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>59. Elmer O. Allman in veterinary physiology laboratory</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1916 December 12"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1916">1916</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b4933726be2ddd7c803a560ca5c92090">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 5 x 7 inches, frame 8 x 10 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: St. Joseph, Missouri.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244022"
               id="aspace_9dfb185314a9c751b13eb9f62117b580"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>60. Nurses and doctors pose outside entrance of woman's hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1905" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1905">1905</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1d6d336a6bc189ed26c4532617167ab0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 8 x 10 inches, frame 13 x 14.74 inches. Photographer: unknown.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244023"
               id="aspace_632b73cd3f761313df07c13d84e2d2e2"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>61. Nurses graduating class of 1917</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1910" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1910">1910</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_372a2d70bdea9b196c1a217c1d3b972e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver print, 14 x 9 inches, frame 16.5 x 13. 25 inches. Photographer: Kalmas.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243783"
            id="aspace_1b3b8688ccd2e7b5b9ef07023cb969bb"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Hard images</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
            </did>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243784"
            id="aspace_93ec745f7243d3f6eabd0597f7ecf5ba"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Lantern slides</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
            </did>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243785"
            id="aspace_c57a617de1581e8a9783fa5f5fa95720"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Panoramic photographs</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series IV</unitid>
            </did>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244024"
            id="aspace_b8994353869c3eb46cccabf79d05cce4"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Assembled collections</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series V</unitid>
               <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1900-1970"
                                   label="creation"
                                   unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <daterange>
                     <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                     <todate standarddate="1970">1970</todate>
                  </daterange>
               </unitdatestructured>
            </did>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244025"
               id="aspace_35f229fe0646c3e6e037b1728ee490b1"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ambulances and wards</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_97717a4bee4a0e640e4b319766919ce8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>64 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244026"
               id="aspace_affb172b6a1946081a2897659075f841"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cabinet cards</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_dd44be60137f33a35f88661b212a6f1f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>179 cabinet photographs (cabinet cards).</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244027"
               id="aspace_1d087b6517317b6f8f13d5f2e1d7a04f"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cardiology</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d64e8cdcc7a2cfc596de0305c9569b4f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>84 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244028"
               id="aspace_d68246b5778907801146194d4adb63cc"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dentistry</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_446f098e2ae94c96442186c12ac16e51">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>79 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244029"
               id="aspace_84bb236e68580cccde397c16684f74e0"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dermatology</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4ebb62aa9918d3c160916a3c2372a094">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>51 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244030"
               id="aspace_d4e1147ac890b3f4c7de491d0101f621"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Disability</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_80a9004bc70a67b20514f248bb8682cb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>109 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244031"
               id="aspace_e94c0e7af583ec87ba6849c6a19d1e59"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dissection</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_eb88f1357f8ea6b847c10c0673ef178f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>98 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244032"
               id="aspace_efea2c51436e355a1ffefb6a6f5f4efd"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Doctors at work</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_953f4f124412741ea8d8e4e53d1b6978">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>71 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244033"
               id="aspace_c931e5996256ae252dfc09ca9d84d60a"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Doctors' offices</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aff5ba34c6880f99aa783ad49a431fb9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>65 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244034"
               id="aspace_ca55c5d1e2471f2f050c50ec73cba7d1"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Doctors' portraits</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_41ba54a9767dcd1ab4991d9bc5b0bf06">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>120 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244035"
               id="aspace_1ee665e7b2d2eefa3090c456c429e491"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hospitals</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_efbfa6dfa4b23946dd9d4e96af7bfb4c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>148 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244036"
               id="aspace_cf9b93a5711af6ef89a57fcc608cbec4"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Infectious disease</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1a322c313991ca908acebf6c3138b63d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>89 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244037"
               id="aspace_1938029f252db47c6e6ed6c406f0f299"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Inventions and devices</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d6bbdcc37b3b0366c88902d04660e736">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>81 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244038"
               id="aspace_c0055bad763e6e86caa6b7f7709b8e8b"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Labs and vaccines</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3fe6e7a98113e630a7e720f3af93d676">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>87 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244039"
               id="aspace_7a5150f676dd86170597a605487cf427"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Large format</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_372e35d3c6da7e0d112807fed522a9f3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>116 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244040"
               id="aspace_30cbd7f681faf2e6d6730ed3247faaf6"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Masterpiece medical</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_120478d69c06dbe73329f2d5e8e9e14b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>69 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244041"
               id="aspace_6673cb0155460d31469a440863c85612"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical cartes-de-visite</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ce8eb48116909f9eabaf5499ea9f30a5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>204 cartes-de-visite.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244042"
               id="aspace_bf13c1660161a419fb80982ba52c6e0c"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical postcards</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e0cade1b3a6cc41dafcc5f8c8aa3125f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>401 photographic postcards and picture postcards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244043"
               id="aspace_e20aeb5ffd433b6eb117dfe963eb76dd"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mental health</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_743d65f0464ac32bf935ef474407ec4a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>59 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244044"
               id="aspace_5db92d705c2d331a3133c1c7965fe351"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nursing</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_befd0d5ca7f5843d1721aa453faf8b90">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>161 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244045"
               id="aspace_97df6d535c1c8f0d1f5a531e3cd4ae03"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Oncology</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f087649964709efb5177b8aafcf2c42d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>46 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244046"
               id="aspace_d4436e8e9b324647f3924ff99234bb7b"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ophthalmology</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8affa0d3b18fd7757a63df859b0d830e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>188 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244047"
               id="aspace_440142c2878997385da30d9b9ab533d8"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pediatrics</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d9f16d7429a9e63c0a741eae8c4a4437">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>32 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244048"
               id="aspace_2dbe20971a1dfe6f6dfc169eadc9a789"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pharmacy</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a65393012a3f67ce188ff34bf0be4dc0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>99 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244049"
               id="aspace_13a2396779ff8831695bd999a907b515"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Radiology</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bf73e71ac6340f893e61d44f20c6dc49">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>100 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244050"
               id="aspace_5bc144c705aad4d993a75c709d343279"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Respiratory</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5c61e2ab954d6d75aabf7b413f663b6b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>19 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244051"
               id="aspace_dec2f9b6dfda7e06b59c87251de7c85d"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Skulls and skeletons</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_60bd7f4298dcaf41fc3daa9345b255fd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>62 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244052"
               id="aspace_2e78f3489bf9180886ac85e1c7b232d6"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stereoviews</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c0699449b19ceed55bf4841f1f6b5b11">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>119 stereoscopic photographs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244053"
               id="aspace_e6d172afb75f70bdcfdf47f1d43cb88e"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stereoviews - war</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_22f52eb5cc85db13b5ee1d7d988b71b8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>113 stereoscopic photographs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244054"
               id="aspace_e4fd558163175cc491809ca18bd0b3dd"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Surgical scenes</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ad5be969dc333ca71665bab4f80790d1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>332 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244055"
               id="aspace_039bfa70353eb201a5b9ef0d4ced4545"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Tuberculosis</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fe582fd8187054c526df928c9e05014c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>57 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244056"
               id="aspace_94ddebbf91e40bde1e6b5037e8445aaf"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War I medicine</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d02f24c7cd86e4fd73252dbf2e601b54">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>62 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244057"
               id="aspace_ec6966729157e88fff433ac720762148"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War I postcards</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6ff0ccf2b3cfe8d34ba429a3961a8ccb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>442 photographic postcards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244058"
               id="aspace_721e4ba2b845a28a157884b855ae4ac2"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War II medicine</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_010807725c1f971b1302b41b2709f973">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>79 photographic prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244059"
            id="aspace_27e1ec0b4c43c101ab2fb94218b3dad7"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Special collections</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series VI</unitid>
               <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1860-1964"
                                   label="creation"
                                   unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <daterange>
                     <fromdate standarddate="1860">1860</fromdate>
                     <todate standarddate="1964">1964</todate>
                  </daterange>
               </unitdatestructured>
            </did>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244060"
               id="aspace_cc8d8869654a24390c749b533dca182a"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Abdominal surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a7d7b868002a6387b4c9edfb98c0ecdd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>23 gelatin silver prints, 7 x 5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: unknown. Description: doctors and nurses conducting an abdominal surgery at a hospital. The images document the patient receiving anesthesia, nurses prepping tools, and doctors using various instruments over the patient's body. Subject: operative scenes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244061"
               id="aspace_14b3bdeb245d0adc5a4aa47776ba1071"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists cervical cone display, Atlantic City, New Jersey</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1959" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1959">1959</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f0689b915f86bda53500c09b14d3cef7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>13 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244062"
               id="aspace_a6c889e80559dbecdc93232ce06f7d07"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Airfare examination center</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1944" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1944">1944</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_be3b67a032ead5a05bb8981d31c4ad82">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>16 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244063"
               id="aspace_a9f785197a1a25601de5921fd9a620e3"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>American Women's Hospital, France, World War I</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1915" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fc98f1d48da90afeb50c6dd7d6d4869c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>12 gelatin silver prints, 6.6 x 4.75 inches. Photographer: E. Belval. Location: France. Description: photographs of scenes at the American's Women Hospital in France circa 1915. Includes exterior shots of the hospital as well as surgical scenes, nurses and doctors with patients in wards, and other scenes around the hospital. All of the medical professionals pictured are women. Subject: medicine and war; hospitals and wards; nursing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244064"
               id="aspace_bb9fb2442fc1db9fde615716e662477f"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bellevue doctor's album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1880-1889"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1889">1889</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e7cef3afadf0fd94979484fc2a09869e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>8 cartes-de-visite, 2.5 x 4.25 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: New York City. Description: portraits of Bellevue physicians in the 1880s. The doctor's names are noted on the backs of the Cartes de Visite. Subject: pioneers and innovators; hospitals and wards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244065"
               id="aspace_c95ffb61bbfa5ef6c37ea0c0d16abb15"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Bellevue Training School for Male Nurses</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1888" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1888">1888</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_114fd6b4b0d5407286f2d51dbbb2b60f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>18 gelatin silver prints, 5.25 x 4.25 inches, mounted. Photographer: unknown. Location: New York City. Description: scenes includes exterior shots of the hospital, posed group portraits of nurses, and training scenes around the hospital. Female nurses are present in addition to the male nurses. Subjects: nursing; hospitals and wards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244066"
               id="aspace_386439ea3b1db4081cc4e68c6b758c0c"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Boston City Hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1878" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1878">1878</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_64df8f5d45de4396fc72882b586487c1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>12 albumen prints, multiple sizes, mounted, 6.5 x 8.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Boston, Massachusetts. Description: various scenes around the Boston City Hospital, including many exterior views, wards and operating rooms. Doctors, nurses, and patients are visible in several images. Subject: hospitals and wards; nursing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244067"
               id="aspace_4e924b202c616ecc0dbb787b938a887c"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Camp Dix Base Hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1918" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1918">1918</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_73ae5837d44879d9078b1cd6cb25c18f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>8 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244068"
               id="aspace_cc54d7c501b26dc9dfef5f09917d48a2"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Circumcision surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_15672e2cf08512be27a31c28fc31e2b4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>10 gelatin silver prints, 4.2 x 3.25 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: unknown. Description: collection of ten differentiate circumcision surgery scenes. Subject: operative scenes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244069"
               id="aspace_6778e2b5896036dc88b6435ac128ba06"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pierre and Marie Curie postcards, France</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1898–1906" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1898">1898</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1906">1906</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0828d648f1400116263ea95ba5c3fe21">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>4 photographic postcards, 5.5 x 2.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: France. Description: includes a portrait of Marie Curie, a portrait of Pierre Curie, a portrait of both at a lab bench, and a photograph of Pierre Curie at La Sorbonne surrounded by his students. Specialty: radiology, oncology, radium therapy. Subject: pioneers and innovators; laboratories and doctors' offices.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244070"
               id="aspace_df392c915f8f53e27ab89aa57706f62b"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Doctor's visit postcard series, Spain</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1900" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4340837e257e4029b4c840f639e6f3f4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>10 photographic postcards, 3.5 x 5.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Spain. Description: series chronicling a doctor's visit to a family. The postcards are numbered 1-10 and tell a chronological story. Subject: therapy and treatment.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244071"
               id="aspace_d3f46af946e0af9727ca9a00c0e76dec"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Carlos Finlay, M.D., yellow fever research, Havana, Cuba</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1879" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1879">1879</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3751d93b2dda9befb94729af9c18b678">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>21 gelatin silver prints, 4.25 x 6.5inches, mounted. Photographer: Carlos Finlay. Location: Havana, Cuba. Description: photographs of microscope slides from Dr. Carlos Finlay's study of yellow fever in Cuba. Each image of blood infected with yellow fever indicates day of the patient's infection the blood was taken (i.e. 5th day), and whether or not the case was fatal. Also includes photographs from other glass slides. Specialty: infectious diseases. Subject: medical specialties; disease and pathology; pioneers and innovators.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244072"
               id="aspace_16a7c0508c98aa8d82f72e189041db37"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dr. Caulkins, intestinal surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930-1939"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1939">1939</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6a849c5bd38d1aa34b1628033d20ef77">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>30 items; 29 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244073"
               id="aspace_275dcdacffcc12d65272ce46b3b390a3"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>European hospital collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1914" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_69d75854df4a9849ebe55ad3c703b7b0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>41 gelatin silver prints, mounted on album pages.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244074"
               id="aspace_f37196500320073bcdd48c40b7a55760"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Female chiropractor's personal collection, Palmer Chiropractor School</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920-1929"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1929">1929</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_46bf1077bf0378bfdfcc569a56b97841">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>87 items; 86 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244075"
               id="aspace_aef95dcaeeca233661852ff099418043"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Female orthopedic surgical cases</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1938" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1938">1938</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_025ae85a3c47644253abb5129b7b937e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>6 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244076"
               id="aspace_241fd1e2504d37bf4943531b40810d3e"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Great pediatricians</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1893" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1893">1893</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_88a088735e90bbf4e04bc70efd8c884f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>12 publication prints, multiple sizes on 5.5 x 9 inch pages. Photographer: Archives of Pediatrics. Location: various. Description: portraits of "Eminent Pediatrists of the World." Each page contains a portrait, the doctor's signature, and a month and year. Specialty: pediatrics. Subject: medical specialties; pioneers and innovators.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244077"
               id="aspace_14b002225a99fa5eae15dbdc2bc9d9c8"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hospitals and staff</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1910" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1910">1910</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b885140b3e26346937daaeb86bcbdef1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>9 gelatin silver prints, 8.5 x 6.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: unknown. Description: recovering in wards. Subject: hospitals and wards; nursing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244078"
               id="aspace_17fb111b535e0eeccf88d6f345910644"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hospital survey</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ad45c637cbc62490551a41d0ca508f41">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>6 gelatin silver prints, 8 x 5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: unknown. Description: posed group portraits of doctors and nurses in various parts of a hospital, including an operating room, lounge, and front steps. Also includes an exterior shot. Subject: hospitals and wards; nursing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244079"
               id="aspace_76e535c0c18fec7ef36521b7f51a7386"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Israeli Medical Corp</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1950" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1950">1950</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e112517a204689ebc65a0ed8b9d9efd2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>13 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244080"
               id="aspace_1eb569d74e486f0adce67ace62e6e539"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jersey City Hospital</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ab9dac12ec096ce534be1a172fe53697">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>4 gelatin silver prints, one mounted.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244081"
               id="aspace_142146b504999ad69d9b637be30bf35d"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Johns Hopkins surgical cases</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1920–1928" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1928">1928</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_1b25786ec04f63e3f179653036c6dabd">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>123 gelatin silver prints, multiple sizes. Photographer: unknown. Location: Baltimore, Maryland. Description: surgical photographs from Johns Hopkins, pre and post operative images of multiple conditions including lip reconstruction and head wounds; x-rays; surgical instruments; and dissected organs. Subject: disease and pathology; therapy and treatments; hospitals and wards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244082"
               id="aspace_c6cfd93301c7fd5ffd38de04b1e70417"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Lernt Helfen" (Learn to Help), Germany</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1952" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1952">1952</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ba02929775cc1319a0d2ed2e20cee1eb">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>60 stereoscopic photographs, 5.1 x 2.3 inches. Photographer: Raumbild-Verlag Otto Schonstein. Location: Germany. Description: series of 60 stereoviews titled (from German): "Learn to Help. A stereoview of first aid work for lay helpers." Most scenes show people aiding injured people. A few are x-rays or close up shots of injuries. The back of each stereoview has a description of the scene. Subject: anatomy and education.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244083"
               id="aspace_3bbadb24de1a4e8e16ddd048d6d2d383"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lincoln School for Nurses, Bronx, New York City</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_87a4ab62e81138fd737357514d014a8d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>13 gelatin silver prints, multiple sizes. Photographer: unknown. Location: New York City. Description: candid photographs of African American nurses in uniform and in regular clothing. Subject: nursing.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244084"
               id="aspace_6cc636a168c87dfdb39dee7bb2e84af2"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Henry O. Marcy operating collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1900" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e92e598c12150d992623e3780f5e8654">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>8 gelatin silver prints, mounted.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244085"
               id="aspace_03d55b17526211f70a48cf1bed6087a8"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Edward Maynard M.D., pioneer dentist</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1860–1891" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1860">1860</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1891">1891</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_38748e9cde25c6c8019c09df0d6610cf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>10 cartes-de-visites, 2.5 x 4.25 inches. Photographer: Gardner Phillip; Solomon Maurice Farrington, and unknown. Location: New York City. Description: images of Dr. Edward Maynard, dentist and firearms inventor, as well as his family. Specialty: dentistry. Subject: medical specialties; pioneers and innovators.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244086"
               id="aspace_7cf9be79b298047742b12d9f3df52d2e"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Medical school, Burlington, Vermont</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1880-1889"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1889">1889</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4b5d273ac09f75a8e739702cf149e521">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>9 cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), 4.2 x 6.5 inches. Photographer: unknown. Location: Burlington, Vermont. Description: portraits of medical school doctors with names noted on the backs of cards. Subject: anatomy and education.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244087"
               id="aspace_e7448e6dc67b7f2cb0ea3025553b6b2b"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>J. Meeker M.D., Morristown, New Jersey</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1860-1870"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1860">1860</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1870">1870</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_39a8cb4e4bd356fbdf03acf034bd7487">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>35 cartes-de-visites, 2.5 x 4.25 inches, multiple sizes. Photographer: Gurney, Brady, D. Clark, Lacey, and others. Location: Morristown, New Jersey. Description: from the family album of Dr. J. W. Meeker. Subject: pioneers and innovators.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244088"
               id="aspace_6d360ba8f3d1b17703e697ebec16c39a"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Negative of patients</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4c9a9bf4d31a03f39ded97bf42ccb369">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>18 photographic negatives, multiple sizes. Photographer: unknown. Location: unknown. Description: negatives of unidentified patients, mainly portraits, also includes a photograph of skin lesions, some diseased organs, and medical instruments. Subject: disease and pathology.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244089"
               id="aspace_933cbfa14c093901b8e3ffac81399c96"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Neurological exams, San Francisco</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1880-1889"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1889">1889</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5bb2ed9f417d65d1b90c122ce07d1220">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>4 cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), 4.2 x 6.4 inches. Photographer: Charles Lainer. Location: 715 Market Street, San Francisco, California. Description: images of a young male patient during a neurological exam. Includes reflex testing, etc. Specialty: neurology. Subject: medical specialties; therapy and treatments.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244090"
               id="aspace_11f70c205a7a52e208e18798df3fec14"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New York State Mental Health Exhibition collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1915–1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1920">1920</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_30a19e024113bfe6d2e9e4e9391860a1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>11 gelatin silver prints, 10 x 8 inches, mounted, 14 x 12 inches. Photographer: Cunningham Studios, Utica, New York. Location: New York City. Description: patients at the Utica State Hospital participating in different exercise and crafting classes. Men and women are treated separately. Male classes include exercising and woodworking, female classes are mainly knitting and needlepoint. Some captions denote the "grade," or the severity of mental illness of the patients. One photograph is of patients performing "The Merchant of Venice" at the Central Islip State Hospital. Specialty: mental health. Subject: medical specialties; therapy and treatments; hospitals and wards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244091"
               id="aspace_49c5b8f29a8d8d19fba1c5141ce773b3"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New Jersey Orthopedic College</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1925-1935"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1925">1925</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1935">1935</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e804ee438efa21f3e989394668071c0d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>37 gelatin silver prints, multiple dimensions. Photographer: unknown. Location: New Jersey. Description: includes images of patients recovering in wards, adults and children with physical abnormalities, and "diagnosis photographs" of patients, including African American men, standing against a wall. Photographs of leg and foot problems, such as turned feet, knock knees, and hip problems are featured. Specialty: orthopedics. Subject: hospitals and wards; disease and pathology; therapy and treatments.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244092"
               id="aspace_8122422bcab7f7a632fd549d2d972acd"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New York Medical College graduates</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1896–1897" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1896">1896</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1897">1897</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_77bbacb0f9c1a3da67768f5f9a865777">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>33 cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), 4.25 x 6.5 inches. Photographer: Dana of New York. Location: New York City. Description: portraits, some have doctor's names and hospital appointments on the back. Subject: anatomy and education.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244093"
               id="aspace_d7b3b5e32c873cc06d8c41a91b325fe8"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New York State Mental Hospital</unittitle>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_23821142e336555be9a9e91ef563a340">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>63 items: 53 gelatin silver prints, 10 glass negatives.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244094"
               id="aspace_7d08e342000af736af69d7bce5aa54e5"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>New York University Physicians, Gurney collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1880-1889"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_aa51a764c2d02093bb41a485c0de8011">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>10 cartes-de-visites, 2.5 x 4.25 inches. Photographer: Gurney. Location: New York City. Description: Portraits, some with name of the doctor noted on the back. Subject: hospitals and wards; pioneers and innovators.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244095"
               id="aspace_dc8e8b4da309dc0266a428739d36b170"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nurses personal collection, Cook County Hospital, Chicago</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940-1949"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1949">1949</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_73941fdd709a13fd934813d97b67570b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>65 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244096"
               id="aspace_49a36c4102fad543ae5b8eeb8b533582"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nurse's album pages</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1890" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1890">1890</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_036d04dcd1322fafeac6e78c6969b0c9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>17 gelatin silver prints, mounted on album pages.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244097"
               id="aspace_4d9addf9da3137432d75c2b1ad29a420"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ophthalmologist Victor Morax personal collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930-1939"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1939">1939</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5de093fd99d5da9a4053bcb2bb42bb7a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>21 photographic prints, multiple formats, multiple dimensions. Photographer: unknown. Location: France. Description: personal photographs of Dr. Victor Morax. Includes postcards and photographs, mostly group shots of family and friends. Dr. Morax was one of the world's leading ophthalmologists, famous for his work in bacteriology, notably the discovery of Morax-Axenfeld diplobacilli. Specialty: opthalmology. Subject: medical specialties.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244098"
               id="aspace_981ce81562a142bd3071fd89835f7cf7"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ophthalmology clinic, Haifa, Israel</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1922" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1922">1922</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_752960a0242939bca141ff196c14e3c8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>9 photographic prints, multiple formats, multiple dimensions. Photographer: unknown. Location: Haifa, Israel. Description: includes portraits of doctors, doctors examining patients, etc. Specialty: ophthalmology. Subject: laboratories and doctors' offices; therapy and treatments; operative scenes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244099"
               id="aspace_53f5f2ca8828fc9285d5d89f035882dc"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ophthalmologic exam stereoview collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5d46f5aa55cbcc7defcbd0214097c1dc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>19 items; 15 stereoscopic photographs.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244100"
               id="aspace_72d0df02bacb96e92de909bcae0a173a"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ophthalmology exhibition, Manhattan Eye Ear and Throat Hospital </unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1947" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1947">1947</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_37edc1c478406345544d00ce3bae8913">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>11 items: 10 photographic prints, 13 x 17 inches, and 1 exhibition catalog. Photographer: Tad Horton. Location: New York City. Description: prints from exhibit at the hospital, including surgical scenes and patient exams, in large format, mainly focusing on ophthalmology. The photographs were also used for "The Continuing Story of Manhattan Eye, Ear and Throat Hospital - 77th Annual Report" in 1947. Also includes the annual report booklet. Specialty: ophthalmology. Subject: medical specialties; therapy and treatments; operative scenes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244101"
               id="aspace_336ee5dfe69af005e244e7b8b338179b"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Palmer Chiropractic School women's collection, Davenport, Iowa</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6f9f41dc6f388d93de4224a18da990de">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>19 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244102"
               id="aspace_3e2490780f1116921ab21f35565d7906"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dr. Pick neurology glass negatives</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1910" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1910">1910</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b903ed823911e9444f0ea5601477f96b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>3 glass plate negatives.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244103"
               id="aspace_4b3ccd7c066936a36f3e7a77b5ff0757"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pre and post-operative cancer patients, Allentown, Pennsylvania</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1915" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1915">1915</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_01fab688cb76d859859e5d3781dac22a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>108 gelatin silver prints, multiple sizes. Photographer: unknown. Location: Allentown, Pennsylvania. Description: includes everything from oral wounds to mastectomies. Collection is divided into male (45 photos) and female (63 photos) cancer patients. Subject: disease and pathology; therapy and treatments.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244104"
               id="aspace_57e66d7008981bc0879524a99bfbe422"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Red Cross, Laos</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1964" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1964">1964</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8ec1a0129e15d24140598a009603af34">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>12 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244105"
               id="aspace_ceab3411b3b6fcc32d304836e8391021"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Russian lung cancer animal research</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1967" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1967">1967</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c54009c2577e96da20e493c4fd695b0e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>10 gelatin silver prints, 10 x 8 inches. Photographer: Syndication International. Location: Russian Republic of Georgia (now Georgia). Description: rabbits and monkeys participating in a lung cancer study. Pictures include animals with "duck bill" masks strapped to their faces, which each have an opening with a large cigarette sticking out. Scientists are seen lighting cigarettes and checking on the animals. Also includes photographs of monkeys in a zoo-like habitat, which is perhaps where they live when not participating in the experiment. Subject: disease and pathology; therapy and treatments.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244106"
               id="aspace_72124977dabb00da02775e0f028a9b08"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>W. M. Schroeder, M.D., Medical Photographer</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1880-1889"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1880">1880</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1889">1889</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_cffbd5fdcd68c52a130805c5916441d6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>8 albumen prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244107"
               id="aspace_ef68ac2c0e8e06157e51b355d2b42bd2"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Smallpox epidemic New York City</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1881" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1881">1881</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_f01c2f435911c534d21a43cd34b847f0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>21 platinum prints, 7 x 9 inches, mounted. Photographer: unknown. Location: New York City. Description: person showing just the face, or face and partial torso. A few images show two people, siblings or mother and child. Some portraits note when during the patient's illness the photograph was taken (i.e. 6 hours before death). Specialty: infectious diseases. Subject: disease and pathology; therapy and treatments.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244108"
               id="aspace_cf6af66bc743c95b399f7bce11234dc4"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Syfogen naso-therapy unit</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4533b9b89adfb6f3fe83e41d9b5f2e0c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Prints from pages of a publication.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244109"
               id="aspace_2ba91e0e43be58e32859844fcb76cbdd"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>United States Army serum preparation</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1918" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1918">1918</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_04eb4b612bc00893c3d9cadf24056758">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>16 gelatin silver prints, 10 x 8 inches. Photographer: United States Army. Location: unknown. Description: scientists preparing serums, pictured during different parts of the creation process. Some of the photographs list the step they are on, or the equipment being used. All scientists are male. Subject: therapy and treatments; laboratories and doctors' offices; medicine and war.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244110"
               id="aspace_871b207011d544c330c0acbf9eb661ee"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>United States General Hospital Number 30, Plattsburgh, New York</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1919" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1919">1919</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8f37177e4e68dacc77213ae2a8b62488">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>9 photographic postcards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244111"
               id="aspace_27b91f8d427f6f3a7f901818adda89bc"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Walter Reed chest injuries, World War I</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1914-1919"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1919">1919</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_edd2d1c5591d327614d5a2891bfa234b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>4 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244112"
               id="aspace_b220ff20f435fae4d6ec65a64e6a0e39"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Walter Reed plastic surgery</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1919–1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1919">1919</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1920">1920</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ba1b2bed6156c6712df4b1a9b5b3bd0b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>111 gelatin silver prints, multiple sizes. Photographer: Alice L. Becht. Location: Washington, D.C. Description: photographs of soldiers who received plastic surgery in the Maxillo-Facial Ward of Walter Reed United States Army Hospital. Several photos per case show pre and post-operative wounds. Specialty: plastic surgery. Subject: medicine and war; therapy and treatments; hospitals and wards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244113"
               id="aspace_e76610c295b1eeccabda4bd6f3d49b22"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War I hospital chart head wound photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1914-1919"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1919">1919</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8735e560fc625fca78f4b2006c2143c5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>6 photographic postcards.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244114"
               id="aspace_6b90e1b11359db603cba6ead781b984c"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War I photography exhibit</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1918" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1918">1918</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8c53002b6a7985519bada8e3f40969a3">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244115"
               id="aspace_91a5ea2e0f6806bd7def6c598810a3c8"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War II Australian military medical series, New Guinea</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940-1945"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1945">1945</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b2247e762b9cbcc2c59c24284dc86e86">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>7 gelatin silver prints, multiple sizes. Photographer: (Australian) Department of Information. Location: New Guinea. Description: Australian military medical doctors, includes operative scenes, makeshift triage stations and wards, soldiers burying the dead, and dead soldiers in rubble. Subject: medicine and war; operative scenes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244116"
               id="aspace_20a2fc91f0d21caef4510f5ce4df2fb9"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>World War II blood transfusion collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940-1945"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1945">1945</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_06cb4524c6458b0e9646ea81d67fc5f0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>12 gelatin silver prints.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244117"
               id="aspace_444bd117b33041632eab307f27ad49cf"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hugh H. Young, M.D., copy print collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1930" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c9827498b7da105fd0fd5bb9bd6acfdf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>4 items: 3 gelatin silver prints and 1 photocopy of letter.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244127"
            id="aspace_5109b5712e9f9af1f0fd395f0b88227e"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Medical photograph albums</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series VII</unitid>
            </did>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244144"
               id="aspace_44bd2a3b94b832eaec9fcc9cf4fc4807"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>25th Medical Battalion, Yokohama, Japan</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1947–1950" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1947">1947</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1950">1950</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b83dcd0beb22ed843d73aec19b2a8084">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.75 x 14.5 inches; 306 photographic prints, 3 x 4 inches, 2 x 3 inches. Japanese lacquered cover with image of Mt. Fuji and abalone inlay, heavy black paper leaves, multiple images per page. Album created by noncommissioned officer in medical corps, includes photographs of the clinic, medical dressing station, and soldier's life in Japan, including trips to Hiroshima and 8 colorized tourist photographs of Kobe. Also includes one photograph of dentists at work. Some photographs are captioned in ink on surface.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244145"
               id="aspace_c8db125ecc5fc09ba15e67bb04fe973d"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Avranches, Dr. Bernard Heon, X-ray album, France</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1902" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1902">1902</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_82fbf578f0173de5476d75cb55759c38">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10 x 13 inches; 46 photographic prints, multiple sizes. Red cloth over board album covers, hard board leaves. Album contains X-ray photographs of human body parts and some animals. Photographs are glued to album pages, includes some handwritten descriptions in French. Several photographs stamped "Doctor Bernard Heon Avranches" on reverse.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244140"
               id="aspace_d494088bfc5e3283d274ab6400487554"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Berkley Gymnasium spinal curvature and posture logbook</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1905–1909" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1905">1905</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1909">1909</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a4b5d38a7dff2b004d3b8b20008d02e2">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10.5 x 8.25 inches; 10 photographic prints, 5 x 7 inches; patient intake cards, posture change plots, and labratory test result reports. Leather covered notebook, 252 lined pages, contains hand written notes and documention of scoliosis patients recorded by M. K. Wallin, M.D. Examination cards, lab result reports, drawings recording changes in spinal curvature, and photographs are interleaved with notes.  Some photographs include captions on reverse.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244170"
               id="aspace_2fd6323c8266ce894eb6852de2a16031"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Boxer Rebellion military hospital album, China</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1899-1901"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1899">1899</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1901">1901</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_32a696ea7d77fc395bfc321ee5b5534b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7 x 10 inches; 53 items: photographic prints, cyanotypes, photographic postcards. Gray paper cover with partial border and "Photographs" in raised green; 16 grey paper leaves; bound with string. Sticker inside back cover: "Mfd. By the Heinn Specialty Co., Milwaukee, Wis., Badger Albums 03." Photographs include medical tents, doctors, patient care, priests, military scenes, and locations including Peking (now Beijing), Mt. Wang-Sho, and Tientsin (also known as Tianjin) during the Boxer Rebellion in China.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244171"
               id="aspace_d05ce848bbac1313d5b75acd879d8576"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Cambridge Instrument Company, electro cardiology equipment album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920-1950"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1950">1950</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4bb1c0bedf17e3fb35953e1d5d9470ef">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.25 x 9.5 inches; 32 photographic prints. Brown faux leather binder with 2 prong metal attachment bar. Half of album contents in plastic sleeves, remainder is tipped in or hole punched. Materials in album include photographic prints of people, electrocardiology equipment, and written material; glossy and matte paper with images and text; cardboard leaf with electrocardiograph printouts attached; and reproductions of typed documents on Cambridge Instrument Company letterhead stationery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3252790"
               id="aspace_09924cf8e3e7c9dd7b848adf49f8bab9"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>"Cardinal Spellman at Fort Sam, Spring 1952"</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1952">1952</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2d80d843c3402e4ab65406d8e6fa008d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Page dimensions: 12 x 9 inches. 5 photographic prints, 4.5 x 3 inches. 1 disbound black paper album page. Photographs of Cardinal Spellman with a wounded soldier in a ward and with doctors and military staff in a ward and exiting a building.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244130"
               id="aspace_57befe027b1fc67856a54f1ffda14454"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>La Cassagne, Alexander, dermatological album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1900" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_56a6f5f7c1759bb3271933d875e0d7d9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 14.5 x 11.5 inches; 95 photographic prints, 5 x 7 inches. Maroon leather album with art nouveau style metal decorations on front cover, leaves are pale green board with frame openings. Album created by Alexander Lacassagne, Leon, France. Includes portraits of various  dermatological diseases with handwritten notes.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244173"
               id="aspace_f362d8a17fa165af4d9b001d00233665"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Chadwick-Herns, Ava V., Battle Creek Sanitarium album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1906–1907" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1906">1906</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1907">1907</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_10fbc26edd1fb81a7e90cafff450cacc">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 6.75 x 9.75; multiple trimmed photographic prints. Printed publication with brown paper cover, enclosed in green suede outer cover, secured with suede string. Title on brochure cover is "Battle Creek Sanitarium" embossed in silver gilt with oval print illustration of hospital exterior adhered to cover. Brochure published by the sanitarium used by sanitarium employee Ava V. Chadwick as a personal photograph album. Contains handwritten notes and inscriptions to Chadwick from sanitarium patients and staff, many accompanied by small portrait photographs, also 1 tipped in note and photograph of exterior of institution adhered to title page.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244174"
               id="aspace_8767f9e60c4e4c3320a33ae77eb112bf"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Colonie Marine 1925: Fondazione Citta Fiume per la Colonie Infantili Marine et Montane</part>
                     </title>. Pediatric tuberculosis sanitarium, Fiume, Italy</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1925" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1925">1925</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="ita">Italian</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_93a1562b0211faa0161dd36807a55b6b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 8.75 x 6.75 inches; 17 photographic prints, 4.5 x 6.25 inches and 3.25 x 5.25 inches. Gray cover with "Colonie Marine, 1925" and "Fondazione Citta Fiume per la Colonie Infantili Marine et Montane" printed in embossed gold; leaves are gray paper. Inscription on first page: "A John J. Freschi Presidente del Comitante, Corciata per i bambini tubereolotici di Fiume in segno di viva gratitudine, la Fondazione "Citta di Fiume" per colonie Marine e Montane offre. Fiume Ottobre 1925." Album depicts treatments for children with tuberculosis, including swimming in the ocean, heliotherapy, dining outside, napping under trees, being weighed and measured, taking medication, and attending class in open sided tents. Inscriptions written in ink below photographs are in Italian.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244154"
               id="aspace_f8ddc37ffcd2706ed0041963ce72f63e"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Conquest of yellow fever, Cuba</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1904" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1904">1904</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_4ee5f8eb14423fa3c9e32b9a99f18bca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.25 x 15.5 iches; 89 photographic prints in bound album, 31 prints on unbound album pages. Album covers are missing, black paper leaves. Photographer: Trafton and unknown. Detailed documentation of the conquest of yellow fever in Havana including sanitary efforts, medical procedures, laboratory studies, administrative efforts, and vaccine preparations. Album includes list of contents.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244155"
               id="aspace_8a6e08a71a234de725f226a30c4d0b12"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Considérations sur la Rééducation Professionelle Dans les Industries du Bâtiment</part>
                     </title>. Post World War I French disability rehabilitation report</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1917" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1917">1917</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ba736415eaa8d5b985b2d6bd86a6131e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 4.25 x 6.5 inches; 13 photographic prints and typed report. Library binding, disbound pages of manilla paper, and tipped in report on translucent paper. Photographs are glued to pages with typed text. Official research presentation to the French Government showing how to rehabilitate soldiers with leg amputations into various occupations. Photographs show healed amputations, prosthetics, and soldiers wearing prosthetics at work. Report is signed by C. Vallée. Album is in French.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244151"
               id="aspace_4d081e31f80cee92ea716e539b69fc37"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Cook County Hospital</part>
                     </title>, Chicago, Illinois</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1890" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1890">1890</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ef1ce3cd994a1cee579a627555462e76">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.25 x 9 inches; 21 photographic prints. Yellow paper cover album laced with blue string, 21 medium weight off-white paper leaves. Images and captions are printed on pages. Includes prints of photographs of autopsy, surgical scenes, and emergency room treatment.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_86c20ef7f1053583c0c5fb67d93d7d9c"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3252787"
               id="aspace_fb0a7765614d55ccd9da50bb96cf3c0e"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Cornell Medical College</part>
                     </title>, Sept-June 1920-21</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1921">1921</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fd95d85d4c7a71b6929e81e48cfd8cb0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10 x 12.75. 14 photographic prints, multiple sizes. 3 disbound black paper leaves of a photograph album. Album title and captions in white ink. Photographs include bacteriology lab, students, doctors, and building exteriors. Also includes 2 photographs of a visit to Yale.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3252788"
               id="aspace_8fef2618085010a1f9ef71a60ca51913"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>European hospital album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1914" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_8ae16ffaaea7171a5f6ca5b881271fd5">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Page dimensions: 9.5 x 12.75; 40 photographic prints, multiple sizes. 4 disbound off-white paper leaves from one or more photograph albums. Images include nurses and doctors attending patients and at rest, surgical scenes, traction apparatus, wards, and patients.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244128"
               id="aspace_05ee847ce959afa233c269de9adffae8"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>LaFerte, Dr. Daniel Antoin, pediatric orthopedic album, Volume 1</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1894–1895" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1894">1894</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1895">1895</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7310093c677770452d4d60b456f4d02f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10.5 x 8.5 inches; 21 cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), cyanotypes (photographs). Brown covers, leaves are off white board with frame openings. Photographer: C. Eisenheart. Individual portraits of patients with names and dates written in ink below. Includes letter from Wes Cowam with doctor's information: Dr. Daniel Antoin La Ferte began practice in 1871 at Harper General and Children's Free Hospital, he died in 1924. He was a pioneer in hip surgery.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244129"
               id="aspace_b6b0c78ddc6fdd803c3bbd795218990e"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>LaFerte, Dr. Daniel Antoin, pediatric orthopedic album, Volume 2</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1899–1900" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1899">1899</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1900">1900</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9bc78d6f3ac892517afe7ef717bf7fae">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.25 x 9.25 inches; 25 cabinet photographs (cabinet cards). Brown covers, leaves are off white board with frame openings. Photographer: Watson. Individual portraits of patients with names and dates written in ink below.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244152"
               id="aspace_ecb8c601fb1d8cb21702ee2569a8849f"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Faulkner, James, M.D., Harvard Medical Unit, World War I </unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1914-1918"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1918">1918</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7cda0f9f7d4e477175b3de216e7985ba">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11 x 14 inches; 469 photographic prints, typed documents, ephemera, newspaper clippings. Album created by Dr. James Faulkner, documents activities of medical unit in France, training in the United States, and general war scenes in France and Germany. Photographs are captioned with handwritten descriptions or captions printed in the image. Documents include discharge papers. Also includes program from Harvard University Unit, 2nd Contingent, visit to Oxford signed by William Osler.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_62a26c2718fe4511bece99cb204a0462"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244135"
               id="aspace_0a4e65d113057855c074e4b2cf89f837"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Fulton, Mrs. Dr. A. M., Women's Medical College, London</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1874" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1874">1874</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b7280821841ba13c7970735f12bcd41b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 9 x 12 inches; 65 photographic prints; cartes-de-visite (card photographs), cabinet photographs (cabinet cards), and 13.4 x 6.5 inch photographic prints. Dark brown leather cover with metal clasp, leaves are off-white board with frame openings. Gold embossed inscription reads: "Presented to Mrs. Dr. A. M. Fulton by friends in London. February 1874." Album of first woman graduate of Women's Medical College. Includes 52 cartes-de-visites of physicians and nurses, cartes-de-visite and cabinet photographs (cabinet cards) of English royalty, and large format photographic prints of British landscape. Some photographs are inscribed on reverse, some are captioned on album pages.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3252792"
               id="aspace_697a4e8929a41d5704ff4987e90d4511"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>German children's hospitals album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1925">1925</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1926">1926</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_40fa3169f9f9162c0d7666c5d2abbebf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11 x 15 inches. 27 photographic prints, multiple sizes. Disbound black paper leaves, 2 full and 2 partial from a photograph album. Includes photographs of Pirquet Klinik, Kaiser and Kaiserin Friedrich Kinderkranken Haus, and tourist photographs of Berlin with captions written in white ink. Images include wards, preparing food, patients, children napping outside, doctors, and nurses.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244162"
               id="aspace_9272d400199eaacaac3053b09b60de87"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Homeopathic medical school carte de visite album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1860-1870"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1860">1860</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1870">1870</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d2239504fbad2c5d5d645e7795fee3b6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 5.5 x 8 inches; 79 cartes-de-visite (card photographs). Leather covered 3 dimensional covers with gold embossed patterning, 4 ceramic buttons on top and bottom covers, 2 metal and ceramic hinged hasp closures. Leaves of paper covered board have frame openings and slots for inserting carte de visite photographs, gold borders around frame and sides of page, edges of leaves are gilded. Each page holds the portraits of two doctors, many with names inscribed on front or reverse. Includes two photographs of portraits of C. F. Hahnemann, founder of homeopathic medicine.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244159"
               id="aspace_91650e24c40364532f61d2890ad196da"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hookworm Disease Commission album, Jamaica</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_5d369aada4a88003e782d7f7ef499684">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 5.75 x 8.5 inches; 50 items: 46 photographic prints, 2 drawings, 1 printed photograph (paper copy), 1 certificate. Black cloth over board covers, leaves secured with black string. Album includes text and photographs documenting hookworm disease parasite, symptoms, causes, efforts to eradicate disease in Jamaica, and treatment of patients. Includes photographs of microscopic views of the parasite, people infected with Hookworm, public education events,  patients before and after treatment, Jamaica Hookworm Commission staff, documents and signs, and the transcript of a patient testimonial letter.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244142"
               id="aspace_304340b4f5c1e4e99e47837a359bdfe4"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Jewish doctor studying medicine in Vienna</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1929-1936" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1929">1929</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1936">1936</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ee8efdb4bd5a11e899a84aa4730910a8">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 8.25 x 12 inches; 197 photographic prints. 42 leaves of dark brown paper alternate with patterned translucent paper. Album created by a Jewish doctor from New York, documents several trips to Europe, including medical studies in Vienna 1932-1933, and vacations in the United States. Contains photographs from medical school, autopsies, anatomy institute, travels, and family members. Most photographs are captioned with names, dates, and locations.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3252793"
               id="aspace_c743c7d6c582d5febe8dc6edb157328f"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Schönborn, Siegfried and Krieger, Hans, <title>
                        <part>Klinischer Atlas der Nervenkrankheiten</part>
                     </title>, 71 plates</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1908" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1908">1908</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="ger">German</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0728e5b34f6ca3c61d0e8f447e93c2a9">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Disbound pages from an incomplete volume in a 3 ring binder. Includes plates and description of plates from Klinischer Atlas der Nervenkrankheiten (Clinical Atlas of Nerve Diseases) by Siegfried Schönborn and Hans Krieger. Publication is in German.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244161"
               id="aspace_da8402903b9765de1508c457a48178f5"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Kriegszahnklinik der IV. Armee in Lublin</part>
                     </title>. German army maxillofacial surgery album, World War I</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1916" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1916">1916</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="ger">German</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_3178bbfc7f3c0d791970b7c36d329ea4">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10 x 13 inches; 43 photographic prints, 4.5 x 6.5 inches, 4 x 5.75 inches. Green cloth covered album, leaves of dark green board, and brown patterned end papers. Title "Kriegszahnklinik der IV Armee in Lublin" (War Dental Clinic of the Fourth Army in Lublin). Photographs mounted one or two per page. Images of medical staff, patients being treated, medical equipment and facilities. Images include soldiers who have had reconstructive surgery on their face and jaws sitting next to a cast of their injures. Also includes images of the city of Lublin, including Jewish areas.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244146"
               id="aspace_22731d1709cddc90e415d0a0d0c66ffa"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>London Military Hospitals of the Grand Duchess George of Russia</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1914–1918" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1918">1918</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_a1c4c0590e3ff70da8cfadc25309c2cf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 9.25 x 12.25  inches; 193 photographic prints, multiple sizes including 3 x 5 inches, 3 x 4 inches, and 8 x 10 inches; 1 Christmas card and 1 newspaper clipping. Purple leather cover with gold embosseded interior, hard board leaves. Portrait glued to inside of front cover. Photographs of wounded British soldiers from various military hospitals including Heather Hill hospital, Tewit Hall Hospital, Hospital  H.I.H. Grand Duchess George of Russia, and St. Nicholas Hospital. Includes hand written captions, some on reverse of prints. Inscription on first page reads "From the staff and wounded men at St. Nicholas Hospital, [?] 1915, Harragate."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244141"
               id="aspace_373d944f7d7ec9ef3d9472f30b65579d"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Mackinnon, Ethel F., nurse's album, World War I, England</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1919" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1919">1919</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_57b11c0a14a6bab60e31744e6c2c44db">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.5 x 10.25 inches; 60 items: 51 photographic prints, 9 photographic postcards. Brown cloth covered board cover, dark brown board leaves. Inscription on the front endpaper reads "Ethel F. Mackinnon, Greenback House, Greenick(?), 11th Novr., 1919." Includes photographs of nurses, soldiers, wards, hospital lounges, and recreation rooms at Southwood and Springburn hospitals, some captioned with names and positions below. Also incudes postcard of rail car fitted out for tranport of wounded British soldiers.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244156"
               id="aspace_62b7868b54ac5f6d7a0774a1cc81369c"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>MacKinnon, Lillian, Anglo-American Hospital superintendent, Havana, Cuba</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1943-1953" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1943">1943</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1953">1953</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0fa7e6b8cf987125960360c968e6adb7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11 x 8.75 inches; 10 photographic prints, multiple sizes; clippings; and ephemera. Unbound black paper leaves, no cover. Album created by Lillian MacKinnon, superintendent of the Anglo-American Hospital in Havana, Cuba. Clippings discuss MacKinnon's career in South American and the Carribean, hospital organization and care, and Anglo-American society in Havana. Ephemera includes thank you notes from former patients and colleagues, event invitations from ambassadors and political figures, and material from her work with the Red Cross.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244131"
               id="aspace_66e85645010f931e0cbe091ccf9375fb"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Microscopic studies</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1910" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1910">1910</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_63cd9fe58f207c1f03db18a571b5617e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 6.25 x 7.5 inches; 26 prints, adhered to album pages. Maroon fabric cover with black leather corners and spine, leaves are off-white board. Includes microscopic views of human tissue.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_18538cc7de8ebfc0ec314295ef137884"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244149"
               id="aspace_77c7e62fd7e535db685b15c1a5781982"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Missouri State Sanatorium at Mount Vernon Mo.</part>
                     </title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0d0610e33aa5a51c8dbb9caa884220d6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 5.75 x 8.25 inches; 85 photographic prints, multiple dimensions. Black cloth cover with title written in gold ink and double barred cross in red ink; black paper leaves. Sticker inside back cover reads "The IDEAL, to duplicate order No. 2305B, Made by the J.L. Hanson Co., Chicago." Photographs of Missouri State Sanatorium at Mount Vernon, Missouri. Includes grounds, building exteriors, dining hall, wards, patients, nurses, and doctors.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244147"
               id="aspace_914629b06d8d09ff8f5d9a186e7f7587"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>National Drug Company Biologicals and Pharmaceuticals, Philadelphia, U.S.A.</part>
                     </title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1933" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1933">1933</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_b251532d2de3fd049f2787cd0874fd84">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10.25 x 13.75 inches; 21 large photographic prints. Leather cover. Each photograph preceded by description printed on a translucent page. Album documents production of tetanus and smallpox vaccines at Swiftwater Antitoxin and Vaccine Laboratories of the National Drug Company in the Pocono Mountains, pennsylvania. Includes photographs of facility exteriors, stables and animal pens, sterilizing room, laboratories, storage of "biologicals", collection of sera by vacuum, and purification process.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_b407f87d901b42e8efa9d9d330ddc892"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3252791"
               id="aspace_d2987a2d7f9414e903f2748c6156cd71"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nurses' album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1890" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1890">1890</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6859fadae729de6f86b53651121f0b0d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimension: 6.5 x 9 inches; 17 photographic prints, multiple sizes. 4 black paper leaves from a photograph album. Includes photographs of nurses in uniform performing work, interior and exterior shots of nurses posing in groups, and 4 photographs of women not in uniform.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244132"
               id="aspace_d925163cce483677b0a32d0e20e892d6"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nurse's album, Jewish Hospital, Philadelphia</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1917–1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1917">1917</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1920">1920</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_afef2674a90a8444a4c743c7dc3779d0">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.25 x 10.25 inches; 161 photographic prints, photographs are glued to album pages. Brown cloth cover, black paper leaves. Album created by a nurse who worked at the Jewish Hospital in Philadelphia and other institutions. Photographs include nurses, patients, doctors, hospital building exteriors and grounds, World War I soldiers, vacations and family.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_be196d6d877a72dc13bd445f44e3db0d"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244133"
               id="aspace_a76bd4b357346ae2db311ebe5b6b88fc"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Nurse's album, Memorial Hospital, New York City</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1900-1910"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1910">1910</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_12384d183430552d948f0e26a9188fe1">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.75 x 5.5 inches; 102 photographic prints, multiple format, including cyanotype (photographs). Red leather cover with black paper leaves, front cover missing. Contains photographs from multiple states in the U.S.A. and Japan. Includes all female surgical scene and nurses attending patients at Memorial Hospital [for Women and Children], Brooklyn New York; vacations; family scenes; and homes. Photographs cut into various shapes, arranged, some are individually labeled.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244150"
               id="aspace_191a5e6a27baeb04c236b5b9be749ac4"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pediatric Argentine Hospital album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940-1949"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1949">1949</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_d3dcd7e0dcdacf857589fc52bd9cee69">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.75 x 12.5 inches; 49 photographic prints. Grey paper cover; 20 off-white paper leaves with irregular faux parchment edges, printed gray border, inscribed "Marilu" in blue pencil at bottom of page. 2 or 3 photographs are adhered to each page. Back of photos stamped "Photo Marilu. Cabildo 1708 - U. T. 73-8291" and have control numbers written in pencil. Album contains images of patient examinations with pediatricians and nurse.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244166"
               id="aspace_1fc9e1b39be06f6fdd8d9f5c8e6640f0"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pfahler, George E., M.D., Old Blockley Hospital album, Philadelphia</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1900–1901" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1901">1901</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ae4eaa00bbadfff28f3df28642b9ff9d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 5.75 x 7.5 inches; 26 photographic prints, 4.75  x 3.75 inches. Gray fabric covered paper covers with "photographs" printed in gilt on front; leaves are off white paper. Album created by George E. Pfahler M.D., a physician from Philadelphia. Each page contains 1 photograph with caption. Photographs include hospital staff, wards, events, and doctors and nurses socializing. Includes image of operating room and new ambulance.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244169"
               id="aspace_94df09f43b52e6e67a0a35d91b6e8ca5"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pharmaceutical institute student album, Sweden</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920-1930"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1930">1930</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="swe">Swedish</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9238b80e69f968106166cebcdf64ee56">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.5 x 10.75 inches; 59 photographic prints, multiple sizes, bulk 4.25 x 2.5 inches and part of student identity card. Black patterned paper cover with 2 raised geometric decorations on front cover; heavy dark gray paper leaves. Album created by female student of Swedish Farmaceutska Institute. Images depict students and instructors with microscopes, in laboratories and classrooms, posed in groups, and photographs of individual female students in laboratories. Also includes personal images of home and family.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244134"
               id="aspace_3b82197134f4d4a6b63c01064583466d"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Plastic surgery case studies, New Jersey</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1930–1940" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1940">1940</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c4838525cc7b4b62a9b5449d013e5590">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 14.5 x 17 inches; 541 photographic prints, multiple sizes, bulk 3.25 x 4.25 inches. Photographs are adhered to black paper leaves. Plastic surgeon case study records. List of patients taped to the front page of the book; photographs chronicle the patients' progress over time.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_ffb927c819a3f4bcf507b1604bfcda31"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244163"
               id="aspace_4fa54d75841b46adbc400188895df8a4"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Pneumonic plague, China</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1911" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1911">1911</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0247da2a139b00934c4c612ee9ff0d25">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.75 x 10.25 inches; 134 photographic prints, 4 x 6 and 3.5 x 5.5 inches. Photographs are in vinyl 3 ring binder with photograph sleeves. Some photographs include handwritten descriptive notes on reverse. Album documents pneumonic plague in Fu Chia Dieu, China. Photographs include doctors, hospital buildings, mass graves, and buildings burning. Also includes photograph of Dr. Paul Hoffkine at the Plague Hospital.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244167"
               id="aspace_2aaee175c4354c67a0bbb029a6ddc2b6"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Precision X-ray equipment</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1930-1939"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1939">1939</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_9dfdaabf061544c3352b5ccee4e1af48">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 4.25 x 6 inches; 46 photographic prints. Black leather album cover with a logo that reads "Precision" on the front; leaves are photographs adhered to canvas, album secured by 2 brass screws. Contains 13 images of machines and 33 images of hospitals, including photographs of several x-ray machines in use by physicians, and list of hospitals using the machines.</p>
               </scopecontent>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_580e138ec82d930b809ed4595af24ef7"
                               localtype="ColdStorageBrbl">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This item is restricted pending preservation treatment.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244153"
               id="aspace_4e0acaf0b44af2a7443adb2c0ee14786"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Red Cross Blood Drive album, World War II</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1941-1945"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1941">1941</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1945">1945</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ac8bcc505600ab0856b1a93b6b6b4847">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 14.5 x 12.25 inches; 19 gelatin silver prints, newspaper clippings, Red Cross publications, reports, and letter. Red cover, 26 off white paper leaves. Scrapbook from World War II Red Cross nurses collecting blood in the United States for the war effort abroad. Scrapbook created by Red Cross nurse Betty Weatherington. Inscription on first page reads "Red Cross Blood Drive Center, 925 S. Western Ave, Los Angeles, Calif." Photographs include nurse portraits and nurses collecting blood. Red Cross material includes "What Can I Do - The Citizen's Handbook for War." Photographs are captioned in red ink.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244136"
               id="aspace_5be6c67c0a69ac76309934c2621c1d89"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Royhan, W. H., Ambulance Company 331, World War I</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1914-1918"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bf1961af234b9837c3a8b03775cbd8ca">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 10.1 x 6.9 inches; 92 gelatin silver prints, multiple sizes, one 7 x 9 inch print. Also includes a poem, 1 mark bill, diagram of an ambulance, and amusement company program. Embossed leather-like cover, 29 black paper leaves. Personal photograph album of Mr. W.H. Royhan from Akron, Ohio, who served as a soldier in World War I. Photographs include formal portraits, images from the field, groups of soldiers, ambulances, parades, boat trips, funerals, and war hospitals. Back of the album has a large format formal portrait of a soldier, presumably W. H. Royan, taken in 1919 in Ashtabula, Ohio.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244177"
               id="aspace_d2e06d87cf6d010e38eb94125c76b347"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Russian medical school album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1904" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1904">1904</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bf07d18c4e2ebc6ab4b11fe03dbdf465">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 14 x 17.25 inches; 16 photographic prints. Fabric covered board cover, 16 unbound leaves of heavy board secured in 4 flap enclosure. Each leaf has one large photographic print adhered, enclosed by printed border. Prints depict assembled photocollages (photographic compositions) of 20-24 photographs, including portraits of medical specialists, images of wards, operations, and classrooms.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244176"
               id="aspace_4b1c2fdf43f262fcb0f0541799e40926"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Russian medical school album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1920">1920</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_c2892b4c7e9c594519f5f7addd64be96">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7 x 9.25 inches; 300 photographic prints, various  sizes. 22 unbound pages. Each page contains a printed collage of portraits and images, including hospital exteriors, surgical scenes, dissection hall, laboratories, and patient treatment.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244148"
               id="aspace_817cc5b009e357c3cd0065f1c13afb08"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stickney, Dr. E. P., Arlington Hospital album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1913-1920"
                                      label="creation"
                                      unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1913">1913</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1920">1920</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_fc5a2adfca7558c9255981844274001b">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.25 x 10.25 inches; 17 photographic prints. Black cloth covered album, 25 black paper leaves. "Dr. E. P. Stickney" embossed in gold on front cover, sticker inside back cover: "Devine &amp; Parsons, Commercial Photographers, P. O. Box 62, Station A, 830 Washington St., Boston, Mass." One photograph affixed to each page with caption in gold ink below. Photographs of Arlington Hospital exteriors and interior spaces, nurses, patients in wards, and operating room during surgical procedure.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244164"
               id="aspace_984cfc31ecee8aae2119caa329888ab1"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stusick, Stanley S., Springfield Hospital physician album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1924–1931" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1924">1924</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1931">1931</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2dcb9fa0231c86b4aff7d77ca6c50b1a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7.5 x 11.5 inches; 171 items: gelatin silver prints, newspaper clippings, and ephemera. Paper cover, 48 black paper leaves, secured by string. Personal album of physician Stanley S. Stusick, covers a wide variety of activities, including surgical scenes and medical staff at Springfield Hospital, nurses at a Providence, Rhode Island maternity ward, and personal vacations. Many photographs in the album are captioned with dates and locations.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244168"
               id="aspace_61e461d9bd6397dc86992a2a237cfd02"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Sweetland Apparatus medical equipment</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1935" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1935">1935</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e2e3b4ce3828ac304cb767ee62bd1e8d">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 5.75 x 9 inches; 21 photographic prints. Brown leather cover; photographs are adhered to paper or fabric leaves, 1 photograph on front of each leaf; secured with leather string. Sweetland apparatus advertisement, designed by Ernest J. Sweetland, from San Francisco California. Includes images demonstrating the apparatus for drying plaster casts, relieving shock, and warming beds. Some pages have handwritten descriptions on the reverse.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244139"
               id="aspace_78ed4ba9a5bde61d110a8a3b9268a72f"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ukraine medical school album</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1940" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_55f4d3857a7b831517ab552e55fa3a96">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 7 x 9.25 inches, unbound; 17 gelatin silver prints. 16 photographic prints of page layouts with portraits, 1 non-composite image. Loose pages from a yearbook-like album for a Ukranian medical school. Each page contains portraits of professors and students, as well as one "scene" from school. Also includes one full page portrait. Students are male and female. Some of the pages have holes where photographs were cut out.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244160"
               id="aspace_09c17fccaef5f2d484973d341e463854"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>U. S. Army Allerey Hospital Center, World War I, France</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1914–1918" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1914">1914</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1918">1918</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_7f8167a95cbd2a0fd8aefd930336f59c">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Photographic prints removed from an album; 64 photographic prints, multiple sizes, from 2.25 x 3.25 inches to 4.75 x 6.75 inches. Notable images include the camp hospital, Red Cross stations, sterilizing rooms, and holiday meals with the staff.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244175"
               id="aspace_afcbce4b882c1a58e263acf7844ec6c9"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>U.S. Army Base Hospital, Camp Mills, Mineola, New York, World War I</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1918–1919" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1918">1918</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1919">1919</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_90f00bb77fc87b3111b378c7239da926">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 5.5 x 8 inches; 25 photographic prints, 2 x 3.5 inches and 5 x 7 inches. Unbound black paper album leaves, photographs adhered to pages. Includes photographs of nurses and doctors, mess hall, camp, kitchen, and hospital of Camp Mills military base in Mineola, New York.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244138"
               id="aspace_44fb2a32019038e61f36754d4dee112f"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title>
                        <part>Université de Bordeaux</part>
                     </title>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1895" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1895">1895</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_025567fff898286d1e2f7eb513400e9a">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 13 x 14.5 inches; 12 photographic prints, 7 x 9 inches. Title on cover: "Université de Bordeaux." Leaves are off white board, photographs are mounted and matted, with captions below. Reverse of each photograph stamped "Université de Bordeaux, faculté de Médecine &amp; de Pharmacie." Photographs show building exteriors and interiors, including dissection hall, laboratory, and museum.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3244165"
               id="aspace_0eeecbd05e6b020fab6941b5d5ce0228"
               level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Walter Reed Maxillo-Facial Surgery Department World War I soldier case files</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured altrender="1919–1920" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1919">1919</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1920">1920</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_6d4ccb0db3ed704e9c35687e78724ba7">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Album dimensions: 11.75 x 10.25 inches; 107 photographic prints, multiple sizes, 5 x 7 inches and smaller. Modern 3 ring vinyl binder with photograph sleeves. Photographer: Alice L. Becht. Photographs of World War I soldiers who were treated by the Maxillo-Facial Department of Walter Reed United States  Army Hospital. Images include the patients before and after reconstructive surgery and the facial and dental implants that were used. Album includes list of patients. Reverse of photographs includes patient name written in pencil and stamp:"Maxillo-facial Dep't, Walter Reed Gen. Hospital, U.S. Army, Photo A. L. Becht."</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3243789"
            id="aspace_4a4e097bec11b7d5f08afd2a3813439f"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Albums des internat</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series VIII</unitid>
            </did>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250675"
               id="aspace_f4d03a117865cd84314368e3a826fb09"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Offert par la Societe des Eaux Minerales de Pougues et de Carabana</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1903">1903</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1904">1904</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250676"
               id="aspace_daeefe6d298b9a8a1e75b4bce4706055"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Offert par la Societe des Eaux Minerales de Pougues et de Carabana</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1904">1904</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1905">1905</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250677"
               id="aspace_4489eecc2eb291103a65784587f0ddf1"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1905">1905</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1906">1906</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250678"
               id="aspace_6be041c2e42e0549fa520c846ba049d7"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Offert par la Societe des Eaux Minerales de Pougues et de Carabana</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1906">1906</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1907">1907</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250679"
               id="aspace_fe293496aadece605975d93420db2e93"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Offert par la Societe des Eaux Minerales de Vittel</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1923">1923</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250680"
               id="aspace_1a117ad4eabf64a22b99a312c4ff2bb4"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Offert par le Laboratoire des Produits Seientia (Tricalcine) et pa la Cie des Eaux de Pougues et de Carabana</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1924">1924</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250681"
               id="aspace_5572ec3a473cfe42577a61ae39fe94d5"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1926">1926</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250682"
               id="aspace_b79485b683afb59ba35ef062545dc346"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1927">1927</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250683"
               id="aspace_adf9394c5e307b1dfab4d9b21759f526"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1928">1928</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250684"
               id="aspace_abbb7cb5a8bcda80c567f1b6b064399d"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1929">1929</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250685"
               id="aspace_2446fb1b7d4179d58d3861732a97e02d"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250686"
               id="aspace_f4a1c8e3ad826c1baa2a4ff79eb8e352"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Offert par le Laboratoire des Produits Scientia Tricalcine-Peptalmine Calcoleol et Par La Compagnie des Eaux de Pogues et De Carabana</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1930">1930</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1931">1931</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c altrender="/repositories/10/archival_objects/3250687"
               id="aspace_8803f6f821390cd35c07e6397b4da97d"
               level="item">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Album de l'Internat Laboratorie des produits Scientia Tricalcine - Peptalmine - Globexine - PolyCalcion - Pancrepar - Iodocitrane - Compagnie des Eaux - Minerales de Pougues Laboratoire Mariani</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured label="other" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1945">1945</fromdate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <langmaterial>
                     <language langcode="fre">French</language>
                  </langmaterial>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
