<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YaleArchivesSpace/EAD3-to-PDF-UA/master/ead3-yale.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="https://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.2131">mssa.ms.2131</recordid>
      <otherrecordid localtype="BIB">17513338</otherrecordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Edward V. Knight Papers </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Knight (Edward V.) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>Alison Fulmer</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="telephone">(203) 432-1735</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="fax">(203) 432-7441</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                       linktitle="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                       show="new">http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>November 2024</date>
            <num>MS 2131</num>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <controlnote>
               <p>This finding aid, which is compliant with the Yale EAD Best Practice Guidelines, Version 1.0., has a MARC record in Yale's ILS with the following bib number: <num localtype="Orbis-bib">17513338</num>.</p>
            </controlnote>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency>
         <agencycode>US-CtY</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Manuscripts and Archives</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>Finding aid description and metadata in Archives at Yale are licensed under a CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication. This means that anyone may copy, modify, and distribute this descriptive metadata without restriction or permission. The CC0 license is explained in full on the Creative Commons website: <ref href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication</ref>. More information is available on our <ref href="https://archives.yale.edu/help">Help page</ref>.</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>completed</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2024-12-04T03:48:31-05:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace yale-rebased-v3.3.1</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Wednesday December  4, 2024 at 03:48</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc altrender="/repositories/12/resources/12833" level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Edward V. Knight papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 2131</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Manuscripts and Archives</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>2.8</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(7 boxes)</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1931">1931</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="2002">2002</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="bulk">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1931">1931</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1945">1945</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_d2bfc653407f73d2bfd3f3808f77bc00">This collection contains the correspondence, photographs, and personal papers of Edward Vinton Knight, Yale 1931. Of note is Knight's correspondence to his family dating from 1931-1933 when he worked in Changsha, China teaching English with the Yale-in-China Association (now the Yale-China Association). Correspondence also includes communications about Japan's hostile activities during the invasion of Manchuria in the early 1930s and later during the Second Sino-Japanese War. There is a significant amount of correspondence dating from 1937-1945 from Knight to his fiancée and later wife, Lois Hathaway Upton. Photographic materials include black and white prints of Knight and his Yale-in-China colleagues and students as well as images of the landscape, architecture, and people in China. Personal papers include Knight's miscellaneous print and manuscript materials.</abstract>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname source="local">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Knight, Edward V.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_8136340dfeaec01befc999e8ee38ab10">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_370176147665492f4b68a8885fc7ec12">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Sylvia Knight and David H. Knight, 2022.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_b498f1a2b367f08512225d3dc5a680df">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>This collection is arranged in three series: I. Correspondence, 1931-1988; II. Photographs, 1931-1951, undated; III. Personal papers, 1931-2002.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_398835d4f3bb75304af7399099d69cbc">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Edward Vinton Knight (1910-2004) was born in New Haven, Connecticut on April 4, 1910 to parents Reverend Franklin Knight and Gertrude Mosher Knight. Knight graduated from Holyoke High School in 1927 and graduated from Yale University in 1931. Knight spent two years in Changsha, China (Summer 1931-Summer 1933) teaching English with the Yale-in-China Association. Knight moved to Salem, Massachusetts and married Lois Hathaway Upton on June 23, 1939. Knight later taught English and Latin at the Darrow School in New Lebanon, New York. He also worked as a technical writer and later a marketing specialist for General Electric in Pittsfield, Massachusetts. Knight retired in 1975, moving to Lenox, Massachusetts and finally to Richmond, Virginia, where he died on November 13, 2004.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_fdae7f1655506845237cfc05a9043cb5">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Edward V. Knight Papers. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_d290ee2f5d34fca6fb188334fdbf9062">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected. The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>All folder titles have been transcribed or derived from existing folder titles or material descriptions. These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards. For more information, please refer to the Beinecke Archival Description Unit Processing Manual.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_caae4559ce065d3a718ad541a0f2b77a">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>This collection contains the correspondence, photographs, and personal papers of Edward Vinton Knight, Yale 1931. Of note is Knight's correspondence to his family dating from 1931-1933 when he worked in Changsha, China teaching English at the Yali Union Middle School, a boys' preparatory school, with the Yale-in-China Association (now the Yale-China Association). There is correspondence from Association administrators to Knight's family regarding his travels and his bout with typhoid. Administrators also communicated about Japan's hostile activities during the invasion of Manchuria in the early 1930s and later during the Second Sino-Japanese War. Correspondence also includes a description of Knight's travels on the Trans-Siberian Railroad to Europe.</p>
         <p>There is a significant amount of correspondence dating from 1937-1945 from Knight to his fiancée and later wife, Lois Hathaway Upton. Correspondence dating from 1937-1939 pertains to the period before Edward and Lois were married when Edward lived in Salem, Massachusetts while recovering from appendicitis and in Boston where he volunteered at Hale House and searched for work. Lois attended nursing school in Salem and Boston, graduating in November 1938. Correspondence from 1944-1945 pertains to the period when Lois and their daughter Sylvia lived with Lois's family in Salem during a difficult pregnancy with their second child, David. At the time, Edward remained in Pittsfield, Massachusetts where he worked with General Electric. Letters between the couple include information about their personal lives, relationship, and work.</p>
         <p>Photographic materials include black and white prints of Knight and his Yale-in-China colleagues and students as well as images of the landscape, architecture, and people in China. Personal papers include material relating to Knight's travels, the Yale-in-China Association, and his miscellaneous print and manuscript materials.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_a513d46145f298f6c670c30bbcb78f73">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright and other associated proprietary rights for unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by Edward V. Knight was transferred to Yale University in 2022. These materials may be used for non-commercial purposes without seeking permission from Yale University as the copyright holder. For other uses of these materials, please contact mssa.assist@yale.edu.com. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user. </p>
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="local">
            <part localtype="topical">Schools, American</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">China</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nr2004004912"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">Changsha Shi (China)</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85024006"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">China</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Description and travel</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="sh2008114679" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">China</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Foreign relations</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">Japan</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026877" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Correspondence </part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Photographs</part>
         </genreform>
         <persname source="local">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Knight, Lois H.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname rules="aacr">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Weigle, Richard Daniel, 1912-</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname>
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Yale-in-China Association</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
