<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YaleArchivesSpace/EAD3-to-PDF-UA/master/ead3-yale.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="https://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ru.1196">mssa.ru.1196</recordid>
      <otherrecordid localtype="BIB">17636972</otherrecordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Records of the Yale Swimming and Diving Association  </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Records of the Yale Swimming and Diving Association </titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Michael Lotstein </author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="telephone">(203) 432-1735</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="fax">(203) 432-7441</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                       linktitle="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                       show="new">http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>February 2025</date>
            <num>RU 1196</num>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <controlnote>
               <p>This encoded finding aid is compliant with the Yale EAD Best Practice Guidelines, Version 1.0.</p>
            </controlnote>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency>
         <agencycode>US-CtY</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Manuscripts and Archives</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>Finding aid description and metadata in Archives at Yale are licensed under a CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication. This means that anyone may copy, modify, and distribute this descriptive metadata without restriction or permission. The CC0 license is explained in full on the Creative Commons website: <ref href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication</ref>. More information is available on our <ref href="https://archives.yale.edu/help">Help page</ref>.</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>in_progress</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2025-03-22T03:01:05-04:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace yale-rebased-v3.3.1</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Saturday March 22, 2025 at 03:01</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc altrender="/repositories/12/resources/13744" level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Records of the Yale Swimming and Diving Association</unittitle>
         <unitid>RU 1196</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Manuscripts and Archives</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <languageset>
               <language langcode="eng">English</language>
               <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
            </languageset>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>9</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <unitdatestructured altrender="1944-2002" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1944">1944</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="2002">2002</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_4a2d7faac87ef163b9f5f98166610e48">The records consist of correspondence, publications and printed materials, reports, photographs, and ephemera documenting the endeavors of the Yale Swimming Association. The bulk of the records come from Hamilton Milroy and John Lapides (who inherited Milroy's records). 

The records fall into two main arrangements for the textual records; they are chronologically arranged correspondence of the officers, and alphabetically arranged subject files. There is also a section of photographs and videotapes.
In addition to the records of the YSA, there are also runs of publications and printed materials from the Yale Athletics Dept., and other athletic organizations regarding collegiate level swimming.</abstract>
      </did>
      <odd id="aspace_77469e3b3b56204f913459ff5abcd0d8">
         <head>General</head>
         <p>Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.</p>
      </odd>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_04a633c7bf3f5738d0113a40507c7bc2">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting swimming (RU 941).</p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_cded6a7d55891a1ef7e028167eadf69d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_9243b331ce1b14250db7a09838873d43">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Records of the Yale Swimming and Diving Association (RU 1196). Manuscripts and Archives. Yale University Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <arrangement id="aspace_9e166da986436649fa6fdefb4b9caa90">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>The collection consists of Officers' correspondence; alphabetical subject files; photographs and other audio-visual materials; ephemera.</p>
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_997e916f7de390c4b917063700e968dc">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>The Yale Swimming Association (YSA), an association comprised of Yale swimming alumni and friends to support the swim team became formally established in 1952 with the creation of its articles of association. The Board of Directors, comprised of more than 60 Yale swimming alumni, first met on 8 March 1952 in the Ray Tompkins House. Among those who were elected to the Board of Directors for a five-year term were Richard Baribault '49, Dr. David H. Clement '31, Russell Duncan '40S, Alan Ford '45, Howard Johnson '42, DeLaney Kiphuth '41, Gus Langner '31S, John Macionis '38, Everett MacLeman '42, Phillip Pillsbury '24, C. Dudley Pratt '22, Raymond Reid '51, and Allen Stack '48. Yale's coaches Harry Burke, Oscar Kiphuth, Robert J.H. Kiphuth (head coach), and Philip Moriarty attended the meeting. The YSA then elected Edward Hetzler as president, Howard Johnson as vice-president, and Russell Duncan as secretary-treasurer.  Hetzler lived in NYC.</p>
         <p>The first group of officers passed two resolutions at the outset: 1. Dues were set at $3 per annum per member; and, 2. they established an executive committee consisting of the officers and any other additional members, appointed solely by the president, to act as an interim governing body. Shortly afterwards, a bank account was set up with the Bankers Trust Co. in New York City.Membership chiefly consisted of alumni who swam for Yale, but also included, and continues to include members of the Yale community and New Haven CT who have a strong interest in Yale's swimming programs.</p>
         <p>In 1948, Howie Johnson '41 chaired the YSA"s 50th anniversary celebration at the Quinnipiac Club in New Haven.  Howie, captain of the NCAA Championship team.  He tied the world record for the 100 yd freestyle of 51.0 s set by Johnny Weissmeuller. David Clement's term, 1958-1969, established the YSA as an influential alumni organization. He called upon the captains and coaches of the swim team to participate in the association's activities and meetings; thus incorporating present and past members of the swim team into a single entity to promote Yale's world-class swimming program. Clement also sought to celebrate Coach Robert J. H. Kiphuth. In 1959, on behalf of the YSA, he presented Kiphuth with George Bellow's lithograph Stag at Sharkeys; in 1962 he commissioned Deane Keller, Yale's premier portrait painter at the time, to paint an historical portrait of the coach; and, in 1967, after Kiphuth's death, he petitioned for the exhibition pool to be named in his honor.</p>
         <p>During the presidential terms of Munson, Koletsky, and Milroy, (1970-1982) the YSA subsisted as a mostly reactive organization, accomplishing little except for the collection of dues to fund standing annual events. Enthusiasm and membership ebbed at this time. The 1973 treasurer's report revealed a lack of funds needed to support the Yale swimming program adequately; this resulted in raising the dues to $8 annually. A dearth of records during this era confirms the lack of interest in maintaining the YSA as an influential voice on Yale swimming. These 12 quiet years saw did pay attention to documenting the YSA's financial standing. 1970 saw the introduction of finances and budgets as an integral part of meetings, and the beginning of a formal treasurer's report the following year. During that year, David Clement reported on the YSA's new Kiphuth Memorial Fund. (It is interesting to note that the drop in membership and lack of interest in the YSA parallels the first slump of the renowned Yale swim team.)</p>
         <p>In the summer of 1981, John Lapides breathed fresh air into the organization. Lapides' first years (He became president in 1982) resurrected enthusiasm for the YSA and Yale's swimming program. Lapides simultaneously injected a professional business approach into the association's structure not seen since Clement's term. Lapides quickly brought into being a steering committee and a more clearly defined organizational structure. Through the development and implementation of a steering committee, he asserted objectives, strategies and tactics, and formulated a disbursements budget. These initial restructuring meetings led to the creation of other committees to carry out the steering committee's objectives. These standing committees covered the areas of membership, Y newsletter, entertainment, and history.</p>
         <p>Lapides also pressed for the consideration of an institutional archives to preserve the records and images of YSA and Yale swimming, publication of two issues of the newsletter annually, and the setting up of a high interest money market account for funds. With a new structure in place in 1983, Lapides and Milroy met with Charles Pagnum, associate director of Athletics, and set the association's budget at $17,000. YSA also voted to support the fledgling Federation of Yale Athletics, establish an archives, fund the swim team's Christmas trip, and hired a secretary. Later that year, Milroy relinquished his 13 year tenure as a YSA officer. The remainder of the decade saw the YSA become an established and respected voice at Yale. Student swimmers, Andrew Lipsher '88 and Robert C. Hazlett III '87, petitioned for another restructuring of the association in light of the water polo team's incorporation into the YSA. The YSA called on Lainie Lipsher's (mother of Andrew) fundraising expertise which significantly reversed a $10,000+ projected deficit in 1987 to a budget over $28,000 in the black with a an additional $13,000 from fundraising.</p>
         <p>Deft business skills allowed Lapides to become quickly a strong voice for Yale swimming. Lapides used these skills to request of Yale's President Levin to elevate the priority for the renovation of the Payne Whitney Gymnasium in the 1990s, especially concerning the decayed and obsolescent Kiphuth Exhibition Pool, once one of the world's greatest competition swimming pools. Howard Johnson, Moriarty, and Everett MacLeman led efforts in this area that included fundraising, studies and proposals, and negotiations with Yale officials.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_e5e8641cd21583547462dacbc660b03e">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Records donated by: John S. Lapides, 2001, 2002; Hamilton Milroy, 1983; and, Philip Moriarty, 1998?</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4d010c763d64f09202f049cb7c521e9d">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The records of the Yale Swimming Association included in this record group (approx. 15 ft of records, photographs, audio-video recordings, and ephemera) consist of correspondence, minutes, publications and printed materials, reports, photographs, and ephemera extensively documenting the endeavors of the Yale Swimming Association, especially during the tenures of David C. Clement  MD (1958-1969) and John S. Lapides (1982- ). The bulk of the records come from Hamilton Milroy, who served as the secretary-treasurer during the 1970s and early 1980s, and Lapides, who inherited Milroy's records when he succeeded him as president.</p>
         <p>The records fall into two main arrangements for the text-based records; the first series is chiefly arranged by officer or governing body, and then chronologically. The second series is arranged alphabetically by subject. There are also discreet series for photographs and audio and video recordings. Starting with Lapides' memo dated 8 June 1981 (box 1, f. 6) calling for a revived "interest in the Yale Swimming Association," YSA's records became a natural output of a well-run organization's innate need to document itself for accountability, and for historical reasons. Records created during this era show a marked change in the administration of the YSA and in its record-keeping practices. The organization of and content found in Lapides' records are more akin to business records; they thoroughly trace the progress of the organization's goals as administered by the officers and committees. His 20-year-long term as president has only added to the stability of the organization and its record-keeping practices, resulting in a steady documentation of the YSA. Records pre-Lapides could be described as "club" records – an informal set of files that unevenly document its activities and efforts.
The records of the governing bodies (board of directors, steering committee, membership committee – box 1, f. 1-16) consist of minutes, agendas, lists, and notes, beginning with the 1952 articles of association. Of special note are the documents on the roles of the officers and a description of the structure of the organization (box 1, f. 2). While the board of directors' records carefully cover YSA's first two decades, and the steering committee's records back to 1981, there is nothing during 1974-1980 nor after 1989. Lapides records as president fills the gap post-1989, but 1974-1980 remains a dark spot with only fragments of information found in Milroy's records as secretary-treasurer.</p>
         <p>The officers' correspondence consists of letters, memoranda, notes, and appeals documenting the role of each officer. The secretary-treasurer's records are chiefly concerned with financial matters, and the president's records are chiefly concerned with executive management and outreach/marketing. While most of the secretary-treasurer's records consist of routine letters and notes, it is interesting to not the slow change in handling transactions from the YSA's early informal years to the more recent calculated and business-like approach. 
Early presidential correspondence, especially from Clement's term illustrates the YSA's efforts to establish itself as a viable and successful alumni support organization dedicated to fostering and promoting Yale's world-class swimming program. This can also be seen in Clement's letters instituting the formalization meetings and minutes, and in strengthening ties with the Athletic Dept. by honoring and celebrating major contributors to the swimming program.</p>
         <p>Records of the president during the 1970-1981 shed very little light on the YSA. The office (and with it the organizations as a whole) switched from being pro-active and influential with Yale's administration to reactive, existing at a minimal level. Correspondence from Munson, Koletsky, and Milroy, filling just two slim folders, is very telling in its limited documentation on such topics as the administration of Yale's Athletic Dept. and the swimming program. To its credit, the office did begin to examine seriously efforts to renovate and expand the Kiphuth Exhibition Pool. Not until Lapides' nomination in 1982 do the president's records again become highly illustrative of the YSA's leadership and its natural relationship with the larger Yale community.</p>
         <p>Outside of the officers' correspondence was a mass of files with no apparent order consisting of newspaper clippings, flyers, brochures, printed matter, reports, newsletters, photographs, videotapes, a sculpture, and so on. From this developed an alphabetic arrangement of the files by subject. Subjects with substantial documentation include: expansion/renovation of the exhibition pool, finances, the newsletter, swimmers, Yale University Athletics, and the swimming program.</p>
         <p>The financial records chiefly consist of budget files arranged by fiscal year. Donor records are found within the budget files (usually in the 1980s) as well as with the financial reports at the beginning of the series. Financial and budget correspondence may also be found in the correspondence files of the secretary-treasurer and the president.
Records on the exhibition pool include proposals from design and engineering firms, development, and negotiations with Yale's administration. Some of these records may be closely related to records concerning the renovation of the Payne Whitney Gymnasium.</p>
         <p>To accommodate the various clippings sporadic correspondence, and obituaries, the section titled "Swimmers" was established. The records are less archival and more informational, generally giving basic biographical data or highlighting a singular achievement of a Yale swimmer. In addition to the records of the YSA, there are also runs of publications and printed materials from the Yale Athletics Dept., the Ivy Group, Connecticut Swimming Committee, and other related institutions.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <odd id="aspace_d6048c22ab499bbc0a341a0e2a2ae65a">
         <head>General</head>
         <p>Officers of the YSA, 1952-2001</p>
         <p>Presidents
1952-1957	Edward T. Hetzler '23
1958-1969	David H. Clement '31, MD
1970-1978	Larom B. Munson '51
1979-1981	Joseph Koletsky '59
1981-1982	Hamilton Milroy '53
1982-2011	John Lapides '72</p>
         <p>Vice Presidents
1952-1957	Howard R. Johnson '42S
1958-1967	Raymond M. Reid '51
1967-1969	Larom B. Munson '51
1970-1979	Howard R. Johnson '42S
1979-1981	Roger Goettsche '65</p>
         <p>Secretary-Treasurers
1952-1958	Russell Duncan '40S
1958-1969	William F. Sanford '28
1970-1981	Hamilton Milroy '53 (1979-1981 treasurer)
1979-1981	Phil Prince '52 (secretary)
1982-1985	Hamilton Milroy '53</p>
      </odd>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh86000158"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">College athletes</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85131207"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Swimming</part>
         </subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c altrender="/repositories/12/archival_objects/3192663"
            id="aspace_744d0af0c7a732ee88e4c56fc659b45e"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Newsletters</unittitle>
               <unitid>Accession 2020-A-0047</unitid>
               <unitdatestructured altrender="1953-2012" label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <daterange>
                     <fromdate standarddate="1953">1953</fromdate>
                     <todate standarddate="2012">2012</todate>
                  </daterange>
               </unitdatestructured>
            </did>
         </c>
         <c altrender="/repositories/12/archival_objects/3931030"
            id="aspace_fcd20d4191a7801179c29210c155d936"
            level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Records </unittitle>
               <unitid>Accession 2025-A-0030</unitid>
            </did>
            <accessrestrict id="aspace_cae0460242017427430ac0a6f1032023">
               <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
               <p>Open for research.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
