<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/mssa.ms.1247">mssa.ms.1247</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Chengting Thomas Wang Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Wang (Chengting Thomas) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>compiled by Leslie Koch</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Manuscripts and Archives</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>Yale University Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 208240</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8240</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">mssa.assist@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                       linktitle="http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/"
                       show="new">http://www.library.yale.edu/mssa/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>April 1982</date>
            <num>MS 1247</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency>
         <agencycode>US-CtY</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Manuscripts and Archives</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English.</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>finding aid created in accordance with manuscripts and archives' processing manual.</abbr>
         <citation/>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>under_revision</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-12-07T10:15:56+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.4.1.yale.hm.mm</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Friday December  7, 2018 at 10:15</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Chengting Thomas Wang papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>MS 1247</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Manuscripts and Archives</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>0.75</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1950">1950</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1983">1983</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_c98135a88f51785a92477468cf80d648">Manuscript biography of his life with particular emphasis on his career as a prominent official in the Chinese Nationalist government. Also included is a biographical article on Chengting Wang written by Vincent Liu and printed in the Biographical Journal.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="local">
               <part>Wang, Chengting Thomas, 1882-1961</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1bce9050cc5357049796b2ad5e65d5a6">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>Copyright has been transferred to Yale University for unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator(s) of this collection. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_6ca622dcf81c4ce1d572f8aa9bf6ab80">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Chengting Thomas Wang Papers (MS 1247). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_b3bebb9fe8cf6c2204b2236379d6cea5">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Chenting Thomas Wang papers consist of the original manuscript of his autobiography, "Looking Back and Looking Forward," together with electrostatic and typed copies. The memoir largely relates to his career as a prominent official in the Chinese Nationalist government and concludes in the 1950s after the Nationalist government moved to Taiwan. A biographical article on Wang (in Chinese) by Vincent Liu, his son-in-law, and material related to the presentation of the manuscript to the Yale University Library on April 3, 1981 are also included.</p>
         <p>The papers were the gift of Anfu Wang Liu, daughter of Chenting T. Wang.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <bioghist id="aspace_e5a26721f9e66fb3e1734cace126196c">
         <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
         <p>Chengting T. Wang:</p>
         <p>On returning to China from Yale, Wang became secretary of the Young Men's Christian Association in Shanghai. Within a few months, however, he plunged into the turmoil of Chinese politics. He was active in the Revolution of 1911 which overthrew the Empire and helped draft the basic law on which the Republic was tentatively organized. In January 1912, he was elected a member of the Provisional Legislature and was chosen its Deputy Speaker. In February 1913, he was made Vice-Minister of Industry and Commerce and became Acting Minister of the same Board in May. When, in 1913, the first National Assembly of the Republic met in Peking, he was Vice-President Deputy Speaker of the Senate. In the ensuing struggle between the President, Yuan Shih-k'ai, and the majority party of the Assembly, Wang took sides against the President. In consequence, his life was in danger and he was among those unseated by the would-be dictator.</p>
         <p>Then for two years, while out of public office, he found vent for his energies in social service as
national secretary of the Young Men's Christian Association and in lecturing and church work. On
the death of Yuan Shih-k'ai in 1916, the National Assembly dismissed by him reassembled, and
Wang resumed his post of the Deputy Speaker of the Senate. Within about a year, in the vicissitudes
of Chinese politics, the National Assembly was again dismissed, this time at the instance of a clique
of military leaders in the North who inherited the traditions of Yuan. Thereupon a group of the
Assemblymen, Wang among them, in protest against what they believed a retrograde and
unconstitutional action, formed a government at Canton. In the autumn of 1918 Wang was sent by
this government as its representative to the United States. The following year he was appointed a
member of the official delegation which so ably presented the case of China at the Peace
Conference at Paris. When eventually Japan became willing to withdraw  from Shantung, Wang became (June 1922) China's ranking member of the joint Sino-Japanese commision which drew up the formal agreement. With these achievements as evidence of his ability in diplomacy, he became, in October 1922, Minister of Foreign Affairs and the following December was appointed to act as Premier.</p>
         <p>In the rapid shifts of government in the next four years he was sometimes in office and sometimes out. Always he was striving for a stable regime and for the increase of the prestige of China in international arffairs. During part of the time he handled the delicate and highly important negotiations with Soviet Russia and in March 1924, signed the preliminary agreement with Karakhan. Other posts held during these troubled years were Minister of Justice, member of the Educational Sinking Funds Commission, and chairman of the Customs Conference which prepared the way for the full recovery by China of her control over her own foreign tariff duties.</p>
         <p>In 1927 he became director-general of the Lung-Hai Railway. In 1926 and 1927 the forces of the Kuomintang, of which he had long been a member, were successfully proceeding with the program of the unification of China and were setting up the Nationalist Government at Nanking. In 1926 Wang became Minister of Foreign Affairs and Minister of Finance concurrently and in these positions gave astute and vigorous leadership in the negotiations for a revision of the treaties for the recovery of customs autonomy and the end of extraterritoriality. In the student agitation formented by the enemies of the Government during the Japanese operations in Manchuria in 1931, Wang was attacked by the mob and severely wounded. He resigned his post, but continued as a member of the Central Executive Committee of the Kuomintang and in January, 1932, became state councilor of the Nationalist Government.</p>
         <p>Along with his many political duties, Wang has found time to engage in business. He was the
organizer of an import and export company, was the founder of the Hua Feng Cotton Mill Company
at Woosung, and for a time was its managing director. Since 1926 he has been president, and
beginning with 1932, general manger of the Liu Ho Kou Mining Company, Ltd. He has also taken
an active part in many private or semi-public institutions and organizations of the assistance of
China. He is president of China University (in Peiping) and a member of the board of directors of
St. John's University, Futan University, and Nanking University. He has also been a director of the
China International Famine Relief Commission, a member of the National Flood Relief
Commission, chairman of the finance committee of the United Philanthropic Associations of
Shanghai, a member of the Standing Committee of the China Aviation League, and president of the
China Good Roads Movement Association and the Pan-Pacific Association. He belongs to the
Chinese Episocopal Church.</p>
         <p>He also has found time for the preparation of many articles for Chinese and foreign magazines and
newspapers, and in 1933 some of his addresses of the previous ten years were published (in
Chinese) by the Modern Book Company of Shanghai. Among his honors are an LL.D. From
Peiping University (1917) and from St. John's University (1920), the First Class Tashou Chiaho
decoration (1922), the First Class Tashou Paokuang Chiaho (1922), and the First Class Wenhu
(1923).</p>
         <p>Exerpted from the biography of Chenting T. Wang which appeared in the twenty-fifth year record of the Class of 1910, Yale College.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_c6f9d106eae242bd980adf4c2ff549bb">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The collection is open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85024153"
                   source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>China -- Politics and government</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300080104" source="aat">
            <part>Autobiographies (documents)</part>
         </genreform>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85038202"
                  source="Library of Congress Subject Headings">
            <part>Diplomats</part>
         </subject>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2006034176"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>Liu, Vincent</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>Wang, Chengting Thomas, 1882-1961</part>
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref10" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Inventory</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c id="ref11" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        <part>Looking Back and Looking Forward</part>
                     </title>, manuscript</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref12" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Prologue, pp. 1-28</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_1ee750aaa814dda94726dad147f70201"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4ea4ad308edfefb35ec55dd873962069"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1ee750aaa814dda94726dad147f70201">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref13" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 29-98</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_45c94b1359ff94e2f6476f303d55a937"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_ef58dddac25b6f6624a199d133c0d6a5"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_45c94b1359ff94e2f6476f303d55a937">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref14" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 99-174</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_10e99fe60d4b47313b4baebc0e02781e"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3b7cd86c5446e0f860f0eda7e195365f"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_10e99fe60d4b47313b4baebc0e02781e">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref15" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 175-265</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_72cb90aa3f6717c6765ce8f3ee9215f9"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_666bb885029a1acfab17944823db364b"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_72cb90aa3f6717c6765ce8f3ee9215f9">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref16" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 266-345</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_81ce32ca2bbeb8c38b1e128d6e0b5900"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_aca4170a209cb1d560da3734f2c2bf0a"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_81ce32ca2bbeb8c38b1e128d6e0b5900">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref17" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 346-414</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_2f8eb32a0de9dc348c9f417b0db93609"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_dbe6a8b950429efde695cd63c2852a6f"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_2f8eb32a0de9dc348c9f417b0db93609">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref18" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 415-502</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_dfb320afc5d44732b6e7b7f6947d6bab"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_d44ae5929f932a474879d18dce0747c8"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_dfb320afc5d44732b6e7b7f6947d6bab">7</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref19" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 503-562</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_48ded7f3a598594fa814c45133d5497b"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f55445f1f4b4a8e0ecf19c1b3a7441fa"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_48ded7f3a598594fa814c45133d5497b">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        <part>Looking Back and Looking Forward</part>
                     </title>, electrostatic copy</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref21" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 1-164</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_1fe8786803a5d04ac59c16b7d2b71ba1"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_3e7f49d626c5364abc75ecdcc93fe56a"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1fe8786803a5d04ac59c16b7d2b71ba1">9</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref22" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 165-376</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_520304c612d038fb47f18fd201b805be"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_c156c6db9e886a094216519565938706"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_520304c612d038fb47f18fd201b805be">10</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref23" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>pp. 377-562</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive letter"
                                containerid="39002042368762"
                                id="aspace_862839261890c7b6569b3d58e7bc7989"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_9d42dca39c4a40893f083310a4254aaf"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_862839261890c7b6569b3d58e7bc7989">11</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>
                     <title render="italic">
                        <part>Looking Back and Looking Forward</part>
                     </title>, typescript</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref25" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Chapters 1-12</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive half letter"
                                containerid="39002042368770"
                                id="aspace_66b26c63223fbe3d3ec7b26ad90e246b"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_74c916b7c7d6a67a57d17d2837666181"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_66b26c63223fbe3d3ec7b26ad90e246b">12</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref26" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Chapters 13-25</unittitle>
                     <container altrender="archive half letter"
                                containerid="39002042368770"
                                id="aspace_c54c6c7c0d5f1cb16f1d59ec8dbecf24"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_2793ce30b1da102a5d9110b9afae6cde"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_c54c6c7c0d5f1cb16f1d59ec8dbecf24">13</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Anfu Wang Liu, speech, April 3, 1981, on presentation of <title render="italic">
                        <part>Looking Back and Looking Forward</part>
                     </title> manuscript to Yale University Library; two copies</unittitle>
                  <container altrender="archive half letter"
                             containerid="39002042368770"
                             id="aspace_69e67f9a86a2eae7d7d6b8e149fd1e0e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_256fa5ef1b541fb121e3c095397efd31"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_69e67f9a86a2eae7d7d6b8e149fd1e0e">14</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Chenting T. Wang, <title render="italic">
                        <part>The Biographical Journal</part>
                     </title>, with an article by Vincent Liu (printed; Chinese); two copies</unittitle>
                  <container altrender="archive half letter"
                             containerid="39002042368770"
                             id="aspace_43b80c8f566f54fba261f37f2f3f6513"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1102a8aa544da4ef7364bfbc1450b92d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_43b80c8f566f54fba261f37f2f3f6513">15</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Wang, Chenting T. <title render="italic">
                        <part>The Biographical Journal</part>
                     </title>, with an article by Vincent Liu [printed in Chinese]; Feb 1983</unittitle>
                  <container altrender="archive half letter"
                             containerid="39002042368770"
                             id="aspace_269d27723132a2323b91a72809d1c2c1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_26aaf5b15bc7269b1d4be489a243275c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_269d27723132a2323b91a72809d1c2c1">16</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
