<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="">beinecke.vanvechtmaur</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Letters to Saul Mauriber </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Van Vechten (Carl) Letters to Saul Mauriber</titleproper>
            <author>by Susan Brady</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>June 2018</date>
            <num>YCAL MSS 1144</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-BR</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>in_progress</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-06-12T19:03:08-04:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace v2.2.0</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Tuesday June 12, 2018 at 19:03</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Carl Van Vechten Letters to Saul Mauriber</unittitle>
         <unitid>YCAL MSS 1144</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
    
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>6.9</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(17 boxes)</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1943">1943</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1965">1965</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_9f64e5ce2aaf51082a24dc9c62e75e6d">The Carl Van Vechten Letters to Saul Mauriber date from April 1943 to December 1965, and include typed and manuscript notes, letters, greeting cards, postcards, and telegrams documenting their relationship over twenty years.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_d443d347ccfccaed2c669c453982087d">
            <language>In English.</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_6a9af5d8a67344232771e486bee8a5f5">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for research</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <arrangement id="aspace_28f6a9ab9a7c649646413f443e854c79">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_688fb727ab5b4504d98b51085cd11bc0">
         <head>Carl Van Vechten (1880-1964)</head>
         <p>Carl Van Vechten was a writer, photographer, collector, and patron of the arts.  Born in Cedar Rapids, Iowa, on June 17, 1880, Van Vechten developed an early interest in literature and the fine and performing arts.  He attended the University of Chicago, and wrote for several Chicago newspapers before moving to New York City in 1906.  Over the next five decades he established himself as a journalist, critic, novelist, photographer, and cultural icon.  He wrote music, dance, and theater reviews in New York and Paris for <title>
               <part>The New York Times</part>
            </title> and <title>
               <part>The New York Press</part>
            </title>, and for magazines and journals including <title>
               <part>Trend</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Vanity Fair</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Crisis</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>New Republic</part>
            </title>, and <title>
               <part>Esquire</part>
            </title>.  He authored numerous books including, <title>
               <part>Music After the Great War</part>
            </title> (1915), <title>
               <part>The Tiger in the House</part>
            </title> (1920), <title>
               <part>Peter Whiffle</part>
            </title>: <title>
               <part>His Life and Works</part>
            </title> (1922), <title>
               <part>The Blind-Bow Boy</part>
            </title> (1923), <title>
               <part>The Tattooed Countess</part>
            </title> (1924), <title>
               <part>Firecrackers</part>
            </title> (1925), <title>
               <part>Nigger Heaven</part>
            </title> (1926), <title>
               <part>Spider Boy</part>
            </title> (1928), <title>
               <part>Parties</part>
            </title> (1930), and <title>
               <part>Sacred and Profane Memories</part>
            </title> (1932), most of which were published by Alfred A. Knopf.</p>
         <p>His 1907 marriage to Ann Snyder, a friend since his youth in Cedar Rapids, ended in divorce in 1912.  On October 21, 1914 he married Fania Marinoff, an actress who had immigrated to the United States as a child from Russia.  They were married for fifty years.  A family inheritance received in 1927 provided Van Vechten with the means to support himself and Fania, and freed him to pursue his interests without financial constraints.  During the 1920s, Van Vechten was introduced to members of the artistic and cultural movement that would become known as the Harlem Renaissance.  He enjoyed frequenting the clubs, restaurants, and salons of Harlem, and he began to develop friendships among members of the Black community.  His 1926 novel, <title>
               <part>Nigger Heaven</part>
            </title>, was inspired by his visits to Harlem and its residents.</p>
         <p>Beginning in the early 1930s Van Vechten devoted much of his time to photography.  In his home studio he produced hundreds of photographic portraits of his friends and acquaintances, as well as other world figures whom he photographed by invitation and by recommendations from mutual friends.  He and Fania developed a large multicultural network of friends and acquaintances in New York, throughout the United States, and abroad.  The Van Vechten apartment became a meeting place for established and developing writers, visual and performing artists, publishers, educators, social activists, and others.  Throughout his life Van Vechten developed close friendships with women as well as intimate relationships with men.</p>
         <p>As a collector, Van Vechten acquired important collections of books and manuscripts, particularly those relating to African-American arts and literature.  In 1941, he established the James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts and Letters at Yale University, in honor of the writer and close friend who had died in 1938.  In 1947, Van Vechten established the Anna Marble-Pollock Collection of Books about Cats at Yale. He also gave to Yale additional individual books and manuscripts, as well as a large group of his personal papers.  He established and/or donated material to collections at other institutions including Fisk University, Howard University, the University of New Mexico, and the New York Public Library (including personal papers dating from 1833 to 1965).  Carl Van Vechten died in New York City on December 22, 1964.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <userestrict id="aspace_7addf2faa33bb4a9d8ceda4398622d29">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Carl Van Vechten Letters to Saul Mauriber is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_fbf20bc960c93ea973fc2597f6e02ef9">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased from Beverly Hill on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2018.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <prefercite id="aspace_7791a2c4c5b29c452e17b3ba9aeb2a93">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Carl Van Vechten Letters to Saul Mauriber. Yale Collection of American Literature, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_6879588ef8ae1d894b7b044aa7f53ec8">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Carl Van Vechten Letters to Saul Mauriber date from April 1943 to December 1965, and include typed and manuscript notes, letters, greeting cards, postcards, and telegrams documenting their relationship over twenty years.  As Mauriber lived in Brooklyn with his mother, Sadie Mauriber, and for many years had no telephone, they communicated by mail on a frequent basis.  In his letters Van Vechten noted appointments with sitters for photographic portraits with which Mauriber was to assist; described his social activities and news of mutual friends; and commented on Mauriber's work, travel, and family issues.  Van Vechten expressed his love for Mauriber often, and his messages included plans to meet him alone or to attend dinners or performances with Van Vechten's wife, Fania Marinoff, and friends.  Enclosures include third-party letters from mutual friends and others; newspaper clippings regarding the arts, celebrities, fashion and other subjects; advertisements for performances and exhibitions; ticket stubs (which Mauriber collected); performance programs; postcards (many of which were photographic postcards by Van Vechten); and miscellaneous objects.  The collection also includes postcards, greeting cards, and letters from Marinoff to Mauriber (in which she described her travels, thanked him for a gift, or sent birthday or holiday greetings), and greeting cards from the Van Vechten's to Saul's mother.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <processinfo id="aspace_d89a595962af64027e4419415fead29a">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected.  The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>Envelopes not associated with letters were interfiled with chronologically-arranged letters.  Postmark dates were assigned to letters (and appear in square brackets] when not dated by Van Vechten.  Letters that were sealed (or resealed) at the time of acquisition were opened by the library May, 2018, and noted as such on paper enclosure.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_bbf3f180982eb46a2dd70867638a6d77">
         <head>Saul Mauriber (1915-2003)</head>
         <p>Saul Mauriber was born in New York City, and lived most of his life in Brooklyn.  He worked as a clerk in various retail establishments including Bergdorf Goodman department store.  Mauriber also studied fashion, and for a time designed and made clothing for friends and acquaintances.  Later in life he was a real estate investor. He met Carl Van Vechten in November of 1942, when both were volunteers at the American Theatre Wing's Stage Door Canteen for servicemen during World War II.  At a gathering and photo session of Canteen volunteers at Van Vechten's home, Mauriber demonstrated an interest and ability in assisting Van Vechten with the photography.  Shortly thereafter, he became Van Vechten's photographic assistant in his home studio, setting up lighting equipment and assisting with the printing and organizing of photographs.  Their friendship grew into an intimate relationship which continued for twenty years.  After Van Vechten's death Mauriber assisted with the organization of Van Vechten's photographs and the donation of them to various cultural and educational institutions.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <dsc>
         <c id="aspace_19170bbf99ec8378debbeae0f3098b9e" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Letters</unittitle>
               <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
                  <quantity>6.3</quantity>
                  <unittype>Linear feet</unittype>
               </physdescstructured>
               <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(15 boxes)</physdesc>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1943-1965, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
            <c id="aspace_00475439c7134456cf3e05f5c0564bdc" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1943-04-23">1943-04-23</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1945-12-30">1945-12-30</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1943 April 23-1945 December 30, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_0fa3ff18920487d33480f79f4e837903"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e776fe930197c0e6e13c6fb28f5aad52"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_0fa3ff18920487d33480f79f4e837903">1-9</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_f64f2d3643e6650b976d8ba028392534" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1946-01-23">1946-01-23</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1947-12-28">1947-12-28</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1946 January 23-1947 December 28, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_b31a9dc5111e3d313e28e90b9aa393cd"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6c197c403b9e4de337df8d86302911c2"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_b31a9dc5111e3d313e28e90b9aa393cd">10-21</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_f747974693ed0be75f4e8839dd7a7cca" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1948-01-05">1948-01-05</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1949-07-31">1949-07-31</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1948 January 5-1949 July 31, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_1bb9eba1852e4b738fdc35a1dc779694"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7f432ba7a4377a2c849e39b6fd8bea98"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_1bb9eba1852e4b738fdc35a1dc779694">22-30</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_c7bcc867ae022c850537cc1cf8acd36c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1949-08-01">1949-08-01</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1950-02-28">1950-02-28</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1949 August 1-1950 February 28, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_49496645698e9af79b19ee91feb341fb"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">4</container>
                  <container id="aspace_4b04657dfdff08a43c392dc205970a8a"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_49496645698e9af79b19ee91feb341fb">31-37</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_020dfe70185d414d9bbc3a4dca3c35c6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1950-03-02">1950-03-02</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1950-09-30">1950-09-30</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1950 March 2-September 30, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_3355f707d3c7b236d86f076128426aa8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">5</container>
                  <container id="aspace_199a622fed29eddf613b139cb1b96700"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_3355f707d3c7b236d86f076128426aa8">38-46</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_b6c5c66c0c653b0285ab65f14342139c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1950-10-01">1950-10-01</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1950-12-31">1950-12-31</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1950 October 1-December 31, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_5294020d6bc771782bdd921be152c90f"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">6</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3740f9e730e3ef1e16c3d7356f532120"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_5294020d6bc771782bdd921be152c90f">47-52</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_666f8a165f1b067599884d15ee570aad" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1951-01-02">1951-01-02</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1951-06-04">1951-06-04</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1951 January 2-1951 June 4, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_54786b7e2c9c8901231f4addd67c550a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">7</container>
                  <container id="aspace_cbacc36d5869396e8cca721ad90dc9ff"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_54786b7e2c9c8901231f4addd67c550a">53-60</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_b31d0a161446ad5ffad96494a14ae359" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1951-06-09">1951-06-09</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1951-12-23">1951-12-23</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1951 June 9-December 23, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_95b5c3481738412de54e35d430f0f6a1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">8</container>
                  <container id="aspace_43061939784c660d09dabd7333ea8bdd"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_95b5c3481738412de54e35d430f0f6a1">61-66</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_6f2b89b53c2df6b3481c36622051b543" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1952-01-06">1952-01-06</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1952-07-09">1952-07-09</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1952 January 6-July 9, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_2c3c3cedd91c6cd65b9b0f421613648c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">9</container>
                  <container id="aspace_88d12ead77a53b75bdb84d0ec13acd82"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_2c3c3cedd91c6cd65b9b0f421613648c">67-76</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_86d31e6ab42a627275929fb6fc7959d5" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1952-07-10">1952-07-10</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1952-12-28">1952-12-28</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1952 July 10-December 28, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_f876f67a1b8eb370c3969828e23cc196"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">10</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1c913bc3011a65b74383d64a30a840b6"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_f876f67a1b8eb370c3969828e23cc196">77-87</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_ae0cffb4180bb9dbe0714f9bd5be818c" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1953-01-03">1953-01-03</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1954-01-09">1954-01-09</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1953 January 3-1954 January 9, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_e5092dbddf34c892c8e544c7a15fa503"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">11</container>
                  <container id="aspace_57858a2f9289a6598d50153da7525543"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_e5092dbddf34c892c8e544c7a15fa503">88-97</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_63352a4f1e1ba75b23ecddf157dbeb7f">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes children's book, Heads Bodies &amp; Legs by Denis Wirth-Miller and Richard Chopping (London: Penguin, 1951) in envlope postmarked December 16, 1952; third-party letter from "Dot," likely Dorothy Mauriber, Saul's sister-in-law (1953 December 29)</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_d3772aae308fca516bade0687fd59a82" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1954-01-11">1954-01-11</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1955-12-18">1955-12-18</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1954 January 11-1955 December 18, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_686963c5762b8aea1f44ad0bd65f9231"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">12</container>
                  <container id="aspace_cadc4df16d928aaa45c55ad8e52e7707"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_686963c5762b8aea1f44ad0bd65f9231">98-107</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_0c2bbe80379c237beedcb1e6fac8fa67">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes third-party letters to CVV from George Kennedy, Christopher Isherwood, Bruce Kellner, Dick Wardell, Edward Donahoe, and Walter Burr Van Vechten enclosed with letters from CVV to Mauriber</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_f1e35420d3f8d14ce7fa3656ea10768b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1956-02-11">1956-02-11</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1958-12-18">1958-12-18</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1956 February 11-1958 December 18, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_141d732e86660a234449d1d904296cf3"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">13</container>
                  <container id="aspace_523bed6108451f9e1064f2b04c5e603f"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_141d732e86660a234449d1d904296cf3">108-116</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_d0238abb7f02c0ea717745564f33a51b" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1959-01-09">1959-01-09</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1961-12-28">1961-12-28</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1959 January 9-1961 December 28, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_131b721853108f789082e047fff49465"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">14</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f31f866bc2dd3e136e1c903dfd70240e"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_131b721853108f789082e047fff49465">117-126</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="aspace_7ee7c0f2a0d886277098741faf70c15d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1962-09-22">1962-09-22</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1965-12">1965-12</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1962 September 22-1965 December, undated</unitdate>
                  <container id="aspace_79ca3c32e5539c3e28a66c463320a0f0"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="Box">15</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1c68ccdbba4ef6539ec7dbc1bfdc924b"
                             localtype="Folder"
                             parent="aspace_79ca3c32e5539c3e28a66c463320a0f0">127-135</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_2c4023c87aa78278729c044d2e9a92bf">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Includes Christmas card containing a manuscript note from CVV to Mauriber dated "Christmas 1965"; and a folder of undated photographic postcards of CVV, Mauriber and others by CVV, some of which have manuscript notes from CVV on the versos</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
