<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.geary">beinecke.geary</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the John White Geary Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Geary (John White) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>by Beinecke Staff</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>August 1992</date>
            <num>WA MSS 212</num>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-BR</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>beinecke manuscript unit archival processing manual</abbr>
         <citation>translation missing: en.enumerations.resource_finding_aid_description_rules.beinecke manuscript unit archival processing manual</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>under_revision</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-12-09T04:28:18+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.4.1.yale.hm.mm</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Sunday December  9, 2018 at 04:28</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="revised"/>
            <eventdatetime>2010-02-10</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="unknown"/>
            <agent/>
            <eventdescription>Transformed with yale.addEadidUrl.xsl. Adds @url with handle for finding aid. Overwrites @url if already present. </eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="revised"/>
            <eventdatetime>2007-08-13</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="unknown"/>
            <agent/>
            <eventdescription>beinecke.geary.xml converted for compliance with Yale EAD Best Practice Guidelines with brbl-migrate-01.xsl (mr2007-08-13). </eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="revised"/>
            <eventdatetime>2007-07-26</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="unknown"/>
            <agent/>
            <eventdescription>PUBLIC "-//Yale University::Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library//TEXT (US::CtYBR::::[JOHN WHITE GEARY PAPERS ])//EN" "geary.xml" converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.xsl (sy2003-10-15). </eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>John White Geary papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>WA MSS 212</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>1.6</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(4 boxes)</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1855">1855</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1871">1871</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_117829ae5c7e1a989111ec14a2d2d881">The collection consists of the official papers of John Geary while governor of Kansas Territory, 1856-57, with some personal papers, 1855-71. The papers document Kansas during the Free State War and the building of the capitol.</abstract>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81118811" source="naf">
               <part>Geary, John White, 1819-1873</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_671be151ed7da863347f8e12083e2cd2">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of William Robertson Coe.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_1b95080e3fceefc59e027387814de594">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The John White Geary Papers are the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_d3e6970e62f8e5e851091e14354ba367">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>John White Geary Papers. Yale Collection of Western Americana, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_24c35e2176ffd71aadd0a17715791d39">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_b1b60b42d2744fdab8aadfc7a669a190">
         <head>Associated Materials</head>
         <p>Other Geary collections at the Beinecke are the <ref actuate="onrequest"
                 href="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.gearybus"
                 show="new">John White Geary Business Papers (WA MSS 209)</ref>, the <ref actuate="onrequest"
                 href="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.jwgeary"
                 show="new">John White Geary Mexican War Papers (WA MSS S-585)</ref>, and a letter from Geary to Major General Persifor Smith (WA MSS S-218).</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_adaae95cad415a934abf0133dcb60a0c">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>John White Geary was born near Mount Pleasant, Westmoreland County, Pennsylvania, on December 30, 1819. He served during the Mexican War in the 2d Pennsylvania Infantry. In 1849, President Polk appointed him postmaster at San Francisco, but Geary had hardly begun his duties when his Whig successor, appointed by President Taylor, arrived. Geary was elected first alcalde of San Francisco and appointed judge; he later became the first mayor. In 1852, he returned to Pennsylvania, and in 1856, when Kansas was in a state of civil war, he accepted appointment as governor of the Territory. He made great advances at first, but aroused the enmity of pro-slavery politicians. When he did not receive the necessary military and official support from the government, he resigned and returned to Pennsylvania in 1857. He later served as colonel of the 28th Pennsylvania Regiment during the Civil War and was twice elected governor of the state, serving from 1867 to 1873.</p>
         <p>The manuscripts in the John White Geary Papers give a vivid picture of conditions in Kansas during the Free State War. They consist of the "executive minutes" and official correspondence of John W. Geary, Governor of Kansas Territory, 1856-57, as well as a few personal letters and papers, 1855-57. They include petitions from citizens of other states in behalf of the Free State prisoners, congratulatory letters on Geary's accomplishment in restoring peace in Kansas, and documents and receipts relating to the building of the capitol.</p>
         <p>The letters from Governor Geary are copies, usually in his secretary's hand. There are typewritten transcripts of some of the more important papers. The correspondence, with the exception of five letters written between 1862 and 1871, is dated from April 22, 1856 to December 4, 1857. The minutes, which are almost all in John Gihon's handwriting, contain copies of official letters to and from the governor, his messages to the legislature, and other official acts, with records of events in diary form inserted chronologically.</p>
         <p>The following detailed list of papers in the collection can also be found on pp. 110-24 of A Catalogue of Manuscripts in the Collection of Western Americana in the Yale University Library, Mary C. Withington, editor.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <odd id="aspace_8a024652c03421a2c52ca36b6f86f6ea">
         <head>Appendix: Alphabetical List of Correspondents</head>
         <p>Geary, John White. Executive minutes kept by Governor Geary's private secretary, John H. Gihon, September 9, 1856-March 20, 1857. 2 vols. [i.e., 533 pp.] Original bindings. 31-33 cm.</p>
         <p>The minutes, which are almost entirely in Gihon's handwriting, contain copies of official letters to and from the governor, his messages to the legislature and other official acts, with records of events in diary form inserted chronologically.</p>
         <p>---- Governor Geary's personal letters and reports to Secretary of State William L. Marcy, Secretary of the Treasury James Guthrie, President Pierce, and President Buchanan. September 6, 1856-February 12, 1857. Copied by his secretary. 130 pp. Original binding. 20 1/2 cm.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to James Buchanan. April 27, 1857. Copy. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Two letters to Lewis Cass. April 20, December 4, 1857. Copies. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to George W. Clarke. December 22, 1856. Copy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to William Flinn. January 7, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to John B. Floyd. April 17, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to John A. Halderman, F. Renick, William A. Shannon, Committee. September 9, 1856. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to L. S. Hall. October 11, 1856. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Power of attorney to Andrew J. Jones. August 28, 1856. Witnessed by Richard McAllister and Theodore Adams, and signed by Jones before the same witnesses. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to the Hon. W. Medill. July 8, 1857. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Three letters to Franklin Pierce, President of the United States. August 9-December 10, 1856. Copies. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to William P. Richardson. August 21, 1856. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to Governor Charles Robinson. July 13, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Two letters to Persifor F. Smith. October 6, November 11, 1856. Copies. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to H. T. Titus. November 8, 1856. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to Elisha Whittlesey. February 4, 1857. With statement of account to June 30, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Abstract of account in disbursement for the capitol. April 16, 1857. 2 copies. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Abstract statement of expenditures [ca. July 7, 1856]. 2 copies. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Abstract of expenditures in the purchase of library for Kansas Territory [December 1, 1856]. With the receipted bill for the books signed by James L. Gihon, December 2, 1856. 12 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Affidavit for the arrest of William T. Sherrard before S. G. Cato, February 9, 1857. Copy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Bill for expenses, September 9, 1856-March 5, 1857. Copy. With unsigned copy of accompanying affidavit, April 16, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Estimate by counties of the probable population of the Territory. November 27, 1856. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Memorandum of payments made to Kansas Militia. December 3, 1856. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Memorandum of testimony, Territory vs. J. A. W. Jones. February 28, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- "Opinions &amp; notes." [August 9, 1856.] Not Geary's hand. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Statement of conditions in Kansas Territory. Endorsed: "Notes prepared by JON." [n.d.] 18 pp.</p>
         <p>Abreo, Mrs. Cornelia M. Letter to Geary. December 9, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Adams, Theodore. 13 letters to Geary. August 22, 1856-July 8, 1857. 28 pp.</p>
         <p>Anderson, Robert. Letter to Geary. September 19, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Arny, William F. M. Two letters to Geary. December 8, 1856, February 2, 1857. 12 pp.</p>
         <p>"Atcherson County." Letter to Geary about Charles M. Hays. February 6, 1857. Signed: "Atcherson County." 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Babcock, Carmi W. Letter to Colonel McAllister. February 16, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Bachman, B. C. Letter to Geary. March 10, 1857. With noted added from Josephine Stuart. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Bailey, James G. Letter to Geary. October 9, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Bainter, Ephraim. Territory of Kansas vs. Ephraim Bainter. November 3, 1856. Certiifed copy of judgment, February 17, 1857, James R. Whitehead, clerk, by W. L. Kuykendall, deputy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Baker, Arthur J. Two letters to Geary. January 12, February 10, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Banks, E. A. Letter to Geary. January 26, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bardwell, George H. Letter to Geary. January 19, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Barnett, Ward B. Letter to Geary. September 26, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Barnum, Heron. Letter to Geary. October 11, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Barton, John T. Letter to Geary. House of Representatives, January 1, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bashford, Coles. Letter to Geary. November 29, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Beach, Ashael. Letter to Geary. October 4, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Beeson, Richard. Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Betts, Royston. Letter to Geary. December 31, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Big Springs. Citizens. Report of a meeting upholding Geary. February 17, 1857. Signed by Charles D. Jones, chairman, Charles A. Allen, secretary, and 22 others. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Bigham, John. Letter to Geary. September 15, 1857. Signed also by Joseph Cook, John B. Davison, George Gallagher. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bigler, William. Two letters and a telegram to Geary. July 23- November 14, 1856. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Bingham, E. F. Letter to Geary. January 15, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Bingham, George. Letter to Geary. January 24, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bladen, Washington. Letter to Geary. August 26, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Boone, Albert G. Letter to Geary. March 5, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bowman, George W. Three letters to Geary. January 21-March 11, 1857. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Boyle, J. A. Letter to Geary. March 7, 1857. 2 p.</p>
         <p>Bradshaw, William. Letter to Geary. August 4, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Breece, S. D. Letter to Geary. September 1, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bretz, C. Letter to Geary. November 15, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bright, J. D. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bright, M. G. Letter to Geary. November 7, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Brindle, William. Four letters to Geary. May 15, 1856- January 17, 1857. 7 pp.</p>
         <p>Brookbank, John B. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Brown, George W. Seven letters to Geary. September 1, 1856- January 15, 1857. 13 pp.</p>
         <p>Brown, James W. Letter to Geary. February 8, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Browne, O. H. Letter to Geary. September 13, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Brunswick, Me. Citizens. To the President of the United States. Petition in behalf of prisoners. Endorsed: "Referred to Gov. Geary for any suggestions he may think the case warrants. F. P." [November 1856?] With 30 signatures. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Buchanan, James. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Bullock, Charles P. Letter to Geary. January 13, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Burgess, R. Letter to Geary. January 14, 1857. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Butler, David. Letter to Geary. April 28, 1871. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Caldwell, A. Letter to Geary. August 30, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Calhoun, John. "Proceedings of a meeting said to have been held at Council House, Wyandot." John Calhoun chairman and McLean secretary. Notes in an unidentified hand [July? 1856]. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Calohan, William S. Letter to Geary. August 2, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Carpenter, Samuel L. Letter to Geary. January 29, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Cass, Lewis. Four letters to Geary. October 23, 1856- November 28, 1857. 9 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to Hon. Howell Cobb. May 22, 1857. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Castleman, Benjamin D. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Cato, Sterling G. Letter to Geary. November 10, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Christian, James. Letter to Geary. June 21, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Clegg, B. Letter to Geary. February 10, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Coffey, A. M. Letter to Geary. March 7, 1857. Signed also by M. McCaslin. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Coleman, William. Letter to Geary. June 27, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Collins, Thomas. Letter to Geary. January 28, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Cook, William A. Letter to Geary. July 27, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Cooke, Philip St. George. Five letters to Geary. [September 12, 1856]- March 14, 1857. 8 pp.</p>
         <p>Corley, John. Letter to Geary. February 3, [1857]. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Coyle, John. Three letters to Geary. September 20, 1856- January 26 [i.e., 29], 1857. The letter of September 20 is signed also by William Bryant, Charles King, and J. B. Todd. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Craig, Henry Knox. Letter to Geary. November 13, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Crane, John M. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Cunard, L. M. Letter to Geary. November 6, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Cunningham, Thomas. Letter to Geary. February 15, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Curry, William B. Three letters to Geary. August 13- September 3, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Cushman, C. A. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Cutler, Andrew S. Two letters to Geary. October 22, 29, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Danforth, C. H. Letter to Geary. January 12, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Daniels, Edward. Letter to Geary. December 11, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Davidson, H. O. Letter to Geary. August 17, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Davis, B. F. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Davis, Isaac. Letter to Geary. November 13, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Davis, John W. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Delahay, Mark W. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>DeSelding, Charles. Letter to Geary. January 17, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Dewey, S. P. Letter to Geary. August 2, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>DeWolfe, Ezekiel. Letter to Geary. September 7, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Dick, John T. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Donoughe, Cornelius. Two letters to Geary. August 9, October 22, 1856. 9 pp.</p>
         <p>Dougherty, B. A. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Downer, James P. Three letters to Geary. October 4, 1856- January 30, 1856 [i.e., 1857]. 7 pp.</p>
         <p>Drum, Richard C. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Dull, J. J. Two letters to Geary. January 22, February 23, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Duncan, William M. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Dundas, William H. Letter to Geary. November 26, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Dunn, Richard C. Letter to Geary. February 17, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Dutton, Benjamin F. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Dyer, William F. Letter to Geary. January 26, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Eastin, Lucien J. Letter to Geary. February 26, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Eberhart, A. G. Two letters to Geary. October 30, 1856, February 11, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Edgar, William. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Eldridge, Shaler W. Two letters to Geary. December 18, 1856, February 9, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Elliott, Archibald. Letter to Geary. September 19, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Elliott, John A. Letter to Geary. January 19, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Emerson, W. A. G. Letter to Geary. February 12, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Emory, W. H. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 2pp.</p>
         <p>Emrick, Simon. Letter to Geary. February 7, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Fish, Hamilton. Form letter to Geary. April 15, 1871. With a printed copy of the Act of Congress providing for the commemoration of the centennial. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Flenniken, Robert P. Letter to Geary. January 15, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Flint, F. F. Letter to Geary. January 27, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Forman, John W. Petition to Governor Geary. [September, 1856?] Signed also by William P. Richardson, F. J. Marshall, D. A. N. Grover, B. O. Driscoll, and Thomas W. Waterson. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Forster, John T. Letter to Geary. January 5, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Fox, George K. Letter to Geary. June 6, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Frain, William P. Letter to Geary. March 9, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Friend to the oppressed, A. Letter to Geary. November 21, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Fuller, Perry. Letter to Geary. March 4, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Furcey, William. Letter to Geary. February 6, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Garrett, R. Letter to Governor Geary on the division of Riley County. February 16, 1857. Signed also by Thomas Reynolds and Stephen B. Williams. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Garvey, Edward C. K. Letter to Geary. November 24, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Gates, Mrs. Louise W. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Geary, Edward R. Five letters to his brother, John W. Geary. September 17, 1856-February 19, 1857. 18 pp.</p>
         <p>Geary, Edward R., 2d. Eight letters to his father, J. W. Geary. June 13, 1856-September 2, 1857. 21 pp.</p>
         <p>Geary, John. Letter to his uncle, J. W. Geary. November 1, [1855]. Signed by his mark and written by his father, E. R. Geary, with note added on the same sheet. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>George, George W. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Gihon, John H. 14 letters to Geary. October 28 [i.e., 18], 1856- July 29, 1857. 47 pp.</p>
         <p>Gihon, John L. [H?]. Letter to Geary. July 15, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Gilman, Charles. Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Goetsch, Oscar. Letter in German to Geary. January 29, 1857. Signed also by Maria Goetsch. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Goodin, Joel Kishler. Two letters to Geary. February 12, 18, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Gorley, J. Letter to Geary. November 14, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Graham, A. D. Letter to Geary. February 28, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Grant, Edwin H. Letter to Geary. July 30, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Greathouse, J. S. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Guthrie, John B. Letter to Geary. August 4, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Haldeman, Cyrus S. Six letters to Geary. November 13, 1856- May 22, [1857]. 14 pp.</p>
         <p>Haldeman, Horace. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Halderman, John A. Two letters to Geary. September 9, 1856, January 20, 1857. The earlier letter is signed also by O. F. Renick and W. A. Shannon. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hall, L. S. Two letters to Geary. October 10, November 24, [1856]. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Hampton, Levi J. Two letters to Geary. March 16, 23, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Harvey, John A. Two letters to Geary. November 22, 1856, March 4, 1857. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Hastings, John. Letter to Geary. September 20, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hatch, J. M. Letter to Geary. April 10, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hawke, George. Letter to Geary. February 9, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Hays, John. Letter to Geary. January 3, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Heberton, Edward P. Letter to Geary. [September 1856.] Enclosing a letter of introduction to Governor Geary from David R. Porter, September 6, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Heiskell, William A. Letter to Geary. March 5, 1857. Signed also by L. D. Williams. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Heister, A. O. Letter to Geary. September 18, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Henshaw, John C. Letter to Geary. July 29, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hewitt, Girart. Letter to Geary. November 6, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hickory Point, Jefferson Co., K. T. "Names of Convicts who were convicted for acts committed at Hickory Point, Jefferson County, K. T." [October? 1856.] In an unidentified hand. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hicks, Sarah (Mrs. Joseph). Letter to Geary. November 9, 1856, with added note, November 24. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Higgins, Silas Parsons. Letter to Geary. November 29, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hodge, William L. Letter to Geary. August 12, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Holmes, William W. Letter to Geary. January 29, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hoogland, Edward. 11 letters to Geary. August 18, [1856]- April 19, 1857. 43 pp.</p>
         <p>Horrell, Irwin. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. Signature only. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Hornsby, Brinkly. Letter to Geary. October 27, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hoscroft, John I. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hughes, H. Courtenay. Letter to Geary. January 7, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Hulburd, A. N. Letter to Geary. February 14, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hulse, George T. Letter to Geary. March 3, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Humphrey, John. Letter to Geary. February 2, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Hunter, Alexander Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hurd, H. B. Two letters to Geary. October 8, November 22, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Hyatt, Thaddeus. Two letters to Geary. December 5, 8, 1856. Signatures only. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Iowa County, Wis. Citizens. Petition in behalf of William H. Gill. November 8, 1856. With 37 signatures. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Irvine, James. Two letters to Geary. August 10, 1856, January 19, 1857. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Ives, Timothy. Two letters to Geary. October 24, November 5, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Ivory, William W. Letter to Geary. August 7, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Jackson, Isaiah H. Letter to Geary. November 6, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>James, Burton A. Two letters to Geary. January 7, February 23, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>James, Henry. Letter to Geary. January 11, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Jefferson County, K. T. Citizens. Petition in behalf of Ephraim Bainter. [October? 1856.] With 87 signatures. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Jefferson, Ind. Committee. Petition for clemencey for Otis Mason Marsh. November 5, 1856. Signed by Levi Sparks and nine citizens, with a letter from Joseph A. Wright, Governor of Indiana, November 7, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Johns, Henry F. Letter to Geary. March 30, 1857. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Johnson, James Neely. Letter to Geary. March 18, 1857. Signature only. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Johnson, L. M. Letter to Geary. February 3, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Johnston, B. K. Letter to Geary. September 14, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Johnstone, Edward. Three letters to Geary. September 14-October 22, 1856. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Jones, A. W. Letter to Geary. December 1, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Jones, Andrew J. 21 letters to Geary. July 21, 1856-July 8, 1857. 47 pp.</p>
         <p>Jones, John A. W. Three letters to Geary. October 6, 1856- July 6, 1857. The letter of July 6 encloses a copy of Medill's letter to Jones, July 3, 1857. 8 pp.</p>
         <p>Jones, Sarah L. Letter to Geary. January 24, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Kansas Territory. Citizens. Petition in behalf of William Partridge. December 22, 1856. With 70 signatures. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Petition for the release of Free State prisoners, with the names of the prisoners [January 13, 1857]. Signed by G. W. Brown, Richard J. Hinton, James F. Walker, L. S. Hall, A. W. Gleason. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Kansas Territory. Legislature. Committee. Notes of remarks about Geary [by John Calhoun?] during the 3d Session of the House. [After January 12, 1857.] Endorsed by Geary [?]: "This paper was blown by the wind from Surveyor Genl. Calhoun's office to mine." 1 p.</p>
         <p>Kean, John. Two letters to Geary. January 25, February 20, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Kerr, Leander. Letter to Geary. October 23, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Key, Thomas K. Two letters to Geary. January 26, February 20, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Killen, Daniel. Letter to Geary. March 8, 1857. Signed, with postscript by Killen. 1 p.</p>
         <p>King, Horatio. Letter to Geary. October 29, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>King, John A. Letter to Geary. January 9, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Kirkpatrick, John M. Four letters to Geary. August 23, 1856- April 2, 1857. 10 pp.</p>
         <p>Klotz, Robert. Letter to Geary. March 25, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Ladd, Erastus D. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Ladies Sewing Circle, Lawrence. Invitation to Geary. November 14, 1856. Signed by L. S. Hall, corresponding secretary. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Laird, J. M. Letter to Geary. January 10, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Lanz, Alfred. Letter to Geary. February, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Petition for pardon for men convicted for their part in the attack on Hickory Point. [n.d., October ? 1856.] Signed also by J. M. Bernard, W. W. Spratt, D. K. Stout, M. P. Randall, Matthew R. Walker, G. N. Reis. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Latham, R. W. Letter to Geary. January 22, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Lawrence, Amos A. Two letters to Geary. November 8, 1856, February 5, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Leavitt, Stephen. Letter to Geary. January 8, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>LeCompte, Samuel Dexter. Letter to Geary. September 17, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Lloyd, William M. Letter to Geary. October 9, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Logan, Samuel. Letter to his brother-in-law, J. W. Geary. June 23, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Logan, William W. Three letters to Geary. July 9-August 5, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Lowry, M. B. Letter to Geary. July 30, 1856. Signature only. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>McAleer, Joseph L. Letter to Geary. January 9, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>McAllister, John H. Letter to Geary. December 6, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>McAllister, Richard. Nine letters to Geary. July 14, 1856- May 13, 1857. 28 pp.</p>
         <p>McCandless, Wilson. Letter to Geary. September 19, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>McCann, Thomas K. Three letters to Geary. July 31, 1856- March 27, 1857. 8 pp.</p>
         <p>McCaslin, Maxwell. Seven letters to Geary. August 9, 1856- February 25, 1857. 17 pp.</p>
         <p>McClintock, Jonas R. Letter to Geary. [n.d.] Endorsed: "August 1, 1856." 1 p.</p>
         <p>McFadin, Andrew H. Three letters to Geary about Henry Sherman. March 3-9, 1857. The last letter is signed also by L. D. Williams, Henry Tuley, Thomas Totten, George Wilson and S. P. Boon before Henry W. Peck. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>McFarren, Samuel. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>McGee, E. M. Letter to Geary. January 10, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>McKowen, Samuel. Two letters to Geary. October 8, 1856, February 16, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>McLure, C. C. Letter to Geary. September 9, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>McNamara, Thomas. Two letters to Geary. October 16, 1856, February 23, 1857. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>McQuaide, James G. Letter to Geary. September 15, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Maguire, Thomas A. Two letters to Geary. August 6, September 14, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Marcy, William Learned. Two letters to Geary. August 26, September 2, 1856. Signatures only. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Markoe, Francis. Three letters to Geary. August 8-October 24, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Marsh, Samuel. Two letters to Geary. October 13, 1856. Enclosing a letter of the same date to his brother, Otis Mason Marsh. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to President Pierce. October 13, 1856. Endorsed: "Referred to Gov. Geary. F. P." 1 p.</p>
         <p>Marshall, Frank J. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Agreement with Governor Shannon to transport from St. Louis material for the capitol at Lecompton, April 22, 1856. Signed by Marshall and Wilson Shannon, witnessed by R. C. Bishop, C. A. Perry, Elias H. Perry, and H. Basye. Copy. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Receipt for transporting material for the capitol. January 13, 1857. Certified by Wilson Shannon. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Marye, Simon B. Letter to Geary. August 15, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Mathias, William G. Letter to Geary. February 18, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Matteson, Joel Aldrich. Letter to Geary. December 25, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Maynadier, Henry. Letter to Geary. March 19, 1857. Signature only. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Medary, Samuel. Letter to Geary. January 22, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Medill, William. Three letters to Geary. May 27-July 17, 1857. Signatures only. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Merrill, Abel. Letter to Geary. January 13, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Millar, I. Letter to Geary. November 16, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Miller, George W. Letter to Geary. February 11, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Mitchell, A. M. Letter to Geary. January 7, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Mitchell, D., Jr. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1856 [i.e., 1857]. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Mitchell, Edward P. Letter to Geary. October 25, 1862. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Mitchell, James. Two letters to Geary. November 7, December 12, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Montague, Isaac W., and Hannah S. Letter to Geary. October 17, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Moore, J. D. Letter to Geary. February 24, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Moore, W. W. Letter to Geary. February 11, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Morrison, J. Letter to Governor Wright. November 12, 1856. With postscript by N. Hayden. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Murphy, William E. Letter to Geary. January 21, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Nichols, Julia A. Letter to Geary. November 21, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Nichols, R. D. Letter to Geary. February 26, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Nones, J. H. Letter to C. S. Haldeman. April 8, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>[Nute, Ephraim.] Statement of treatment received from the "Border Ruffians" on August 28, 1856, when he was traveling with his sister-in-law, whose husband, William C. Hoppe, had been murdered a few days before. September 15, 1857. Unsigned. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>O'Hern, M. P. Two telegrams and a letter to Geary. July 23- August 27, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Orr, John M. Letter to Geary. August 19, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Ottawa Creek, K. T. Proceedings of a meeting at Otaway [<title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>sic</part>
            </title>] Creek, February 14, 1857, S. Mewhinney, chairman, John W. Griffith, secretary. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Paine, Alfred J. et al. vs. Territory of Kansas. Copy of the judgment rendered, certified February 17, 1857, James R. Whitehead, clerk, by W. L. Kuykendall, deputy clerk, 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Painter, C. R. Letter to Geary. January 15, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Painter, Israel. Invitation to a dinner in Pittsburgh. March 19, 1857. Signed by Israel Painter, P. C. Shannon and 18 other citizens. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Pardee, A. W. Two letters to Geary. January 28, February 3, 1857. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Parrott, Marcus J. Two letters to Geary. September 13, October 5, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Parsons, Theophilus. Letter to Geary, introducing John Coffey Douglass, Yale 1853. October 29, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Partridge, William. Letter to Geary. January 24, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Patrick, Albert G. Letter to Geary. December 2, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Patterson, Almis B. Letter to Geary. October 30, 1856. 3 pp</p>
         <p>. Patterson, Findley. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Paynter, Reece. Letter to Geary. February 20, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Peck, John. Two letters to Geary. October 24, 1856, January 30, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Pellit, Sarah. Two letters to Geary. January 15, 1856 [i.e., 1857], February 3, 1857. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Peterson, T. B. Letter to John H. Gihon. January 5, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Petition to Governor Geary to pardon Elias Roark. November 24, 1856. With 101 signatures. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Phillips, E. A. Letter to Geary. November 8, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Pierce, Franklin. Telegram and letter to Geary. August 26, 1856, March 25, [1857]. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Pleasant Grove, Ind., Citizens. Petition to Governor Joseph A. Wright in behalf of William Updegraff. October 27, 1857. With 42 signatures. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Plumley, George R. Two letters to Geary. January 14, March 2, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Pomeroy, Phinehas. Letter to Geary. February 2, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Pomeroy, Samuel Clarke. Letter to Geary. February 10, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Porter, David R. Letter to Geary. August 1, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Price, Thomas B. Two letters to Geary. August 28, 1856, July 1857. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Price, William. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Prisoners at Lecompton, November 12, 1856. a list. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Purse, William A. Two letters to Geary. May 19, 1856, February 20, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Rainey, William. Letter to Geary. November 17, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Ray, Alexander. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Reeder, Andrew H. Letter to Geary. May 19, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Republican Central Committee of the City and County of New York. Resolution adopted March 25, 1857. Signed by John A. Kennedy, president, William Peel, J. L. Woodford, secretaries. Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Reynolds, L. C. Letter to Geary. October 26, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Rice, John T. Affidavit. Leavenworth Co., K. T. January 8, 1857, about the sacking of the post office at Alexandria, September 1856, Jos. L. McAleer, postmaster. Sworn before Richard R. Rees, with a note signed by Lewis N. Reis, postmaster, Leavenworth City. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Richardson, William P. Letter to Nathaniel Pascall. February 10, 1857. Copy. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Richmond, L. Three letters to Geary. October 18-November 28, 1856. 8 pp.</p>
         <p>Ritchey, A. J. Letter to Geary. September 27, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Roark, Elias vs. Territory of Kansas. Copy of judgment, certified February 16, 1857 by James R. Whitehead, clerk, W. L. Kuykendall, deputy. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Roberts, William G. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Roberts, William Young. Two letters to Geary of same date. February 1, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Robinson, Charles. Four letters to Geary. September 14-December 20, 1856. 7 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to Geary about the postmaster at Lawrence. December 26, 1856. With added notes, December 27, by G. W. Brown, S. B. Prentiss and C. W. Babcock. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Rodgers, George J[?]. Letter to Geary. September 27, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Rodrigue, Aristides. Letter to Geary. February 4, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Agreement, March 9, 1856, canceling contract of December 27, 1855, for building the capitol. Witnessed by John H. Gihon. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Statement of settlement. March 9, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Abstract of settlement of capitol building contract with Rodrigue. [April 16, 1857.] Copy. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Rogers, A. A. Letter to Geary. September 30, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Ross, Randal. Letter to Geary. January 20, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Rowe, George J. Letter to Geary. January 14, 1857. Signed also by Jacob Rowe. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Ruff, B. F. Letter to Geary. November 21, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Rumbold, William. Two letters to Geary. September 15, 1856, March 14, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Russell, William Hepburn. Seven letters and a telegram to Geary. December 1, 1856-February 16, 1857. 13 pp.</p>
         <p>Sansom, J. B. Two letters to Geary. January 12, March 16, 1857. 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Scamman, T. Letter to Geary. January 10, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Schley, James M. Letter to Geary. August 18, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Seegar, John R. L. Letter to Geary. November 3, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Settle, William H. Letter to Geary. December 1, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Sexton, Charles A. Letter to Geary. November 13, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Shearer, Crawford W. Letter to Geary. August 7, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Sherrard, William T. Letter to Geary. December 22, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Territory of Kansas vs. William T. Sherrard. Writ of arrest, signed by S. G. Cato, assistant justice of the Supreme Court, K. T., February 9, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Shore, S. T. Letter to Geary. November 5, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Sibley, Henry Hastings. Two letters to Geary. December 5, 1856, January 12, 1857. 7 pp.</p>
         <p>Smith, Hamilton. Letter to Geary. December 30, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Smith, Persifor Frazer. Nine letters to Geary. September 16, 1856- February 16, 1857. 28 pp.</p>
         <p>Smith, Samuel O. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Sons of Temperance. Friendship Division No. 19. Resolution of thanks to Governor Geary, April 5, 1870. Signed by Oliver Martin and A. G. Little. Broadside. 36 x 47 1/2 cm.</p>
         <p>Speer, W. R. Letter to Geary. September 16, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Spencer, John C. Letter to Geary. January 1, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Spencer, William. Letter to Geary. January 17, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Spering, Joshua. Letter to Geary. January 5, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Spicer, John. Letter to Geary. Unsigned and undated. Endorsed: "Private. John Spicer, Decr. 21st, 1856." 2 pp.</p>
         <p>
            <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>Squatter Sovereign</part>
            </title>, Atchison, K. T. Bill for printing proclamations and advertisement for proposals for building the capitol, February 9, 1857. Receipted by Stringfellow, Kelly &amp; Lasey, and certified February 21, 1857, by Wilson Shannon. Duplicate. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Sterett, Samuel H. Letter to Geary. September 12, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Sterett, William A. Letter to Geary. September 29, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Stevens, William. Letter to Geary. March 21, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Stewart, Charles. Letter to Geary. August 7, 1856. Written and signed by B. K. Johnston. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Stewart, Owen C. Letter to Geary. February 18, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Stewart, Samuel. Letter to Geary. November 15, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Stewart, T. G. Letter to Geary. January 27, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Stillman, E. A. Letter to Geary. December 25, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Storrs, N. S. Letter to Geary. February 20, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Strickler, Hiram Jackson. Two letters to Geary. May 11, August 11, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Strong, D. Letter to Geary. July 30, 1856. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Stroud, R. P. Letter to Geary. July 31, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Stump, John M. Two letters to Geary. August 20, November 12, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Sturgeon, Isaac H. Three letters to Geary. September 9, 1856- January 29, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to Wilson Shannon. January 27, 1857. Signed by J. W. Wills. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Swift, A. C. Letter to Geary. January 18, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Swiss Colonization Society, Cincinnati. Two letters to Geary. January 19, 1857, signed by J. C. Christian and Felix Schelling; March 7, 1857, signed by Felix Schelling. 6 pp.</p>
         <p>Tanner, William. Letter to Geary. February 22, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Tassey, Mrs. Emily E. Letter to Geary. January 12, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Tebbs, A. Sidney. Three letters to Geary. August 4, 1856- March 19, 1857. 7 pp.</p>
         <p>Ten Eyck, Anthony. Two letters to Geary. November 7, December 12, 1856. 7 pp.</p>
         <p>Thomas, Charles H. Letter to Geary. January 12, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Thomas, Francis John. Letter to Geary. January 20, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Thomas, Lewis A. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Titus, Henry T. Letter to Geary. November 8, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Statement regarding the attack on him sworn to before R. B. Nelson, J. P. August 25, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Todd, J. M. Letter to Geary. August 3, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Topeka, Ladies of. Petition for the pardon and release of Free State prisoners. [October? 1856.] With 19 signatures. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Totten, Thomas. Complaint to Governor Geary against Partridge and Holmes. February 25, 1857. Signed also by Henry Tuley, A. H. McFadin, H. W. Peck and Baptis Peora. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Upton, John. Letter to Geary [?]. August 7, 1856. With postscript by S. F. Tappan. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Van Nostrand, A. M. Letter to Geary. January 14, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Wattles, Augustus. Letter to Geary. January 25, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Wea Emigrants. Address to Governor Geary. Wea Plains, Ind., [1857]. Signed by Daniel H. Roberts, John O. Wattles, Milton Hollingsworth. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Constitution and list of members. [n.d.] 5 pp.</p>
         <p>Whitfield, John W. Letter to Geary. January 18, 1857. 3 pp.</p>
         <p>Whittlesey, Elisha. 15 letters to Geary. October 23, 1856- April 25, 1857. Signatures only. 30 pp. Enclosed with the letter of January 28, 1857 are a statment of differences in the account of Governor Shannon; copy of a letter from Whittlesey to Shannon, January 27, 1857; and two copies of Owen C. Stewart's bill for services on the capitol building, certified, January 23, 1857, by Wilson Shannon. 8 pp.</p>
         <p>Williams, Lorange D. Letter to Geary. January 30, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>---- Affidavit before A. H. McFadin about the death of Henry Sherman. March 3, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Williams, William. Letter to Geary. August 27, 1856. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Wilson, George. Letter to Colonel Boone. March 3, 1857. Signed also by Thomas Totten, and forwarded by Boone to Geary. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Wilson, John A. Letter to Geary. November 4, 1856. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Winston, J. Letter to Geary. February 10, [1857]. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Winston, Thomas B. Letter to Geary. January 21, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Wise, Henry Alexander. Requisition to Governor Geary for delivery of Joseph L. McCubbin. January 3, 1857. Signed by Henry A. Wise, Governor, and George W. Munford, Secretary, with the seal of the state of Virginia. Accompanied by Governor Wise's appointment of Charles P. Arnold as agent to demand and receive Joseph L. McCubbin, signed by Governor Wise and Secretary Munford, January 3, 1857; and statement of Charles P. Arnold before Thomas S. Wood, December 29, 1856. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Womack, George W. Letter to Geary. March 9, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>---- Letter to "Tommy." January 15, 1857. 4 pp.</p>
         <p>Woodbridge, F. H. Letter to Geary. January 3, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Woodruff, W. D. Letter to Geary. February 16, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Woods, Samuel. Letter to Geary. February 15, 1857. 2 pp.</p>
         <p>Wright, Joseph Albert. Letter to Geary. November 11, 1856. Signature only. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Wright, W. W. Letter to Geary. February 19, 1857. 1 p.</p>
         <p>Zigler, I. Telegram and letter to Geary. August 8, September 8, 1856. 2 pp.</p>  
      </odd>
      <controlaccess>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85071514"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Kansas -- History -- 1854-1861</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85071519"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part>Kansas -- Politics and government -- 1854-1861</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform source="local">
            <part>Legal instruments -- United States</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform source="local">
            <part>Petitions -- United State</part>
         </genreform>
         <occupation source="local">
            <part>Public officers -- Kansas</part>
         </occupation>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>Brown, George Washington, 1827-1906</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50034113" source="naf">
            <part>Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n50027269" source="naf">
            <part>Cooke, Philip St. George, 1809-1895</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>Geary, Edward R., II.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>Geary, Edward R., 1811-1886</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81118811" source="naf">
            <part>Geary, John White, 1819-1873</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/nr92027137"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>Gihon, John H.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>Haldeman, Cyrus S.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>Jones, Andrew J.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2005053518"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>McAllister, Richard</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part>McCaslin, Maxwell</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2010063138"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part>Russell, William Hepburn, 1812-1872</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88277191" source="naf">
            <part>Whittlesey, Elisha, 1783-1863</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no99069096"
                   source="local">
            <part>Kansas Territory. Governor (1856-1857 : Geary)</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref10" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
                  <quantity>0.8</quantity>
                  <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
               </physdescstructured>
               <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(2 boxes)</physdesc>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1862-1871</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_79a049021c9db7308a4a41277abc0343">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Series I, Correspondence, consists primarily of the official correspondence of John White Geary, Governor of Kansas Territory, 1856-57, and includes both letters to and from Geary. The letters from Governor Geary are copies, usually in his secretary's hand. The series also contains a few personal and family papers. The correspondence, with the exception of five letters written between 1862 and 1871, is dated from April 22, 1856, to December 4, 1857</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref12" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Apr-Jul</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_a75aaf5908739c227ad99d33e9f96a64"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a4fa50135c28176ac65edb847a06642a"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a75aaf5908739c227ad99d33e9f96a64">1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref13" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Aug 1-15</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_a50626cb0c5f125f00eb07ed1359c2ed"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_18e9d9533fcc54de36c25e235fa18449"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_a50626cb0c5f125f00eb07ed1359c2ed">2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref14" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Aug 16-30</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_c21746aab0d104c4081ddbe354522098"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_83f5d83600f486e6af3c118adfe2b53d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_c21746aab0d104c4081ddbe354522098">3</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref15" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Sep 1-10</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_bb8aa471a8a76aa435cc339f8b0de7f6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f1bedc80541fcbcad07bd0eaca2d8a66"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_bb8aa471a8a76aa435cc339f8b0de7f6">4</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref16" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Sep 11-16</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_3f02c8409ebd3753c1ff6e8ba2c8bdc7"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_11a749dc071b6bef3faa4c86511c1f5f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_3f02c8409ebd3753c1ff6e8ba2c8bdc7">5</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref17" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Sep 17-30</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_f3bac3a16bafe8697af1e16e1e75f3f1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_40dc039f1afab049bf407e9d5c0ded45"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f3bac3a16bafe8697af1e16e1e75f3f1">6</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref18" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Oct 1-15</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_392433c074fab652865cbc8ff6d152de"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d238408aaba7552fbc754e848ef31d52"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_392433c074fab652865cbc8ff6d152de">7</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Oct 16-26</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_b271026f3cdf2e9a1fe0b9add134a6d8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a8b753648b060a21fb82b17cf59c6838"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b271026f3cdf2e9a1fe0b9add134a6d8">8</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref20" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Oct 27-31</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_2de18c503740876c92b526c42b31258c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2073c6f4a1dd412ea45274df2585ea1d"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_2de18c503740876c92b526c42b31258c">9</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref21" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Nov 1-7</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_6ffa5dd80144bbe2c1b1fa3123ada1f0"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_aa50800d621e68cad2228f52a39372d4"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_6ffa5dd80144bbe2c1b1fa3123ada1f0">10</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref22" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Nov 8-14</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_dbb4d23d716ed50208d44bc90247b200"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_bf55201dc71bd3dacc6e674dbed16b87"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_dbb4d23d716ed50208d44bc90247b200">11</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref23" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Nov 14-30</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_eedda10ba9825aa9b8a371b276a1bcc3"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_6d571d0d56dd120a770f7f5868b52d01"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_eedda10ba9825aa9b8a371b276a1bcc3">12</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref24" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Dec 1-8</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_47e6919fc7708978a2fcdc98cc837c7c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_09e595559edc89b4734834e65a6895cc"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_47e6919fc7708978a2fcdc98cc837c7c">13</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref25" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856 Dec 9-31</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632571"
                             id="aspace_2749ad5c2c9226795914307a54ff88b4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">1</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3e35d41bf31f43caeab30fc87a5a3b8f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_2749ad5c2c9226795914307a54ff88b4">14</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref26" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Jan 1-9</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_ed06afb667f87cc739b1414421d739fd"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c193277f1b7838e095b817cc49808586"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_ed06afb667f87cc739b1414421d739fd">15</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref27" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Jan 10-18</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_27c0adf55675d224f808c0f5cab2dda9"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_eae090874437a16ff81ca0caf76aec15"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_27c0adf55675d224f808c0f5cab2dda9">16</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref28" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Jan 19-27</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_5ad7e4f29ba59e555d27f24c6db43fce"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_a481c361b70f66d5ce9059f77f6e9af7"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_5ad7e4f29ba59e555d27f24c6db43fce">17</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref29" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Jan 28-31</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_cf44ca1e87edbc3376c138ee8e09a08c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_2e644b052426d3d171468567f41a1413"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_cf44ca1e87edbc3376c138ee8e09a08c">18</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Feb 1-10</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_8679d25cd5268ab868f0577ba3b78b67"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_b4cf0bd318b5eda6f7806a5480c6152f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_8679d25cd5268ab868f0577ba3b78b67">19</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref31" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Feb 11-17</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_7f9707579d0e87623871de7a7da16a59"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_3f1c5689af77dc386ecfcc3757c41021"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7f9707579d0e87623871de7a7da16a59">20</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref32" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Feb 18-28</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_734e6d2dbaae5848c77a364b9bf3c921"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_e8843170f0ae54b204743466df4e5927"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_734e6d2dbaae5848c77a364b9bf3c921">21</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref33" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Mar 1-15</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_9f31e63190f6a94ed31417fc9a174c42"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_ef9191ea127b64ee5d8ec9600c8d7a92"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9f31e63190f6a94ed31417fc9a174c42">22</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref34" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Mar 16-31</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_078e046636aaf991281d8aeb3ee657b8"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_7407ebbfcc200f251cdcba13ac3cb39f"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_078e046636aaf991281d8aeb3ee657b8">23</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Apr</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_cbef7bc8064ff46915f95778aa6f03d5"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_f50e5aad227a20a12c603601d99d4b5a"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_cbef7bc8064ff46915f95778aa6f03d5">24</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref36" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 May-Jun</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_edd73947f2803d6857a0d0a4c758db6d"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_776791202b01b27ce47a892614cdab50"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_edd73947f2803d6857a0d0a4c758db6d">25</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref37" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Jul-Dec</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_7375c9197ea7ad3992534aa5aea6032a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_d2643e00252b219a04618c2d4993af68"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_7375c9197ea7ad3992534aa5aea6032a">26</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Notes on Kansas</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_0c88e910f86b1677104b58340c1727b4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_10a6332805ff514d3f37ea64a3a28632"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_0c88e910f86b1677104b58340c1727b4">27</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref39" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Newspaper clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856-57</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_f53e390707e0c2161ff3c2be98b6d2f6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_1e34029580cbe8e3075f5d665d03ba3e"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_f53e390707e0c2161ff3c2be98b6d2f6">28</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref40" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1862-71</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_949536ca2ed8c4e5f0f2795cd1f09131"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_61e07dd4ae8ea47b6f167b18aa88db14"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_949536ca2ed8c4e5f0f2795cd1f09131">29</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref41" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Family correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1855-57</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002091632589"
                             id="aspace_1d461c1d9be64bebcdec843f411eb218"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_5918bdde43cfa5478e3ec489b860954c"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1d461c1d9be64bebcdec843f411eb218">30</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref43" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Private Letter Book and Executive Minutes</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
                  <quantity>0.6</quantity>
                  <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
               </physdescstructured>
               <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(3 volumes)</physdesc>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856-1857</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_289fed99e9ab38ae89ec66d62c38c972">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Series II, Private Letter Book and Executive Minutes, consists of three bound volumes kept by Governor Geary's private secretary, John H. Gihon. In two volumes, labelled Executive Minutes, Gihon copied offical letters to and from the governor, his messages to the legislature, other official acts, and a chronological record of events. A third, unlabelled volume contains copies of Geary's letters and reports to various federal officials, including Presidents Pierce and Buchanan</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref45" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Executive minutes and official correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856-57</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002094482149"
                             id="aspace_4d54343e4c2135b58c75e7822ab171e6"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_c11a3381234d33b45c11499d2ef075f5"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_4d54343e4c2135b58c75e7822ab171e6">Vol. 1</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref46" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Executive minutes and official correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857 Feb-Mar</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002094482149"
                             id="aspace_1424764264b6c2ac48120cf07552296d"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_beac76766425f802719d7431e07dbc06"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_1424764264b6c2ac48120cf07552296d">Vol. 2</container>
               </did>
            </c>
            <c id="ref47" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Official correspondence (entitled "Governor Geary's Private Diary, kept by his Secretary")</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856-57</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002094482149"
                             id="aspace_9cdc7750d835f4d9abcd6131738d8ffb"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">3</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9c868f484710c8eba8fbbdf135bbf2bc"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_9cdc7750d835f4d9abcd6131738d8ffb">Vol. 3</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref49" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Transcript</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
               <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
                  <quantity>0.2</quantity>
                  <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
               </physdescstructured>
               <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(1 volume)</physdesc>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856-1857</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2f19a6aa3ef201b93b5a12a5d936dac4">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Series III, Transcript, consists of a typewritten transcript of some of the more important papers in the collection. The transcript is in a single volume</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref51" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Transcript: "A collection of autograph letters and documents written to and by John White Geary during his governorship of Kansas Territory"</unittitle>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1856-57</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002094482131"
                             id="aspace_adb05ed57b6df2337405f48f7d2c44ae"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">4</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
