<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/YaleArchivesSpace/EAD3-to-PDF-UA/master/ead3-yale.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="https://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.genetjean">beinecke.genetjean</recordid>
      <otherrecordid localtype="BIB">15982112</otherrecordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Jean Genet Papers </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Jean Genet Papers</titleproper>
            <author>Sandrine Guérin</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="telephone">(203) 432-2977 </addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>September 2022, January 2025</date>
            <num>GEN MSS 1739</num>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <controlnote localtype="onsite">
               <p>Boxes: 1-22</p>
            </controlnote>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-BR</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>English</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>Finding aid description and metadata in Archives at Yale are licensed under a CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication. This means that anyone may copy, modify, and distribute this descriptive metadata without restriction or permission. The CC0 license is explained in full on the Creative Commons website: <ref href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0) Public Domain Dedication</ref>. More information is available on our <ref href="https://archives.yale.edu/help">Help page</ref>.</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>under_revision</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2025-02-18T23:07:11-05:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace yale-rebased-v3.3.1</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Tuesday February 18, 2025 at 23:07</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="revised"/>
            <eventdatetime>December 2024</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="unknown"/>
            <agent/>
            <eventdescription>Finding aid under revision to reflect comprehensive rearrangement, reprocessing, and processing and description of latest acquisitions (2023-genm-0010, 2023-genm-0023, 2023-genm-0035, and 2024-genm-0031)</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc altrender="/repositories/11/resources/12887" level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Jean Genet papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>GEN MSS 1739</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="fre">French</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>12.75</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">22 boxes</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1940">1940</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1988">1988</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <unitdatestructured label="creation" unitdatetype="bulk">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1944">1944</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1983">1983</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_ea1588405f2f355e1542d7988f39f9b6">The collection consists of manuscript drafts and corrected typescripts as well as galley and page proofs for works by Jean Genet, 1952-1982, including <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Le Balcon</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Les Nègres</part>
            </title>, and <title>
               <part>Le Langage de la muraille: cent ans jour après jour</part>
            </title>. It also contains manuscripts with sketches by the author and artworks on paper by others, including two hand-colored lithographs by Alberto Giacometti, created as a cover illustration for <title>
               <part>Le Balcon</part>
            </title>.</abstract>
         <origination label="Source">
            <corpname relator="bsl" rules="local" source="local">
               <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Librairie Benoit Forgeot</part>
            </corpname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname relator="aut">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Genet, Jean, 1910-1986</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_feaf2bca0040e5d824bdd03ecd6cc88d">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_902816b25c6fe0ac0cd98b4d786ba132">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased from Librairie Benoit Forgeot on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2021.</p>
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_964d3642ded0612661ebc7e239335c60">
         <head>Jean Genet (1910-1986)</head>
         <p>Jean Genet (1910-1986) was a French novelist, poet, playwright, essayist, and political activist.</p>
         <p>Born in Paris, France, Genet was the son of Camille Gabrielle Genet, a 22-year-old single maidservant. Struggling to support herself, she placed her son in the care of social services when he was just seven months old. In July 1911, Genet became a ward of the state and was sent to live with a foster family in Alligny-en-Morvan. Although he excelled in school, he also engaged in petty theft during his youth. In September 1926, after multiple criminal offenses, Genet was sent to the Penal Colony of Mettray. In March 1929, he enlisted in the French Army in order to gain an early release from Mettray. Genet served in Lebanon, Syria, Morocco, and Algeria, but deserted his post in June 1936. He then wandered around Europe as a vagabond, petty thief, and prostitute—experiences later recounted in his book Le <title>
               <part>Journal du voleur</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Thief's Journal</part>
            </title>). Genet returned to France in July 1937, continuing to live off thefts (including stealing and reselling rare books), and spent several years in and out of prison. In 1938, he was dishonorably discharged from the Army for indecency.</p>
         <p>Genet began writing during his periods of incarceration. In 1942, he completed the poem <title>
               <part>Un Condamné à Mort</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Man Sentenced to Death</part>
            </title>) and his first novel, <title>
               <part>Notre-Dame-des-Fleurs</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>Our Lady of the Flowers</part>
            </title>). His work began to gain recognition within literary circles. Paul Morihien, secretary to Jean Cocteau, and Robert Denoël, an associate of Morihien, signed a contract with Genet in March 1943, and published <title>
               <part>Notre-Dame-des-Fleurs</part>
            </title> in a limited, clandestine edition later that year. Around this time, Genet also contacted Marc Barbezat, owner of the publishing house L'Arbalète, who would become one of his primary publishers.</p>
         <p>Between 1944 and 1949, Genet wrote four novels—<title>
               <part>Miracle de la rose</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>Miracle of the Rose</part>
            </title>), <title>
               <part>Pompes funèbres</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>Funeral Rites</part>
            </title>), <title>
               <part>Querelle de Brest</part>
            </title>, and <title>
               <part>Journal d'un voleur</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>A Thief's Journal</part>
            </title>). In 1948, Genet was convicted of theft. Having already been convicted ten times, he faced an automatic sentence of life imprisonment. Prominent figures, including Jean Cocteau and Jean-Paul Sartre, appealed on his behalf, ultimately securing a presidential pardon.</p>
         <p>After turning to theater, Genet wrote <title>
               <part>Haute Surveillance</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>Deathwatch</part>
            </title>) and <title>
               <part>Les Bonnes</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Maids</part>
            </title>) in 1947, followed by <title>
               <part>Splendid's</part>
            </title> in 1948. Throughout the 1950s, he focused on writing plays that were experimental and increasingly political: <title>
               <part>Le Balcon</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Balcony</part>
            </title>), <title>
               <part>Les Nègres</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Blacks</part>
            </title>), and <title>
               <part>Elle</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>Her</part>
            </title>) in 1955, and <title>
               <part>Les Paravents</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Screens</part>
            </title>) between 1956 and 1961, a play about the Algerian War of Independence. Directed by Roger Blin, <title>
               <part>Les Paravents</part>
            </title> premiered at the Odéon Theatre in 1966.</p>
         <p>Genet also wrote several screenplays. In 1950, he wrote and directed the short film <title>
               <part>Un Chant d'Amour</part>
            </title>, depicting the fantasies of a gay male prisoner and his prison warden. In 1951, he wrote a screenplay in the form of a story with dialogues, <title>
               <part>Les Rêves interdits ou l'autre versant du rêve</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Forbidden Dreams or the Other Side of the Dream</part>
            </title>). The story was adapted into the 1966 film <title>
               <part>Mademoiselle</part>
            </title> by Tony Richardson. Genet also wrote the screenplay for <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Penal Colony</part>
            </title>) (1952–1954); <title>
               <part>Divine</part>
            </title>, an adaptation of his first novel <title>
               <part>Notre-Dame-des-Fleurs</part>
            </title> (for David Bowie in 1975); <title>
               <part>La Nuit venue/Le Bleu de L'oeil</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Night Has Come/The Blue of the Eye</part>
            </title>) (1976–1978); and <title>
               <part>Le Langage de la muraille: cent ans jour après jour</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>The Language of the Walls: One Hundred Years Day After Day</part>
            </title>), a TV series for Antenne 2 that was abandoned in 1982 before production.</p>
         <p>After the completion of <title>
               <part>Les Paravents</part>
            </title>, Genet retreated from the literary scene. He became severely depressed following the death of his companion Abdallah Bentaga in 1964, and attempted suicide in Italy during the spring of 1967. He re-entered public life at a time of social unrest and wrote an homage to Daniel Cohn-Bendit after the events of May 1968. He also participated in demonstrations highlighting the living conditions of immigrants in France.</p>
         <p>Genet felt a strong sense of solidarity with the oppressed and marginalized, both in France and abroad, and his political engagement took many forms over his lifetime. In the 1970s, he worked with Michel Foucault's Groupe d'information sur les prisons (GIP), visited members of the Black Panther Party in the United States, supported Angela Davis and George Jackson, and later spent time in Palestinian refugee camps. Genet also wrote articles and essays and gave speeches in support of revolutionary movements. In 1983, Genet began <title>
               <part>Un Captif amoureux</part>
            </title> (<title>
               <part>Prisoner of Love</part>
            </title>), which recounts his experiences with Palestinian fighters and Black Panther Party members. He corrected the proofs just before his death in Paris in April 1986.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <bioghist id="aspace_c3dee642114c82990721d3b9f2d1dcc4">
         <head>Jean Genet Writing Process and Custodial Histories </head>
         <p>
            <title>
               <part>Genet's Writing Method</part>
            </title>
         </p>
         <p>Jean Genet's working method was distinctive. He typically wrote in school notebooks and would hand his drafts over to typists. After receiving the typed text, he would revise it, often by adding new passages. He did this either by annotating the typed pages, inserting handwritten additions on loose sheets, or pasting autograph corrections onto the typed document, essentially creating a new manuscript. The revised version would then be typed again, and the resulting typescript would be corrected, enriched, and restructured. This method highlights the importance of both handwritten and typed manuscripts in Genet's writing process. Genet's method also involved mixing earlier drafts, whether handwritten or typed, making it difficult to trace the precise evolution of his works.</p>
         <p>Several groups of materials in the collection offer an in-depth look at this process. For example, the materials related to <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title> in the Jean Genet papers provide valuable insight into both his writing process and the history of one of his works. Genet wrote the screenplay for <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title> between 1952 and 1954, but he set it aside in 1956. He later began writing a theatrical version in 1958, only to destroy the final version after the suicide of his partner, Abdallah Bentaga, in 1964. However, two sets of drafts of <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title> survived: one he had given to his publisher, Marc Barbezat, in 1963, and another to his literary agent and American translator, Bernard Frechtman. In 1990, Barbezat acquired Frechtman's copy at auction, using both drafts to create a posthumous theatrical version of <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title>, which was published in 1994 by L'Arbalète.</p>
         <p>
            <title>
               <part>Custodial Histories</part>
            </title>
         </p>
         <p>Drafts of Genet's works were often kept in the papers of his publishers and editors (including Paul Morihien, Marc Barbezat, and Monique Lange), literary agent and translator Bernard Frechtman, as well as patrons and friends, such as collector Jacques Guérin and attorney Roland Dumas. Over time, much of this literary material was dispersed through public auctions or private sales. 
Significant material related to Genet has been acquired over the decades by art collectors and bibliophiles Pierre Bergé (1930-2017) and Geneviève and Jean Paul Kahn (1931-2018). These two important collections were gradually dispersed through multiple auctions between 2015 and October 2024 for Bergé—whose proceeds went to charity and the Pierre Bergé-Yves Saint Laurent Foundation—and from November 2019 to June 2024 for the Kahns. Materials from both collections are in the holdings of the Beinecke.</p>
         <p>Another key custodian of Genet's legacy was attorney Roland Dumas (1922-2024). In 1986, just two weeks before his death, Genet entrusted two suitcases filled with a mix of personal artifacts, manuscripts, and notes, to his close friend. These materials are mostly dated from the period 1967-1982, and include works that were thought to have been destroyed or had been unknown, such as drafts of the filmscripts for <title>
               <part>La Nuit</part>
            </title> and <title>
               <part>Divine</part>
            </title>. Dumas donated the suitcases to L'Institut mémoires de l'édition contemporaine (IMEC) in November 2019, where they joined the Fonds Jean Genet at the institute.</p>
         <p>The Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library holds a substantial collection of Genet's papers. The materials come from multiple creators, owners, and collectors. To facilitate the tracing of provenance, information regarding the custodial history of specific groups of materials or individual manuscripts is included in the collection description.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite id="aspace_e8b3efd33268a16a63af12ac74ae0cb9">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Collection of Jean Genet Drafts and Proofs. General Collection, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_a3f8cfe7b80dbbf83163bb60700151c6">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected. The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>These materials have been arranged and described according to national and local standards. For more information, please refer to the Beinecke Manuscript Unit Processing Manual.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_a69ac77a4653d322a2c75e50616e4e6c">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Material closed for reprocessing (expected to open end of January 2025). Several recent acquisitions are being added to the collection, including manuscripts and typescripts of <title>
               <part>Notre-Dame des fleurs</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Miracle de la rose</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>La Galère</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Pompes Funèbre</part>
            </title>s, <title>
               <part>Les Bonnes</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Journal du voleur</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Splendid's</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>L'enfant criminel</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Divine</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Esquisse en 28 stations</part>
            </title>.</p>
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_4241218fd34d815c136ce83a262ad51f">
         <head>Content Description</head>
         <p>The collection consists of manuscript drafts and corrected typescripts as well as galley and page proofs for works by Jean Genet, 1952-1982, including <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Le Balcon</part>
            </title>, <title>
               <part>Les Nègres</part>
            </title>, and <title>
               <part>Le Langage de la muraille: cent ans jour après jour</part>
            </title>. It also contains manuscripts with sketches by the author and artworks on paper by others, including two hand-colored lithographs by Alberto Giacometti, created as a cover illustration for <title>
               <part>Le Balcon</part>
            </title>.</p>
         <p>Material related to <title>
               <part>Le Bagne</part>
            </title> consists of a completed film screenplay, approximately 1952-1954, and fragments of a play script, between 1958 and 1963.</p>
         <p>Material related to <title>
               <part>Le Balcon</part>
            </title> contains drafts, autograph manuscripts, typescripts, and corrected proofs, 1955-1956, for the first edition of Le Balcon published in 1956 by L'Arbalète and Marc Barbezat.</p>
         <p>Material related to <title>
               <part>Les Nègres</part>
            </title> includes multiple drafts, an unpublished preface to the play, and galley proofs, 1955-1957.</p>
         <p>Material related to Le <title>
               <part>Langage de la muraille: cent ans jour après jour</part>
            </title> includes preparatory documents, and manuscript and typescript drafts for the screenplay, approximately 1981-1982, bound in three volumes.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_dc39e36d6f6f78e5ffed09d9b0197a64">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Collection of Jean Genet Drafts and Proofs is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <occupation source="local">
            <part localtype="occupation">Authors</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">20th Century</part>
         </occupation>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85009907"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Authors, French</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051201"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Colonies</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051450"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Politics and government</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051483"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Politics and government</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">1870-1940</part>
         </geogname>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051792"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">French drama</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">20th Century</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85051871"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">French literature</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">20th Century</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85064628"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Imperialism</part>
         </subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Juvenile detention homes</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh97005745" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Male homosexuality in literature</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh85098670" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Paternalism</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh85099359" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Penal colonies</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh94007561" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Penal colonies in literature</part>
         </subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Political activists</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
         </subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Prison industries</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh2008108759" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Prisoners</part>
            <part localtype="genre_form">Fiction</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh94008444" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Race relations in literature</part>
         </subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Reformatories</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">France</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh85123918" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Social change</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh94008625" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Social control in literature</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh85123980" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Social norms</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/sh94008634" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Social norms in literature</part>
         </subject>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300033973" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Drawings (visual works)</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300041379" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Lithographs</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300200438" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Page proofs</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300201028" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Plays (performed works)</part>
         </genreform>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026494" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Television scripts</part>
         </genreform>
         <subject source="local">
            <part localtype="topical">LGBTQ resource</part>
         </subject>
         <persname identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/n88669253"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Barbezat, Marc, 1913-1999</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://viaf.org/viaf/822555" source="viaf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Bary, Antoine de, 1936-</part>
         </persname>
         <persname rules="aacr">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Demetz, M. (Frédéric-Auguste), 1796-1873</part>
         </persname>
         <persname>
            <part localtype="agent_person">Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://viaf.org/viaf/171468086" source="viaf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Lefèvre-Pontalis, Jean-François, 1920-2000</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="https://lccn.loc.gov/no2009058549" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Morihien, Paul, 1917-</part>
         </persname>
         <persname>
            <part localtype="agent_person">Tavernier, Bertrand</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname rules="aacr">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Société nationale de télévision en couleur "Antenne 2"</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname rules="aacr">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Colonie agricole et pénitentiaire de Mettray</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
