<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.cohenlk">beinecke.cohenlk</recordid>
      <otherrecordid localtype="BIB">9344905</otherrecordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Cohen (Lucy Kramer) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>Jennifer Meehan, Jonathan Harmon, and Stephanie Bredbenner</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2010, 2020</date>
            <num>WA MSS S-2635</num>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <controlnote>
               <p>This finding aid, which is compliant with the Yale EAD Best Practice Guidelines, Version 1.0., has a MARC record in Yale's ILS with the following bib number: <num localtype="Orbis-bib">9344905</num>.</p>
            </controlnote>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-BR</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>Finding aid written in English.</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <localcontrol localtype="findaidstatus">
         <term>in_progress</term>
      </localcontrol>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2020-10-21T03:10:54+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.7.1.yale.20200820</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Wednesday October 21, 2020 at 03:10</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc altrender="/repositories/11/resources/1295" level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Lucy Kramer Cohen papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>WA MSS S-2635</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            <language langcode="ger">German</language>
            <language langcode="yid">Yiddish</language>
            <descriptivenote>
               <p>Chiefly in English, some materials in German and Yiddish.</p>
            </descriptivenote>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>52.78</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(122 boxes) + 7 record album storage</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1900-2006"
                             label="creation"
                             unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="2006">2006</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_331c125d4d636ff096df2751eb436140">The collection documents the life and career of Lucy Kramer Cohen, particularly her work for several federal agencies, contributions to <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Handbook of Federal Indian Law</part>
            </title>, and her political and advocacy work. Professional papers document Kramer Cohen's work for the Department of the Interior, Department of Agriculture, National War Labor Board, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Department of Labor, National Science Foundation, Public Health Service, Helen Gahagan Douglas, and Human Relations Area Files. The collection also contains writings by Kramer Cohen and her husband Felix S. Cohen and correspondence concerning Lucy Kramer Cohen's editing of her husband's writings and management of his literary estate. Also present are correspondence, reports, clippings, and printed material concerning the Cohens' involvement with various political and social causes.  Material relating to Kramer Cohen's art projects includes correspondence and notes documenting her work with Italian artist Pietro Lazzari.  Finally, personal and family papers include personal correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia concerning the Cohens, their daughters, and their extended family.</abstract>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2014000628"
                      source="naf">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79066570"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1a7bed86bafa0dad451d22eb03d6d261"
                      localtype="InProcessSpecColl">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>In-process collection. As of October 2019, this collection is closed to readers temporarily, and will reopen when processing is complete. For more information, please consult the Closed Collections Schedule on the Beinecke Web site, at www.library.yale.edu/beinecke</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d7b45af4976d5b389ab7071e36b104fc">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Karen Holmes and Gene Tweraser, 2009, 2014, 2017.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <arrangement id="aspace_8f5e7711795baaa3f198fdb39b1321ba">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Organized into six series: I. Professional Papers, 1927-1989. II. Writings, 1931-2005. III. Political and Advocacy Activities, 1920-1995. IV. Art Projects, 1926-2006. V. Personal and Family Papers, 1900-2005. VI. Printed Materials, 1902-1995.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <bioghist id="aspace_176d631b22218f4bf34746ceccae11d0">
         <head>Lucy Kramer Cohen (1907-2007)</head>
         <p>Lucy Kramer Cohen was born to Aaron Kramer and Annie Frankel Kramer in Brooklyn, New York in 1907. She graduated from Barnard College in 1928 and earned her master's degree in mathematics and anthropology from Columbia University in 1929, where she studied under Franz Boas. She married Felix S. Cohen, a lawyer, in 1931, and they had two daughters, Karen and Gene. Kramer Cohen worked as an unpaid assistant with her husband in the United States Department of the Interior, helping to draft the Indian Reorganization Act of 1934 and <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Handbook of Federal Indian Law</part>
            </title> in 1942. Kramer Cohen also worked for several other federal agencies from the 1930s until her retirement in 1989, including the Department of Agriculture, War Labor Board, Department of Labor, National Science Foundation, and the Public Health Service. She officially retired in 1977 but continued to work on annual contracts until 1989. </p>
         <p>In addition to her government work, Kramer Cohen was on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas (D-Calif.) during Douglas's three terms in the House from 1944 to 1950 and also worked on Douglas's campaign for senator in 1950. Additionally, she did research work for anthropologists in Washington in between her government jobs, including research and writing for Interior Secretary Harold Ickes.  Kramer Cohen also worked for the Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations and as an editor of the Human Relations Area Files.</p>
         <p>Kramer Cohen collected, edited, and published her husband's work as <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Legal Conscience</part>
            </title> (New Haven, Yale University Press: 1960) after his death in 1953.  She also worked on editing her husband's writings about Puerto Rico into a book that was never published, in addition to managing the copyright and reprint rights of his writings after his death.</p>
         <p>Kramer Cohen and her husband were involved in many political and social causes and organizations, including Native American rights, the Socialist Party, anti-fascist organizations, and the League for Industrial Democracy.  She served on the board of directors of the Association on American Indian Affairs from 1956 until 1994. In her later years, she took up painting and worked to promote the work of Italian artist and sculptor Pietro Lazzari.  She died of a stroke in 2007.</p>  
      </bioghist>
  
  
  
  
      <prefercite id="aspace_c5a86cf8757f2efbc9336a4b31541425">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers. Yale Collection of Western Americana, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_0b9ae264cc952b952afd876e273dfedd">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected. The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>This finding aid may be updated periodically to account for new acquisitions to the collection and/or revisions in arrangement and description.</p>  
      </processinfo>
  
  
  
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_79d2d2f7ec4e53e27310757a2d509f57">
         <head>Associated Materials</head>
         <p>
            <ref actuate="onrequest"
                 href="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.cohen"
                 linkrole="text/html"
                 show="new">Felix S. Cohen Papers</ref> (WA MSS S-1325). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_baf2c059c32e56d59938f1243faae6df">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection documents the life and career of Lucy Kramer Cohen, particularly her work for several federal agencies, contributions to <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Handbook of Federal Indian Law</part>
            </title>, and her political and advocacy work.  Professional papers primarily consist of correspondence, memoranda, reports, research notes, printed materials, and other papers relating to Kramer Cohen's work for the Department of the Interior, Department of Agriculture, National War Labor Board, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Department of Labor, National Science Foundation, and Public Health Service.  Other professional papers include speeches and notes from Kramer Cohen's time as a staffer and speechwriter for Helen Gahagan Douglas and memoranda and reports on Korea, Germany, and Iran from her time as an editor of the Human Relations Area Files.  Other professional papers relate to Kramer Cohen's work as a high school math teacher, research jobs, job searches, and the federal government's loyalty investigation concerning Kramer Cohen in the 1950s. </p>
         <p>The collection also contains writings by Kramer Cohen and her husband Felix S. Cohen, including notes and correspondence concerning the publication of <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Legal Conscience</part>
            </title>, Felix S. Cohen's correspondence concerning Puerto Rico, and correspondence concerning Lucy Kramer Cohen's editing of her husband's writings and management of his literary estate.  Also present are correspondence, reports, clippings, and printed material concerning the Cohens' involvement with political and social causes, including board meeting minutes and cassette tapes relating to the Association on American Indian Affairs.  Material relating to Kramer Cohen's art projects includes correspondence and notes documenting her work with Italian artist Pietro Lazzari and copies of the newsletter of the Washington Water Color Association, which she edited. Finally, personal and family papers include personal correspondence, photographs, and memorabilia concerning the Cohens, their daughters, and their extended family.  Includes audiovisual recordings of Felix S. Cohen's memorial service and legal and financial records concerning the estate of Lucy Kramer Cohen's father Aaron Kramer.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9b63df9179140200d077272582829840">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
  
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026398"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Civil service</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85065282"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Indians of North America</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Government relations</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">1934-</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85065315"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Indians of North America</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Legal status, laws, etc.</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh90005036"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Anthropologists</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            <part localtype="topical">Women anthropologists</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140464"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Politics and government</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">1933-1945</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300028045" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Audiovisual materials</part>
         </genreform>
         <subject identifier="sh2008101175" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Collective bargaining</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="sh85028110" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Collective labor agreements</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="sh2010101286" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Medical personnel</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Supply and demand</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh2008101807"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Cost and standard of living</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="sh85108666" source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Public health personnel</part>
         </subject>
         <genreform source="local">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Photographs</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </genreform>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2014000628"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79066570"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82094028" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 (Felix S. Cohen's Handbook of federal Indian law)</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 (Legal conscience)</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81090308" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1900-1980</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no96039639"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Lazzari, Pietro, 1898-1979</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81086457"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Association on American Indian Affairs</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126051" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. Department of the Interior</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85304801"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945)</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79096730" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. Public Health Service</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79008243" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. Department of Agriculture</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="https://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80004214"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations </part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79029796" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. Department of Labor</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79054594"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Human Relations Area Files, inc</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79005681" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">National Science Foundation (U.S.)</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79058629" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">League for Industrial Democracy</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
