<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.cohenlk">beinecke.cohenlk</recordid>
      <otherrecordid localtype="BIB">9344905</otherrecordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Cohen (Lucy Kramer) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>by Jennifer Meehan and Jonathan Harmon</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2010</date>
            <num>WA MSS S-2635</num>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <controlnote>
               <p>This finding aid, which is compliant with the Yale EAD Best Practice Guidelines, Version 1.0., has a MARC record in Yale's ILS with the following bib number: <num localtype="Orbis-bib">9344905</num>.</p>
            </controlnote>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-BR</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>Finding aid written in English.</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <rightsdeclaration>
         <abbr>CC0</abbr>
         <citation href="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"/>
         <descriptivenote>
            <p>CC0 1.0 Universal (CC0 1.0)</p>
         </descriptivenote>
      </rightsdeclaration>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2020-09-02T06:25:04+00:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace 2.7.1.yale.20200820</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Wednesday September  2, 2020 at 06:25</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc altrender="/repositories/11/resources/1295" level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>Lucy Kramer Cohen papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>WA MSS S-2635</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>43.54</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(49 boxes) + 7 record album storage</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured altrender="circa 1900-2005"
                             label="creation"
                             unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1900">1900</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="2005">2005</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <abstract id="aspace_331c125d4d636ff096df2751eb436140">The Lucy Kramer Cohen papers document her decades-long career in the federal government, including her contributions to The Handbook of Federal Indian Law and her work on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas and for the War Labor Board and the Public Health Service, as well as her various professional activities and affiliations as an anthropologist and later as an artist, including her work with the artist and sculptor Pietro Lazzari. The collection consists largely of professional correspondence and memoranda, reports and analyses for various government agencies and projects, conference proceedings, printed material stemming from Kramer Cohen's government employment and organizational affiliations, manuscripts for Felix S. Cohen's The Legal Conscience, which she edited, and various employment papers, including applications, wage records, CV drafts, and employer recommendations. Also found are personal and family papers, which include correspondence between and received by Kramer Cohen and Felix S. Cohen, clippings of obituaries, material relating to the memorial service for Felix S. Cohen, legal and financial documents relating to Kramer Cohen's father's estate and affairs, and property records. Other papers of Felix S. Cohen include research material, clippings, and correspondence relating to Puerto Rico and the Spanish Civil War.  Audiovisual materials include a film and reel-to-reel recordings of of Felix Cohen and audiodiscs of his memorial service.</abstract>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2014000628"
                      source="naf">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79066570"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">
               <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_d7b45af4976d5b389ab7071e36b104fc">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Gift of Karen Holmes and Gene Tweraser, 2009, 2014.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <userestrict id="aspace_9b63df9179140200d077272582829840">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_c5a86cf8757f2efbc9336a4b31541425">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>Lucy Kramer Cohen Papers. Yale Collection of Western Americana, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_0b9ae264cc952b952afd876e273dfedd">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Collections are processed to a variety of levels, depending on the work necessary to make them usable, their perceived research value, the availability of staff, competing priorities, and whether or not further accruals are expected. The library attempts to provide a basic level of preservation and access for all collections, and does more extensive processing of higher priority collections as time and resources permit.</p>
         <p>This collection received a preliminary level of processing at the time of acquisition, including rehousing in acid-free boxes and folders. Material in the collection has yet to be organized. Folder titles appearing in the contents list were transcribed from original folders, but have not been verified against the contents of the folders in all cases. Otherwise, folder titles were supplied by staff during preliminary processing.</p>
         <p>This finding aid may be updated periodically to account for new acquisitions to the collection and/or revisions in arrangement and description.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_79d2d2f7ec4e53e27310757a2d509f57">
         <head>Associated Materials</head>
         <p>
            <ref actuate="onrequest"
                 href="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.cohen"
                 linkrole="text/html"
                 show="new">Felix S. Cohen Papers</ref> (WA MSS S-1325). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>
         <p>
            <ref actuate="onrequest"
                 href="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.cohenadd"
                 linkrole="text/html"
                 show="new">Felix S. Cohen Papers Addition</ref> (WA MSS S-2602). Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <bioghist id="aspace_176d631b22218f4bf34746ceccae11d0">
         <head>Lucy Kramer Cohen (1907-2007)</head>
         <p>Lucy Kramer Cohen was born in Brooklyn, New York, graduated from Barnard College in 1928, and earned her Master's degree in 1929 in mathematics and anthropology at Columbia University. She married Felix S. Cohen, a lawyer, in 1931, and they had two daughters, Karen and Gene. Kramer Cohen worked as an unpaid assistant with her husband in the United States Department of the Interior, helping to draft the Indian Reorganization Act of 1934 and The Handbook of Federal Indian Law in 1942. She was on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas (D-Calif.) during Douglas's three terms in the House from 1944 to 1950. Kramer Cohen also worked for the War Labor Board, the Office of Price Administration, the State Department and the Public Health Service, where she wrote and edited reports in its office of data analysis and management. She also did research work for anthropologists in Washington in between her government jobs, and did researching and writing for Interior Secretary Harold Ickes. She collected, edited, and published her husband's work as <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Legal Conscience</part>
            </title> (New Haven, Yale University Press: 1960) after his death in 1953. She served on the board of directors of the Association on American Indian Affairs from 1961 to 1994. Kramer Cohen officially retired from the federal government in 1977, but continued to work on contract until her actual retirement in 1989. In her later years, she took up drawing and painting, and served as editor of the Washington Watercolor Association newsletter. She died of a stroke in 2007.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_baf2c059c32e56d59938f1243faae6df">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The Lucy Kramer Cohen papers document her decades-long career in the federal government, including her contributions to The Handbook of Federal Indian Law and her work on the staff of Representative Helen Gahagan Douglas and for the War Labor Board and the Public Health Service. They also document her various professional activities and affiliations as an anthropologist and later as an artist, including her work with the Association on American Indian Affairs and with the artist and sculptor Pietro Lazzari. The collection consists largely of professional correspondence and memoranda, reports and analysis for various government agencies and projects, conference proceedings, printed material stemming from Kramer Cohen's government employment and organizational affiliations, manuscripts for Felix S. Cohen's <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Legal Conscience</part>
            </title>, which she edited, and various employment papers, including applications, wage records, CV drafts, and employer recommendations. Also present are personal and family papers, which include correspondence between and received by Kramer Cohen and Felix S. Cohen, clippings of obituaries, material relating to the memorial service for Felix S. Cohen, legal and financial documents relating to Kramer Cohen's father's estate and affairs, and property records. Other papers of Felix S. Cohen include research material, clippings, and correspondence relating to Puerto Rico and the Spanish Civil War.  Audiovisual materials include a film and reel-to-reel recordings of of Felix Cohen and audiodiscs of his memorial service.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_8f5e7711795baaa3f198fdb39b1321ba">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Organized into two groupings: November 2009 Acquisition; and June 2014 Acquisition.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_5581fad4867971c2d0389cafebe2350c">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>
         <p>Boxes 49-56 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_1a7bed86bafa0dad451d22eb03d6d261"
                      localtype="InProcessSpecColl">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>In-process collection. As of October 2019, this collection is closed to readers temporarily, and will reopen when processing is complete. For more information, please consult the Closed Collections Schedule on the Beinecke Web site, at www.library.yale.edu/beinecke</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
  
      <controlaccess>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026398"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Civil service</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85065282"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Indians of North America</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Government relations</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">1934-</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85065315"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Indians of North America</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Legal status, laws, etc.</part>
         </subject>
         <subject identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh90005036"
                  source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="topical">Anthropologists</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <subject source="local">
            <part localtype="topical">Women anthropologists</part>
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85140464"
                   source="lcsh">
            <part localtype="geographic">United States</part>
            <part localtype="topical">Politics and government</part>
            <part localtype="temporal">1933-1945</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform identifier="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300028045" source="aat">
            <part localtype="genre_form">Audiovisual materials</part>
         </genreform>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2014000628"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Lucy Kramer, 1907-2007</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79066570"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82094028" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 (Felix S. Cohen's Handbook of federal Indian law)</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="local">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Cohen, Felix S., 1907-1953 (Legal conscience)</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81090308" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Douglas, Helen Gahagan, 1900-1980</part>
         </persname>
         <persname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no96039639"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_person">Lazzari, Pietro, 1898-1979</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n81086457"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">Association on American Indian Affairs</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n80126051" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. Department of the Interior</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85304801"
                   rules="aacr"
                   source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945)</part>
         </corpname>
         <corpname identifier="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79096730" source="naf">
            <part localtype="agent_corporate_entity">United States. Public Health Service</part>
         </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc/>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
