<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/SAA-SDT/EAD3/master/ead3.rng"
      type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<ead xmlns="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/">
   <control countryencoding="iso3166-1"
            dateencoding="iso8601"
            langencoding="iso639-2b"
            relatedencoding="marc"
            repositoryencoding="iso15511"
            scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <recordid instanceurl="http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.usher">beinecke.usher</recordid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the George F. Usher Papers
 </titleproper>
            <titleproper localtype="filing">Usher (George F.) Papers</titleproper>
            <author>by Beinecke Staff</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>P. O. Box 208330</addressline>
               <addressline>New Haven, CT 06520-8330</addressline>
               <addressline localtype="email">beinecke.library@yale.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>
                  <ref href="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       linktitle="http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/"
                       show="new">http://beinecke.library.yale.edu/</ref>
               </addressline>
            </address>
            <date>2012</date>
            <num>GEN MSS 855</num>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <controlnote>
               <p>This finding aid, which is compliant with the Yale EAD Best Practice Guidelines, Version 1.0., has a MARC record in Yale's ILS with the following bib number: <num localtype="Orbis-bib">10508215</num>.</p>
            </controlnote>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <maintenancestatus value="derived"/>
      <maintenanceagency countrycode="US">
         <agencycode>US-CtY-BR</agencycode>
         <agencyname>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</agencyname>
      </maintenanceagency>
      <languagedeclaration>
         <language>Finding aid written in English.</language>
         <script scriptcode="Latn">Latin</script>
      </languagedeclaration>
      <conventiondeclaration>
         <abbr>dacs</abbr>
         <citation>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</citation>
      </conventiondeclaration>
      <maintenancehistory>
         <maintenanceevent>
            <eventtype value="derived"/>
            <eventdatetime>2018-04-23T23:38:34-04:00</eventdatetime>
            <agenttype value="machine"/>
            <agent>ArchivesSpace v2.2.0</agent>
            <eventdescription>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on Monday April 23, 2018 at 23:38</eventdescription>
         </maintenanceevent>
      </maintenancehistory>
   </control>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <unittitle>George F. Usher papers</unittitle>
         <unitid>GEN MSS 855</unitid>
         <repository>
            <corpname>
               <part>Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library</part>
            </corpname>
         </repository>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
            <quantity>0.83</quantity>
            <unittype>Linear Feet</unittype>
         </physdescstructured>
         <physdesc localtype="container_summary">(2 boxes)</physdesc>
         <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
            <daterange>
               <fromdate standarddate="1852">1852</fromdate>
               <todate standarddate="1877">1877</todate>
            </daterange>
         </unitdatestructured>
         <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1852-1877</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_82c8c795584a06b184c08f5a43be4cb0">The papers contain four letter books and other official papers sent, received, and kept by George F. Usher, Haitian consul in New York under President Fabre Nicolas Geffrard; the correspondence primarily details Usher's diplomatic and commercial work in New York City on behalf of the Republic of Haiti during the years 1859-1867, which included, in 1862, the United States's official recognition of the Haitian government. Among the recipients of Usher's letters are Demosthenes Bruno and Ernest Roumain, chargés d'affaires in Haiti, and August Elie, Hatian secretary of state, as well as B. C. Clark, Haitian consul in Boston, and James Redpath. Some of the letter books include lists of cargo ships trading between Haiti and New York. Usher's papers also include personal letters written from New York and during his retirement in Bristol, Rhode Island, as well as a bound volume of manuscript records of the Sewing School for the Children of St. Michael's Parish, Bristol, conducted by his daughters Helen Maria Usher (1834-1892) and Irene (Ida) Frances Usher (1838-1925) between 1869 and 1873.</abstract>
         <langmaterial id="aspace_729829110e0d61a2f5716e31ce10461d">
            <language>In English and French.

</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="ingest">
               <part>Usher, George F. (George Finney), 1792-1877.</part>
            </persname>
         </origination>
    
      </did>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_2af284b348807595e24dc0f523a6ece4">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>Purchased from Carmen D. Valentino on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_54cc26993c0c2a21dcad8b290e54c899">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>The materials are open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict id="aspace_c64e0f5a66f0a19c6fe3e7d264e00798">
         <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
         <p>The George F. Usher Papers is the physical property of the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University. Literary rights, including copyright, belong to the authors or their legal heirs and assigns. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ab14689381755af0e995e3394c7d6ec5">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>George F. Usher Papers. General Collection, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Yale University.</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <processinfo id="aspace_986bffae91a9b83e67df7b65722661e3">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>Much of the information included in the Description of Papers note and Collection Contents section is drawn from material supplied by the vendor.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <bioghist id="aspace_0aa6825a94eff13c4fd251861c833813">
         <head>George F. Usher (1792-1877)</head>
         <p>George Finney Usher was born in Bristol, Rhode Island, on October 22, 1792, the son of Hezekiah and Sarah Finney Usher. Through his positions as the United States Commercial Agent at Cape Haytien, Haiti (1842-1846) and at Port-au-Prince (1849-1853), Usher gained the financial, trade, and linguistic skills sufficient to win an appointment as Haiti's consul in New York City after General Fabre Nicolas Geffrard deposed Haitian Emperor Faustin Soulouque in 1858. Usher began work as consul on June 10, 1859, and remained in place until Geffrard was overthrown in 1867. Usher was replaced as consul by Elwood Cooper; he retired to Bristol in 1868, and died there on August 16, 1877.</p>
         <p>Usher married Susan Maria Griswold (1797-1825) in 1817; she bore their daughter Elizabeth Griswold (1818-1879), who married Joseph Ames Sprague (d. 1876) in 1839. Usher married Rebecca Bourn (1810-1842) in 1833 and with her had two daughters, Helen Maria (1834-1892) and Irene (Ida) Frances (1838-1925). His third wife was Emily Fitzgerald French (born 1826), whom he married in 1857. Usher and his daughters are buried in Juniper Hill Cemetery, Bristol.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <bioghist id="aspace_6d9f5fae673ae1895c9aa0efa1def094">
         <head>George Lawrence Jr.</head>
         <p>Little is known about George Lawrence Jr., who was an African American abolitionist and activist for Haitian emigration. From 1861 to 1862 Lawrence was editor and publisher of the journal <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
               <part>The Pine and Palm</part>
            </title>, which was owned by the Scottish-born reformer and promoter James Redpath, with offices in Boston and New York. In the fall of 1862 Lawrence became the head of the Haitian Emigration Bureau at 55 Liberty Street in New York, which Redpath had founded in 1859. The bureau's function was to promote and assist with African American emigration to Haiti; Lawrence signed his letters as agent of the Haytian Bureau, or Commissioner of Haytian Emigration. He was listed in the New York City directories through 1868 after which time he lived in Washington, D.C.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_67faf0cd0afa8f3bce5f76034f3a974a">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>The collection primarily contains letterpress copybooks and other official papers sent, received, and kept by George F. Usher, Haitian consul in New York City under President Fabre Nicolas Geffrard, detailing his diplomatic and commercial work in New York City on behalf of the Republic of Haiti during the years 1859-1867, together with letters written during Usher's retirement in Bristol, Rhode Island, and related papers. Also present are letterpress copybooks kept by George Lawrence Jr., the New York Agent (and subsequently Commissioner) for Haitian Emigration operating from New York City between 1862 and 1865.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement id="aspace_63366e58a0e71f05d8fb1f56d27285d1">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Organized into three series: I. George F. Usher Papers, 1852-1877. II. George Lawrence Jr. Letter Book, 1862-1865. III. Other Papers, 1863.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <occupation source="lcsh">
            <part>Consuls -- Haiti -- 19th century.</part>
         </occupation>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>Bristol (R.I. : Town) -- Social life and customs.</part>
         </geogname>
         <genreform source="aat">
            <part>Letterpress copybooks -- United States -- 19th century.</part>
         </genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part>Consuls -- United States.</part>
         </subject>
         <genreform source="aat">
            <part>Letter books -- United States -- 19th century.</part>
         </genreform>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part>Diplomatic and consular service, Haitian -- United States.</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>United States -- Foreign relations -- Haiti.</part>
         </geogname>
         <subject source="lcsh">
            <part>African American abolitionists.</part>
         </subject>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>United States -- Commerce -- Haiti.</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>Haiti -- Politics and government -- 19th century.</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>Haiti -- Foreign relations -- United States.</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>Haiti -- Emigration and immigration.</part>
         </geogname>
         <geogname source="lcnaf">
            <part>Haiti -- Commerce -- United States.</part>
         </geogname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Lawrence, George, fl. 1861-1868.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Le Couteulx de Canteleu, Jean Baptiste Emmanuel Hector, comte, b. 1827.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Harris, J. Dennis.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>James, Henry, 1811-1882.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Clark, B. C. (Benjamin C.)</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Elie, Auguste.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Bruno, Demosthenes.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Usher, Irene Frances, 1838-1925.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Usher, Helen Maria, 1834-1892.</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">
            <part>New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Committee on Ways and Means.</part>
         </corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Mitchell, James, 1818-1903.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Redpath, James, 1833-1891.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Racster, George.</part>
         </persname>
         <corpname source="ingest">
            <part>St. Michael's Church (Bristol, R.I.)</part>
         </corpname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Roumain, Ernest.</part>
         </persname>
         <persname source="ingest">
            <part>Usher, George F. (George Finney), 1792-1877.</part>
         </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c id="ref12" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>George F. Usher Papers</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series I</unitid>
               <physdescstructured coverage="whole" physdescstructuredtype="spaceoccupied">
                  <quantity>12</quantity>
                  <unittype>folders</unittype>
               </physdescstructured>
               <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <daterange>
                     <fromdate standarddate="1852">1852</fromdate>
                     <todate standarddate="1877">1877</todate>
                  </daterange>
               </unitdatestructured>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1852-1877</unitdate>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_a23e66ca60c627fddcdd04a4dd74d0db">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>Series I is organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Documents; and Records of the Sewing School for the Children of St. Michael's Parish.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e6d80fd31e850664910fa8b3fd670ae0">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The series primarily consists of four bound volumes containing copies of more than 1000 diplomatic and personal letters written by George F. Usher between June 1859 and November 1867, plus six folders of incoming letters, ephemera, and other documents. The letters, addressed to Usher's superiors in Haiti (including the secretaries of state for foreign relations, finance and commerce, the interior and agriculture, etc.), to his fellow consuls in Boston, and to the collector of revenue in Port-au-Prince and other Haitian government officials and appointees, range from very short notes and official reports to long accounts of his diplomatic work. During the subsequent three years leading up to the American government's recognition of Haiti's new regime, Usher accomplished and recorded a great deal more work, as he continued to do after recognition. Throughout the volumes, Usher responds to specified reports (not all present but condensed in Usher's own outgoing letters) of President Fabre Nicolas Geffrard's various successes, and Haitian citizens' perceptions of them. He also communicates whatever American news—often of Congressional actions—will interest Haiti's foreign office, such as John Brown's activities at Harper's Ferry. Throughout the Civil War, Usher regularly kept his Haitian superiors apprised of its progress, often reporting with expressed pleasure on the various Union advances and defeats suffered by the rebel states. In April 1865, he officially notified Haiti of Lincoln's assassination in a moving letter that specifies the mourning decorations that adorned Haiti's New York consulate and reports his intention to accept the City of New York's request that he represent Haiti when Lincoln's body passes through the city (see also the invitation in folder 9). Through all this, for more than eight years, Usher remained attentive to trade matters ranging from specific cargo shipments to British proposals to include Port-au-Prince on a new steamship route. Usher writes to his correspondents on a wide variety of business issues, ranging from shipments of coffee, sugar, and other Haitian produce, to his operating instructions for letter copy press equipment he has sent to Port-au-Prince (letter dated June 17, 1859). Many letters specify the sailings to and from Haiti of named ships, with details regarding their cargo (generally reports of merchandise and provisions, but also including more exotic items such as "the beautiful horse for his Excellency the President" that Usher shipped on April 7, 1860). Among the recipients of Usher's letters are Demosthenes Bruno, George Racster, and Ernest Roumain, chargés d'affaires in Haiti, as well as B. C. Clark, Haitian consul in Boston, and the Scottish activist and reformer James Redpath.</p>
               <p>The two letterpress copybooks also contain letters that concern Usher's personal affairs and document important portions of his and his family's life, including his daughters' upbringing by their maternal grandmother upon their mother's death. Also present are those sent between 1868 and 1877 as he concluded his business in New York City and retired to his hometown of Bristol, Rhode Island. Among Usher's regular recipients are his attorney John Turner, several men in Chicago (where he owned property), and his friend James E. French, of Bristol, Rhode Island. Also present in the series is a bound volume containing manuscript records of the Sewing School for the Children of St. Michael's Parish, conducted at Bristol by Usher's daughters Helen Maria Usher (1834-1892) and Irene (Ida) Frances Usher (1838-1925) between 1869 and 1873.</p>
               <p>The earliest item in the collection is in folder 8: an 1852 invitation to the funeral of Anne Burgoyne Gretton, the wife of William Knottesford Gretton, the British vice consul in Haiti.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref14" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence and Documents</unittitle>
               </did>
               <c id="ref15" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Longhand copybook of letters, with list of cargo ships between Haiti and New York</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1859">1859</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1862">1862</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1859-1862</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860791"
                                id="aspace_23d0a4939fde3a40687c3d34c71683d7"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_aa847c90633b6de976672f2945fc71bf"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_23d0a4939fde3a40687c3d34c71683d7">1</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref16" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Longhand copybook of letters, with list of cargo ships between Haiti and New York</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1863">1863</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1867">1867</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1863-1867</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860791"
                                id="aspace_a338bdf1adee4d2166ded6071edf9963"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0bb7d6f6bd137f538f00f3a473db17d7"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_a338bdf1adee4d2166ded6071edf9963">2</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref17" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letterpress copybook of letters</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1859">1859</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1867">1867</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1859-1867</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860791"
                                id="aspace_16fd047fce2451e3a1989fbe10e2c4e2"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_f6cbdc0a0c26019bcaea844bacaee51d"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_16fd047fce2451e3a1989fbe10e2c4e2">3</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref18" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letterpress copybook of letters</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1867">1867</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1877">1877</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1867-1877</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860791"
                                id="aspace_1ba88b06766cf983e5c35dc43d85605a"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">1</container>
                     <container id="aspace_4125e4b81d62ea8b46acdb020fa36ca0"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_1ba88b06766cf983e5c35dc43d85605a">4</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref19" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Correspondence with Ernest Roumain</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1863">1863</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1865">1865</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1863-1865</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_7530110d1ba2a248f14ae4b6fb446289"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_29b6288fd425c9aa6e3a2a2caa4caa50"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7530110d1ba2a248f14ae4b6fb446289">5</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref20" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Letters with Haitian government officials</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1859">1859</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1867">1867</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1859-1867</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_e61af0841c73b8fb563818498b20277c"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_66933da55586e04d0a8e08eb59dfc7a4"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_e61af0841c73b8fb563818498b20277c">6</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref21" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>General correspondence</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1859">1859</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1867">1867</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1859-1867</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_7360c2072f423c993bf108ad950ada86"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_0e340799af2b38d48d2d17f24506ea92"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7360c2072f423c993bf108ad950ada86">7</container>
                  </did>
                  <odd id="aspace_f4f2ceee332701a265342077dffec0ef">
                     <head>General note</head>
                     <p>Includes copies of letters from George Lawrence Jr. to B. C. Clark</p>
                  </odd>
               </c>
               <c id="ref23" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Trade and financial reports</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1859">1859</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1866">1866</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1859-1866</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_7b25a08ded254e9d18511ec709d3b770"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_bcf5a81e02c91af7db9411c17ca7d047"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_7b25a08ded254e9d18511ec709d3b770">8</container>
                  </did>
               </c>
               <c id="ref24" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Printed ephemera</unittitle>
                     <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                        <daterange>
                           <fromdate standarddate="1852">1852</fromdate>
                           <todate standarddate="1865">1865</todate>
                        </daterange>
                     </unitdatestructured>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1852-1865</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_d762d5010b970cda8bf0738aecb93331"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_e834373520a11ad1141fbfd15c52f20c"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_d762d5010b970cda8bf0738aecb93331">9</container>
                  </did>
                  <odd id="aspace_533cb41fafb13e07e7527aad2244161f">
                     <head>General note</head>
                     <p>Includes a publication, <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
                           <part>Rapport de l'Etablissement Wesleyen du Port au Prince, 1860-1863</part>
                        </title>.</p>
                  </odd>
               </c>
               <c id="ref26" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Other papers</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1857, 1862</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_4d837dae8fbda4294e351c3720a1c88f"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_749a4c63e7cab4f6878e6d4f139cf68f"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_4d837dae8fbda4294e351c3720a1c88f">10</container>
                  </did>
                  <odd id="aspace_79229e12d848419fab23de8988481cbf">
                     <head>General note</head>
                     <p>Contains a survey of the brig <emph render="italic">Adelaide G. Washburn</emph> and an essay on the state of Haitian society (annotated: published in <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
                           <part>Pine and Palm</part>
                        </title>, Ap. 62)</p>
                  </odd>
               </c>
               <c id="ref28" level="file">
                  <did>
                     <unittitle>Family and personal correspondence</unittitle>
                     <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1859, 1864</unitdate>
                     <container containerid="39002092860809"
                                id="aspace_f09b3858ae59d0e42db01df55a0f2d4a"
                                label="Mixed Materials"
                                localtype="box">2</container>
                     <container id="aspace_dad085294717cd1529e79130fee109dd"
                                localtype="folder"
                                parent="aspace_f09b3858ae59d0e42db01df55a0f2d4a">11</container>
                  </did>
                  <odd id="aspace_876a5770c8c3a6a85f99769318eeb233">
                     <head>General note</head>
                     <p>Contains a letter from Emily Usher to Irene Usher, and correspondence regarding Juniper Hill Cemetery, Bristol</p>
                  </odd>
               </c>
            </c>
            <c id="ref30" level="subseries">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Records of the Sewing School for the Children of St. Michael's Parish</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1869">1869</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1873">1873</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1869-1873</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002092860809"
                             id="aspace_b1c6e59ee3c9ca3c364d9d9973efbd23"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_9174058a82c30d1cd6eb64269da7ec40"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_b1c6e59ee3c9ca3c364d9d9973efbd23">12</container>
               </did>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_e6b148cbdfbdf91bbc0e66b9e8353de6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>A volume with attendance and financial reports for the school, and an accounting of "garments finished." The school was founded by Sarah Goodwin, May Minturn, Helen Maria Usher, and Irene (Ida) Frances Usher.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref34" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>George Lawrence Jr. Letter Book</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series II</unitid>
               <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <daterange>
                     <fromdate standarddate="1862">1862</fromdate>
                     <todate standarddate="1865">1865</todate>
                  </daterange>
               </unitdatestructured>
               <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1862-1865</unitdate>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_94669a59be4c6c18ce8517c10e6405f5">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>The series contains a letterpress copybook containing about 229 letters written by George Lawrence Jr., the self-described "colored American" successor to James Redpath as New York City Agent/Commissioner for Haitian Emigration from the United States and Canada, between September 1862 and February 1865. As Lawrence reported in his letter of September 9, 1862, to Mr. C. Audry of Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, the Haitian Emigration Bureau's "object ... is to encourage colored emigration, and the class to whom the invitation of the Haytian Government is specially extended is that of farmers or agricultural laborers." As this fact was known to many of Lawrence's correspondents (through advertisements and public lectures of the sort detailed in Lawrence's letter of October 1, 1862, and others), many of these letters are addressed to African Americans (though recipients' race is seldom expressed). To some of these recipients Lawrence further explains that the Haitian government has undertaken this project "in order to facilitate intercourse between the different sections of her territory and thereby to develope [<emph render="italic">sic</emph>] her resources, stimulate industry and promote the advancement of her people."</p>
               <p>Lawrence's letters address a wide variety of travel, emigration, and baggage concerns of the many Americans who have written to him regarding their plans to travel to Haiti (their letters are not present, but many specific details of their content may be inferred from Lawrence's responses). These hopeful emigrants' names, towns and states (from as far away as Wisconsin) are given in many of Lawrence's headings or texts of his letters to them. Many operational details connected with this extensive emigration campaign are mentioned in these letters sent to prospective and actual emigrants, various campaigns supporters, and Lawrence's official colleagues. Topics discussed include the bureau's decision to close its Boston office and temporarily handle all emigration business in New York; the number of free acres promised to each African-American emigrant; shipments of cotton seed; costs of passage and the Haitian government's policy regarding advancing passage costs; the sailing dates of named steamers; the sailing of many named emigrants on particular vessels at particular times; several facets of American publicity for the campaign; and an inventory of office supplies inherited from Redpath. The letters also describe some of Redpath's Boston and Philadelphia work and the field work of J. Dennis Harris, a "Traveling Agent for Haytian Emigration"; and details of the Emigration Bureau's financial affairs. Redpath and B. C. Clark are two of Lawrence's more frequent correspondents, as well as Haitian government officials, but the volume also includes five long letters Lawrence sent to James Mitchell, United States Commissioner of Emigration under Abraham Lincoln, during the year in which the United States government, freed from Southern objections by the South's attempted withdrawal from the Union, finally recognized Haiti's government under President Geffrard. In the second of Lawrence's letters to Mitchell, dated October 14, 1862, he identifies himself as "of African descent." This letter opens, "I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of your able letter to President Lincoln on the relation of the White and African races in the United States" and continues with Lawrence's statement of his own thoughts ("sympathizing with the mass of my fellow colored American, whether bond or free") on American race relations, work opportunities, republican institutions, and emigration.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Letterpress copybook of letters</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <daterange>
                        <fromdate standarddate="1862">1862</fromdate>
                        <todate standarddate="1865">1865</todate>
                     </daterange>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1862-1865</unitdate>
                  <container containerid="39002092860809"
                             id="aspace_68ce3c1b7c0ca504488af222631e6f90"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_0c27c06b85f53f1046fe849216497720"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_68ce3c1b7c0ca504488af222631e6f90">13</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
         <c id="ref37" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Other Papers</unittitle>
               <unitid>Series III</unitid>
               <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                  <datesingle standarddate="1863">1863</datesingle>
               </unitdatestructured>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ac84d713c466815aad04a5686ba085d1">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Series III contains a manuscript volume which appears to be unrelated to Usher, Lawrence, or Haiti. It is written in various hands and opens with records of meetings of the Committee of Ways and Means of the New York State Legislature held between February 6 and April 7, 1863. The minutes are followed by a manuscript translation of <title localtype="simple" render="italic">
                     <part>Les sectes et sociétés secrètes, politiques et religieuses: essai sur leur histoire depuis les temps les plus reculés jusqu'à la Révolution française</part>
                  </title> (titled "Sects and Secret Societies, both Political and Religious"), by Jean Baptiste Emmanuel Hector, comte Le Couteulx de Canteleu, which was published in 1863.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c id="ref38" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Minute book</unittitle>
                  <unitdatestructured unitdatetype="inclusive">
                     <datesingle standarddate="1863">1863</datesingle>
                  </unitdatestructured>
                  <container containerid="39002092860809"
                             id="aspace_5d95ff8de7d362c685dcd945b9a3c6c3"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             localtype="box">2</container>
                  <container id="aspace_80799bb586142d03f8b8f59e36183c47"
                             localtype="folder"
                             parent="aspace_5d95ff8de7d362c685dcd945b9a3c6c3">14</container>
               </did>
            </c>
         </c>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
